<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="first_seam" xreflabel="first_seam">
  <?dbhtml filename="first_seam.html"?>
  <chapterinfo>
    <keywordset>
      <keyword>JBoss Developer Studio</keyword>
      <keyword>Seam</keyword>
      <keyword>JBoss</keyword>
    </keywordset>
  </chapterinfo>

  <title>Write Your First Project with JBoss Developer Studio</title>

  <para>This chapter is a set of hands-on labs. You get step-by-step information about how the JBoss
    Developer Studio can be used during the development process.</para>

  <section id="create_seam_application">
    <title>Create a Seam Application</title>

    <para>In this section you get to know how to create a Seam project in JBDS, how to start the
      server and what a structure your project has after creating.</para>

    <section id="start_dev_db">
      <title>Start Development Database</title>

      <para>Before opening the JBoss Developer studio you need to <ulink
          url="http://anonsvn.jboss.org/repos/jbosstools/trunk/documentation/guides/GettingStartedGuide/en/database.zip"
          >download</ulink> and start a Workshop Database.</para>
      <para>To start the database just run <property>./runDBServer.sh</property> or
          <property>runDBServer.bat</property> from the database directory.</para>
      <para>The end result should be a console window that looks like:</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Starting DataBase</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam1.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

    </section>

    <section id="create_deploy_seam">
      <title>Create and deploy Seam Web Project</title>

      <para>Minimize the terminal window and run the <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property>
        from Applications Menu or from the desktop icon.</para>
      <para>First of all you get the Workspace Launcher. Change the default workspace location if
        it's needed. Click on <property>Ok</property>. </para>

      <figure>
        <title>Workspace Launcher Dialog</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam2.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>After startup, you see the welcome page. You could read how to work with welcome pages
        in <link linkend="Welcome">previous</link> chapter. Now select <property>Create
          New...</property> icon and then press on <property>Create Seam Project</property>
        link.</para>

      <para>The <property>New Seam Project wizard</property> is started. You need to enter a name
        (e.g., &quot;workshop&quot;) and a location directory for your new project. The
        wizard has an option for selecting the actual Server (and not just WTP runtime) that will be
        used for the project. This allows the wizard to correctly identify where the needed
        datasource and driver libraries need to go.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>New Seam Project Wizard</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam3.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>All settings are already specified here, you can just modify the Configuration. Click on
        the <emphasis>
          <property>Modify...</property>
        </emphasis> button to configure your custom facets pattern:</para>


      <figure id="ProjectFacetsSpecifyingScreen">
        <title>Project Facets Specifying</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam4.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>On the whole the dialog allows to select the "features" you want to use in your project.
        Doing this <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> setups the appropriate tooling for
        your project. Since JBoss Seam integrates all popular Java EE frameworks, you can select any
        combination of technologies from the list. Here, for the default configuration, Dynamic Web
        Module, Java, JavaServer Faces (JSF), and Seam Facet are already selected for a typical
        database-driven web application. The default project facets should suffice.</para>

      <para>In the <property>Project Facets</property> form you can also bring up server runtimes
        panel by clicking <property> Runtimes</property> tab on the right corner. This panel shows
        available server runtimes.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Runtimes Selecting</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam5.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Click on <emphasis>
          <property>Ok</property>
        </emphasis> and then <emphasis>
          <property>Next</property>
        </emphasis> to proceed further.</para>

      <para>A dynamic web application contains both web pages and Java code. The wizard will ask you
        where you want to put those files. You can just leave the default values or choose another
        folder.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Web Module Settings</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam6.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>On the next form, you will be able to select where those library JARs come from. The
        easiest is just to select the JARs provided by the JBoss AS runtime associated with this
        project. That is why it is important to chose the right JBoss AS 4.2 runtime in the project
        setup window.</para>
      <itemizedlist>
        <listitem>
          <para>Check <emphasis>
              <property>Server Supplied JSF Implementation</property>
            </emphasis>. We will use <ulink url="&seamlink;#addJSFCapab">JSF
              implementation</ulink> that comes with JBoss server</para>
        </listitem>
        <listitem>
          <para>Click <emphasis>
              <property>Next</property>
            </emphasis></para>
        </listitem>
      </itemizedlist>

      <figure>
        <title>JSF Capabilities Adding</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam7.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Next wizard step needs more settings that previous. Let's start with
          <property>General</property> section.</para>
      <para>Leave the default Seam runtime and check a WAR deployment.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Seam Facet Setting</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam8.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Next <property>Database</property> section is a little tricky. The <property>Connection
          Profile</property> needs to be edited so that the new project works properly with the
        external HSQLDB server. By default the project wizard tries to use the JBoss embedded
        HSQLDB, but the tutorial uses an external database to replicate a more real world
        development scenario. Click on <property>Edit</property> to modify the Connection
        Profile.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>DataBase Setting</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam8_1.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Select <property>JDBC Connection Properties</property>. Make sure the URL is set to <emphasis>
          <property>jdbc:hsqldb:hsql://localhost:1701</property>
        </emphasis></para>

      <figure>
        <title>JDBC Connection Properties</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam9.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Try click on <property>Test Connection</property> button. It probably won’t work. This
        happens if the hsql jdbc driver is not exactly the same. This can be worked around by
        modifying the HSQLDB database driver settings. To modify the settings, click the
          <property>“...”</property> next to the drop-down box.</para>

      <para>The proper Driver JAR File should be listed under <property>Driver File(s)</property>.
        Select the hsqldb.jar file found in the database/lib directory and click on
          <property>Ok</property>.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Driver Details</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam10.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Select <property>Hypersonic DB</property> and click on <property>Ok</property>. Again,
        this only happens if the selected hsqldb.jar is different from the running database.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Hypersonic DB Selecting</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam11.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Now, the <property>Test Connection</property> should succeed. After testing the
        connection, click on Ok.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Connection Testing</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam12.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>You can leave the <property>Code Generation</property> section as is. It refers to Java
        packages in which the generated code will be placed.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Code Generation Setting</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam13.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Click on <property>Finish</property> button. Now, there should be a new Seam project
        called “workshop” listed in Package Explorer view.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>&quot;worskhop&quot; Project in the Package Explorer</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam14.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
    </section>

    <section id="start_JBossAS">
      <title>Start JBoss Application Server</title>

      <para>The complete information on how to manage JBoss AS from JBoss Developer Studio you can
        read in a <link linkend="manage">corresponding chapter</link>.</para>
      <para>Now you just need to start the server by clicking on the Start the server icon ( 
        <inlinemediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam50.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </inlinemediaobject> ) in the
        JBoss Server View.</para>

      <para>Then run the project by selecting the project and use <emphasis><property>Run As... >
            Run on Server</property>.</emphasis></para>

      <note>
        <title>Note:</title>
        <para>If the project does not show up, then you can use a normal browser and use <emphasis>
            <property>http://localhost:8080/workshop/home.seam</property>
          </emphasis> as the url.</para>
      </note>

      <para>Your project looks like this:</para>

      <figure>
        <title>&quot;workshop&quot; Project Started</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam16.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

    </section>

    <section id="workshop_code_overview">
      <title>Workshop Project Code Overview</title>

      <para>Now let's examine the project and its structure. Go back to the Package Explorer view in
        JBoss Developer Studio.</para>

      <para>It seems like it&apos;s not much for project but this shell application contains a login
        screen with default login logic, a menu template that can be further modified, and other
        layout templates.</para>

      <para>It&apos;s important to note that the business logic will reside in the <emphasis>
          <property>src/hot</property>
        </emphasis> folder, by default. And, the package naming conventions that were used in <property>New Seam
        project wizard</property> could have been changed to something different from <emphasis>
          <property>org.domain.workshop.session</property>.
        </emphasis> Also, notice that there is a default <property>Authenticator. java</property>
        file. This is where custom security logic can be added. Seam has a nice declarative security
        model that we will explore in a bit more detail later on. The <emphasis>
          <property>src/main</property>
        </emphasis> folder is a model directory. It stores the project&apos;s JPA entity beans.</para>
      
      <figure>
        <title>Project Structure</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam17.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>
        
        <para>The view tier of the
        application is also important. Seam uses facelets and there is a built-in facelets GUI
        editor that has some nice WYSIWYG and component drag/drop functionality. Try this out by
        opening <property>home.xhtml</property> from <property>WebContent</property> folder.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Facelets GUI Editor</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam18.png" scale="85"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Notice that the templates reside in the <emphasis>
          <property>WebContent/layout</property>
        </emphasis> folder. There is a stylesheet in the <emphasis>
          <property>WebContent/stylesheet</property>
        </emphasis> folder. There is also a login and default error page. The Facelet editor will be
        explored in more detail later in the lab.</para>

      <para>The project already has a datasource that was created per the Seam project wizard
        database settings. And, obviously all of the Seam specific configuration files and JAR
        dependencies are included and placed in the proper locations. On last noteworthy line item
        is related to the build script. There isn’t a build script because the Eclipse WTP(Web Tools
        Project) plugin is used to publish web application changes. As you can see, JBoss Developer
        Studio is removing a great deal of complexity from the enterprise Java project
        setup/deployment process. The end result is a developer that is writing code, not spending
        days/weeks trying to figure out how to get a decent development environment and project
        build process.</para>

    </section>

  </section>


  <section id="seam_action_dev">
    <title>Seam Action Development</title>

    <para>Now, it’s time to write some code. The good news is that JBoss Developer Studio can also
      help out in this respect. In this section, we will create a new Seam Action POJO and facelet
      with some custom business logic and some GUI changes.</para>

    <section id="create_seam_action">
      <title>Create a New Seam Action</title>

      <para>Go to main menu bar and click on <emphasis>
          <property>File > New > New Seam Action</property>
        </emphasis> to start the New Seam Action wizard.</para>

      <para>Specify a <property>Seam component name</property> (e.g., &quot;myAction&quot;).
        The other properties will be auto-completed for you so there is no need to change them.
        Click on <property>Finish</property>.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>New Seam Action Wizard</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam19.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Now, open the <property>MyAction.java</property> file and replace the
        &quot;myAction&quot; method with this logic:</para>

      <programlisting><![CDATA[public void myAction() {
Calendar cal = Calendar.getInstance();
log.info("myAction.myAction() action called");
facesMessages.add("MyAction Executed on:" + cal.getTime());
}]]></programlisting>

      <para>You also need to import the <property>java.util.Calendar</property> class by clicking
            <emphasis><property>CTRL + Shift + O</property>.</emphasis></para>

    </section>

    <section id="test_seam_action">
      <title>Test Seam Action</title>

      <para>The new action can be tested by browsing the workshop-test project. JBoss Developer
        Studio has already created a TestNG test case for you.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>&quot;workshop-test&quot; Project</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam20.png" scale="85"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The test case simulates a Seam component/method execution for the
          <property>MyAction.myAction()</property> logic.</para>
      <para>To run the test case, right click on <property>MyActionTest.xml</property> and click <emphasis>
          <property>Run As > TestNG Suite</property>
        </emphasis> or use the <property>Run As...</property> toolbar shortcut as shown
        below.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>TestNG Running</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam21.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>With any luck, the test case will pass. Look at the TestNG view.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>TestNG Results</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam22.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Now, it’s safe to test the new Seam Action in a web browser. The fastest way to do that
        is to right click on <property>myAction.xhtml</property> and use <emphasis>
          <property>Run As... > Run On Server</property>
        </emphasis> which will show the appropriate url in the browser. Alternatively you can
        manually enter <emphasis>
          <property>http://localhost:8080/workshop/myAction.seam</property>
        </emphasis> into a browser.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Seam Action in a Web Browser</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam23.png" scale="90"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

    </section>

    <section id="modify_seam_action">
      <title>Modify Seam Action User Interface</title>

      <para>Browse to <emphasis>
          <property>http://localhost:8080/workshop/myAction.seam</property>
        </emphasis> and click on <property>myAction</property>. This executes the “myAction” method.
        This looks pretty good, but we could make this page look a little better.</para>

      <para>Open <emphasis>
          <property>WebContent/myAction.xhtml</property>
        </emphasis> in JBoss Developer Studio to use the nice facelets editor.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Open Seam Action with Editor </title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam24.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Right click on the &quot;myAction!&quot; button in the visual part of editor and
        select <property>&lt;h:commandButton&gt; Attributes</property>.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Seam Action Editing</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam25.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Change the <property>value</property> of the button to something different. If desired,
        you can change any other text on the page. Then, type <emphasis>
          <property>CTRL + S</property>
        </emphasis> to save the facelet.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Attributes Dialog</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam26.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Refresh <emphasis>
          <property>http://localhost:8080/workshop/myAction.seam</property>
        </emphasis> and now you should see your changes.</para>

      <para>Notice that you did not have to publish the application. JBoss Developer Studio
        auto-published it for you.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Seam Action Is Modified</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam27.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

    </section>


  </section>

  <section id="declarative_security">
    <title>Declarative Security</title>

    <para>In this section you will see how it’s easy to secure the facelets and facelet components
      in Seam. Let’s go ahead and secure the action button, then we will secure the entire
      page.</para>

    <section id="edit_login">
      <title>Edit Login Authentication Logic</title>

      <para>There is a class called <property>Authenticator.java</property>. The login page will
        execute the <property>Authenticator.authenticate()</property> method by default, so we’ll
        start by adding some custom login logic.</para>
      <para>Open <property>Authenticator.java</property> in JBoss Developer Studio and replace the
          <property>authenticate()</property> method with this code:</para>

      <programlisting><![CDATA[public boolean authenticate() {
if (identity.getUsername().equals("admin")
&& identity.getPassword().equals("password")) {
identity.addRole("admin");
return true;
}
else
return true;
}]]></programlisting>

    </section>
    <section id="secure_seam_page">
      <title>Secure Seam Page Component</title>

      <para>Open <property>myAction.xhtml</property> and add a new secured command button:</para>
      <programlisting><![CDATA[<h:commandButton id="myActionSecured"
value="Secured Action Button"
action="#{myAction.myAction}"
rendered="#{s:hasRole('admin')}"/>]]></programlisting>

      <para>Refresh <emphasis>
          <property>http://localhost:8080/workshop/myAction.seam</property>
        </emphasis> If you are not logged in you will only see one button. If you are logged in,
        there will be two buttons.</para>


      <figure>
        <title>One Button on a Page</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam28.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The secured button is not visible because the user isn’t logged in as
          <property>&quot;admin&quot;</property>.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Secured Button is Visible</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam29.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The user is logged in as <property>&quot;admin&quot;</property>. Securing
        components is easy but securing pages is pretty simple as well. </para>
      <para>Open <emphasis>
          <property>WebContent/WEB-INF/pages.xml</property>
        </emphasis>. Then add this markup directly underneath the &lt;pages&gt;
        element:</para>

      <programlisting><![CDATA[<page view-id="/myAction.xhtml" login-required="true"/>]]></programlisting>

      <para>Refresh <emphasis>
          <property>http://localhost:8080/workshop/myAction.seam</property>
        </emphasis> If you are not logged in you will get bounced back to the login page.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Login Page</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam30.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Thus, if you enter login credentials for the
          <property>&quot;admin&quot;</property> user, you will be re-directed to the
        secured page and secured component. If you enter different login credentials, page access
        will be granted, but the secured component will not be displayed.</para>

      <para>Congratulations! You have secured your new action both at the facelet component and page
        level. You also added custom authentication logic to the login action.</para>

    </section>

  </section>

  <section id="browsing_workshop_db">
    <title>Browsing Workshop Database</title>

    <para>In this section you get to know how to use the workshop database that was started at the
      beginning of the lab.</para>

    <section id="database_connectivity">
      <title>Database Connectivity Setup</title>

      <para>The workshop data can be browsed inside of JBoss Developer Studio.</para>

      <para>To open the Data Source Explorer, click on <emphasis><property>Window > Open Perspective
            > Other > Database Development</property>.</emphasis></para>
      <para>In the Data Source Explorer, expand a <property>Databases</property> node and select a
          <property>Default</property> database. Right click on it, select
          <property>Connect</property> from the context menu.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Data Source Explorer</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam31.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

    </section>

    <section id="browsing_workshop_db2">
      <title>Browse Workshop Database</title>

      <para>Then in the current view, drill down to the <property>CUSTOMERS</property> table.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>&quot;CUSTOMERS&quot; Table</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam32.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Right click on <property>CUSTOMERS</property>, select <emphasis>
          <property>Data > Sample Contents</property>
        </emphasis> to view the data in the table.</para>

      <para>There should be a SQL Results view on the workbench, but it could be hidden. Click on
        the <property>&quot;Result1&quot;</property> tab in the right side and you should
        see the data in the CUSTOMERS table.</para>


      <figure>
        <title>SQL Results View</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam33.png" scale="92"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <note>
        <title>Note:</title>
        <para>If you can’t find the SQL Results view tab, click on <emphasis><property>Window > Show
              View > Other > SQL Development > SQL Results</property>.</emphasis></para>
      </note>

      <para>Congratulations! You just connected to the workshop database and queried the content
        using Database Explorer tools.</para>

    </section>

  </section>

  <section id="db_programming">
    <title>Database Programming</title>

    <para>Now, it’s time to reverse engineer the workshop database into a fully functioning Seam
      CRUD(Create Read Update Delete) application.</para>

    <section id="reverse_engineer_crud">
      <title>Reverse Engineer CRUD from a Running Database</title>

      <para>In <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property>, switch to <property>Seam
          perspective</property>, and then right-click the project and select
            <emphasis><property>New > Seam Generate Entities</property>.</emphasis></para>

      <para>&quot;workshop&quot; project in the <property>Seam Generate Entities
          wizard</property> will be selected automatically. There is no need to change something
        more, click <emphasis>
          <property>Next</property>
        </emphasis> to proceed further.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Generate Seam Entities</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam34.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>On the next page use the <emphasis>
          <property>Include</property>
        </emphasis> button to include all the tables from the database and click <emphasis>
          <property>Finish</property>.</emphasis></para>

      <figure>
        <title>Selecting Tables</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam34a.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>After running the Generate Entities action, you will see new <emphasis>
          <property>org.domain.workshop.entity</property>
        </emphasis> classes. These classes represent insert/update/delete/query logic.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>org.domain.workshop.entity Classes</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam35.png" scale="90"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>There are also <emphasis>
          <property>org.domain.workshop.entity</property>
        </emphasis> package that contains the JPA classes. These are the entity beans that are
        mapped to database tables.Note,that you can use Seam refactoring tools with Seam components.
        Read more about it in <ulink
          url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/nightly-docs/en/seam/html_single/index.html#seam_refactoring"
          >Seam refactoring tools chapter</ulink> of Seam Dev Tools Reference Guide.</para>

      <para>Last, but not least, there are facelets for all of the CRUD screens. The best way to get
        a feel for the generated code is to open a browser and play around with the application. Go
        to <emphasis>
          <property>http://localhost:8080/workshop</property>
        </emphasis> and insert/update/delete/query a few records. There is quite a bit of AJAX in
        this application, but which we will explore further later on in the lab. For now, take note
        of the page tabs, required field logic and data table sorting in the list pages. </para>

      <figure>
        <title>CustomersList.xhtml in the Editor</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam36.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Congratulations! You now have a fully functioning CRUD application that is already AJAX
        enabled.</para>

    </section>

    <section id="use_hibernate_tools">
      <title>Use Hibernate Tools to Query Data via JPA</title>

      <para>Now, it&apos;s time to write some JPA queries using the Hibernate perspective in
          <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property>.</para>
      <para>In the upper right corner of the workbench there is a small icon (see the figure below),
        click on it and choose <property>Hibernate</property>.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Hibernate Perspective</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam37.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Look at the Hibernate Configurations view. In the &quot;workshop&quot; project,
        drill down on the <property>Session Factory</property> and notice that the JPA
        entities/attributes are listed in a nice tree view.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Hibernate Configurations View</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam38.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Right click on the <property>Session Factory</property> and select <property>HQL
          Editor</property>. This will open a JPA query scratch pad window.</para>

      <para>Write your query and click on the &quot;Hibernate Dynamic SQL Preview&quot; tab.
        You should see the SQL that will be executed if this JPA query is run.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>JPA Query Editor</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam39.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Run the query by clicking on the green run icon.</para>

      <para>The results are listed in the &quot;Hibernate Query Result&quot; tab. There is a
        &quot;Properties&quot; tab in the workbench that can be used to see a specific JPA
        result. These results represent the JPA objects because our query did not specify column
        names.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Hibernate Query Result View</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam40.png" scale="80"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The query can be refined, and take note that there is nice code completion in the JPA
        query editor.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Code Completion</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam41.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>A refined query will return results that are more ResultSet oriented. Notice the join
        logic that JPA supports.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>The Results</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam42.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>


      <para>There was no need to specify an <property>Employees</property> table in the
          <property>from</property> part of the JPA query because JPA supports reference traversal
        via Java class attribute references. Not only are JPA and HQL queries fully supported, but
        Criteria based queries can also be written in the Criteria Editor. You should spend some
        time tinkering with different queries and possibly Criteria based queries, even though the
        instructions are not provided in this lab.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Criteria Editor</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam43.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

    </section>

    <section id="use_hibernate_to_vizualize">
      <title>Use Hibernate Tools to visualize the Data Model</title>

      <para>Now, it’s time to view the data model for the workshop database.</para>

      <para>In the Hibernate Configurations view, select &quot;workshop&quot; project and
        expand the <property>Configuration</property> node. Select the
          <property>Customers</property> entity, right click on it, choose <property>Open Mapping
          Diagram</property>.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Mapping Diagram Opening</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam44.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>


      <para>You see a Diagram tab for the CUSTOMERS table and any tables that have FK references.
        This is a handy way to view the data model and JPA mappings. Now, you’ve got access to
        something that the Erwin Data Modeler can’t do.</para>


      <figure>
        <title>Diagram Tab</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam45.png" scale="80"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

    </section>
  </section>


  <section id="rich_components">
    <title>Rich Components</title>

    <para>This lab will conclude with one last AJAX twist. In this section we add a RichFaces
        <property>inputNumberSlider</property> to the Order Details edit screen.</para>

    <section id="add_richfaces">
      <title>Add a Richfaces component to the CRUD Application</title>

      <para>Switch to Seam perspective, open <emphasis>
          <property>WebContent/OrderdetailsEdit.xhtml</property>
        </emphasis> in JBoss Developer Studio.</para>
      <para>Change the form field values using the visual editor. Seam has generated the form field
        names that match the database column names. This is not ideal for business users.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>Form Fields Editing</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam46.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Also, replace the QTY Ordered input field with a <property>inputNumberSlider</property>.
        You can use the JBoss Developer Studio palette or right click on the form and insert the
        RichFaces component.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>RichFaces Component Inserting</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam47.png" scale="85"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>One the last option is to use the source view and manually copy the inputNumberSlider
        markup listed below:</para>

      <programlisting><![CDATA[<rich:inputNumberSlider id="quantityOrdered" required="true"
                                                               value="#{orderdetailsHome.instance.quantityordered}"/>]]></programlisting>

      <figure>
        <title>Adding the Source</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam48.png"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>The end result is an edit page that has better form labels and a new RichFaces
        control.</para>

      <figure>
        <title>The Result Page</title>
        <mediaobject>
          <imageobject>
            <imagedata fileref="images/first_seam/first_seam49.png" scale="85"/>
          </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
      </figure>

      <para>Congratulations! You have completed the JBoss Developer Studio lab.</para>

    </section>

  </section>
</chapter>
