<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<chapter id="guvnor_preferences" xreflabel="guvnor_preferences">
    <?dbhtml filename="guvnor_preferences.html"?>
    <chapterinfo>
        <keywordset>
            <keyword>JBoss Tools</keyword>
            <keyword>Eclipse Guvnor Tools</keyword>
        </keywordset>
    </chapterinfo>

    <title>Guvnor Preferences</title>

    <para>The <property>EGT</property> provides a preference page in the <emphasis>
            <property>Guvnor</property>
        </emphasis> category:</para>

	   <figure>
		<title>Resource Selection</title>
		<mediaobject>
			<imageobject>
				<imagedata fileref="images/guvnor_preferences/guvnor_preferences.png"/>
			</imageobject>
		</mediaobject>
	   </figure>

    <para>The preferences cover two categories:</para>
    <itemizedlist>
        <listitem><para>Guvnor repository connections</para></listitem>
            
        <listitem><para>Local Guvnor
        repository resource decorations.</para></listitem>
     </itemizedlist>

    <section id="repo_connection_preferences">
        <title>Guvnor Repository Connection Preferences</title>
        <para>There are two preferences that can be set for Guvnor repository connections, that are
            used when creating new connections:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>The first is a default Guvnor repository URL template, which can make it
                    easier to create multiple similar connections by simply changing part of the
                    field, such as the host name.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>The second is whether saving of authentication information in the Eclipse
                    platform key-ring should be enabled by default.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>As with the Guvnor repository URL template, actually whether to save a specific
            instance of authentication information in the Eclipse platform key-ring can be
            determined when actually creating the connection. That is, both of these preferences are
            simply convenience values set to reasonable defaults.</para>
    </section>

    <section id="resource_decoration_preferences">
        <title>Local Guvnor Repository Resource Decoration Preferences</title>

        <para>The second category of preferences provided by the <property>EGT</property> deals with how the decoration of
            local resources associated with Guvnor repository resources is presented. Since the
            Guvnor repository is not a substitute for a SCM, and since SCM tools in Eclipse tend to
            decorate local resources, it is useful to be able to control just how the <property>EGT</property> decorate
            its local resources to avoid messy conflicts with SCM packages.</para>
            
        <para>In the <emphasis>
            <property>File Decoration</property></emphasis>
            section of the preference page, you can choose the location (Top right, Top left, Bottom right,
             Bottom left) of the decoration icon, or you can choose not to display it. In
            the <emphasis>
                <property>Text</property></emphasis> section, you can format the Guvnor metadata that is appended to the file
                names:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Whether to show an indicator (&gt;) when the local file has changes not committed back to the
                Guvnor repository</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Whether to show the revision number</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Whether to show the date/time stamp</para>
             </listitem>
        </itemizedlist> 
           
        <para>Any changes to these preferences take effect immediately upon clicking the <emphasis>
            <property>Apply</property></emphasis> and then <emphasis>
                <property>Ok</property></emphasis> buttons.</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
