<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="introduction">
	<?dbhtml filename="introduction.html"?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<keywordset>
			<keyword>JBoss Tools</keyword>
			<keyword>Smooks</keyword>
			<keyword>JBDS</keyword>
		</keywordset>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>Introduction</title>
	<sect1>
		<title>What is Smooks?</title>
		<para>Smooks is a Java Framework/Engine for processing XML and  non XML data (CSV, EDI, Java, JSON etc).</para>
		<para></para>
		<para>
			<orderedlist numeration="Upperroman" inheritnum="inherit">
				<listitem><para>Transformation: Perform a wide range of Data Transforms. Supports many different Source and Result types -XML/CSV/EDI/Java/JSON to XML/CSV/EDI/Java/JSON.</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Java Binding: Bind into a Java Object Model from any data source (CSV, EDI, XML, Java, JSON etc). </para>
				</listitem>
				
				<listitem>
					<para>Huge Message Processing: Process huge messages (GBs) - Split, Transform and Route message fragments to JMS, File, Database etc destinations. Route multiple message formats to multiple destinations in a single pass over a message.
					</para>				
				</listitem>
				
				<listitem>
					<para>Message Enrichment: Enrich a message with data from a Database, or other Datasources.
					</para>				
				</listitem>
				
				<listitem>
					<para>Combine: Combine the above features in different ways e.g. add Message Enrichment as part of a Splitting and Routing process.
					</para>				
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
		</para>
		<figure>
			<title>Smooks</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/common/smooks-usecase.png"
						scale="90" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>  For More informations about Smooks, please visit Smooks official site:
			<ulink url="http://www.smooks.org">Smooks official site</ulink> 
		</para>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>What is Smooks dev tools?</title>
		<para>Smooks dev tools is a sets of graphical tools for editing  Smooks configuration file base on Eclipse.</para>
		<figure>
			<title>Smooks form editor</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/common/form_editor.png" scale="90" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</sect1>
	<sect1>
		<title>How to install Smooks dev tools?</title>
		<para>  The Smooks dev tools was included by the JBossTools since 3.0.0  beta1  version. You can download the JBossTools from:
			<link>http://www.jboss.org/tools/download/index.html
			</link>
			.
		</para>
		<para>  Smooks dev tools(JBossTools) run with the latest Eclipse and  other  required plug-ins(GEF,EMF,etc.).</para>
		<para>  User should download the latest IDE for  Java EE developers from this
			<link linkend="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/">site
			</link>. It contains many plug-ins ( GEF,EMF,etc. ) required by Smooks dev  tools.
		</para>
	</sect1>
</chapter>
