<?xml version='1.0' encoding='ISO-8859-1'?><chapter id="overview">
  <title>JBoss BPEL Tooling Overview</title>
  <para>JBoss Tools now includes a BPEL (Business Process Execution Language) editor that is WS-BPEL 2.0 compliant.</para>
  <para><footnote label="*">
      <para>
   <ulink url="http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsbpel/2.0/OS/wsbpel-v2.0-OS.html">WS-BPEL 2.0</ulink> 
   stands for Web Service Business Process Execution Language. Like EAI, BPEL is an XML-based language,
   but BPEL is more specific and targeted. Typically, BPEL is used to &quot;orchestrate&quot; or join disparate web services into an integrated process, resulting in a seamless use of the Internet to 
   conduct business transactions ranging from simple money exchanges to complex calculations and 
   asset reallocation.</para>
    </footnote>The editor is based on the Eclipse 
        <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/bpel/">BPEL project </ulink> with some additional enhancements and numerous bug fixes. In addition, a deployment framework allows BPEL processes to be deployed to, and executed by the Riftsaw BPEL execution engine which
 is based on the Apache ODE engine (version 1.3.4 as of this writing). Please refer to the <ulink url="http://jboss.org/riftsaw">Riftsaw website</ulink> for more information.</para>
  <para>Here are just some of the new features of the JBoss Tools BPEL editor: </para>
  <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
      <para>Close integration with the Riftsaw BPEL runtime: a new Eclipse project type has been defined to allow simple, one-click deployment.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Increased reliability and language validation over the Eclipse BPEL project.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Enhanced &quot;New Process Wizard&quot; that generates a complete, ready-to-run process on a local server without additional WSDL configuration.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
      <para>Improved BPEL Console for simple monitoring and control of BPEL processes.</para>
    </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
</chapter>