<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<chapter id="functionality_overview">
	<?dbhtml filename="functionality_overview.html"?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<keywordset>
			<keyword>JBoss Tools</keyword>
			<keyword>Eclipse Guvnor Tools</keyword>
		</keywordset>
	</chapterinfo>

	<title>Tasks</title>

	<para>This chapter provides an overview of the functionality provided by the <property>Guvnor Tools</property>.</para>

	<section>
		<title>Creating a New Guvnor Connection</title>
		<para>
			As mentioned in <xref linkend="introduction"/>, the main purpose of the <productname>EGT</productname> is to allow development using resources held in a Guvnor repository. The first task is to make a connection to a Guvnor repository. This is handled by the <guilabel>Connection Wizard</guilabel> (see <xref linkend="connection_wizard"/>). 
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="local_copies">
		<title>Getting Local Copies of Guvnor Files</title>
		<para>There are two methods of getting local copies of Guvnor repository resources:</para>

		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Drag-and-drop from the Guvnor Repositories View, as described in <xref linkend="guvnor_repositories_view"/></para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Using the Resource from Guvnor Wizard, as described in <xref linkend="resources_from_guvnor"/></para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>

		<para>
			When local copies of Guvnor repository files are created, the <property>EGT</property> sets an association between the local copy and the master file in the repository. This information is kept in the (normally) hidden <filename>.guvnorinfo</filename> folder in the local project and, like all metadata, should not be changed by end users.
		</para>
	
		<figure>
			<title>.guvnorinfo metadata</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/guvnorinfo.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	
		<para>
			The association allows for operations such as update and commit in synchronization with the master copy held in the Guvnor repository.
		</para>

		<para>
			The <property>EGT</property> decorates local resources associated with Guvnor repository master copies. This decoration appears in Eclipse views conforming to the Eclipse Common Navigator framework, such as the Eclipse <guilabel>Resource Navigator</guilabel> and the Java <guilabel>Package Explorer</guilabel>. In the image above you can see the <filename>Dummy rule.drl</filename> file with the decoration in the <guilabel>Resource Navigator</guilabel>. The Guvnor icon decorator is on the top right of the file image, and the Guvnor revision details are appended to the file name. The location of these can be changed in the <guilabel>Local Guvnor Repository Resource Decoration Preferences</guilabel> (see the <xref linkend="resource_decoration_preferences"/> section).
		</para>

		<para>
			Here we see that the <filename>Dummy rule.drl</filename> file is associated with a Guvnor repository resource, and the local copy is based on revision 0, with a <code>02-10-2008, 4:21:53</code> date/time stamp. However, the file <filename>Sample.drl</filename> is not associated with a Guvnor repository file. Further details about the association can be found in the standard Eclipse properties page, accessed via the <guilabel>Properties</guilabel> option in the context menu:
		</para>
	
		<figure>
			<title>Association Details</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/association_details.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			The <property>EGT</property> adds a property page to the standard Eclipse properties dialog, the contents of which are shown above. It displays the specific Guvnor repository, the location within the repository, the version (date/time stamp) and the revision number.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="actions">
		<title>Managing Guvnor Resources</title>

		<para>
			The <property>EGT</property> provides a number of actions (available through the <guilabel>Guvnor</guilabel> context menu on files) for working with files, both those associated with Guvnor repository master copies and those not associated. The actions are:
		</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<xref linkend="update_action"/>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<xref linkend="add_action"/>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<xref linkend="commit_action"/>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<xref linkend="show_history_action"/>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<xref linkend="compare_with_version"/>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<xref linkend="switch_to_version"/>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<xref linkend="delete_action"/>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<xref linkend="disconnect_action"/>
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<para>Each of these actions is described below.</para>

		<section id="update_action">
			<title>Update Action</title>

			<para>
				The <guilabel>Update</guilabel> action is available for one or more Guvnor resources that are not synchronized with the Guvnor repository master copies. These resources would not synchronized due to one or or both of the following conditions:
			</para>
	
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>There are local changes to these resources</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>The master copies have been changed in the Guvnor repository</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>

			<para>
				Performing the <guilabel>Update</guilabel> action replaces the local file contents with the current contents from the Guvnor repository master copies (equivalent to <xref linkend="switch_to_version"/> for the latest version).
			</para>
		</section>

		<section id="add_action">
			<title>Add Action</title>

			<para>The <guilabel>Add</guilabel> action is available for one or more local files that are not associated with a Guvnor repository master copy. Choosing the <guilabel>Add</guilabel> action launches the <guilabel>Add to Guvnor</guilabel> wizard:</para>
	
			<figure>
				<title>Add to Guvnor Wizard</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/add_toGuvnor_wizard.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>

			<para>
				The first page of the wizard asks for the selection of the target Guvnor repository, and provides the option of creating a new Guvnor repository connection (in which case the second page is the same as <xref linkend="guvnor_connection_wizard"/>). Once the target Guvnor repository is chosen, the wizard then asks for the folder location to add the selection files:
			</para>
	
			<figure>
				<title>Selecting a Target Folder</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/select_target_folder.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>

			<para>Here the <filename>defaultPackage</filename> folder is selected as the destination location.</para>

			<note>
				<title>Note:</title>
				<para>
					Note that the <filename>snapshot</filename> folder in the Guvnor repository is read-only for <property>EGT</property>, and hence not visible as a candidate location in this wizard. The Guvnor repository web administration tools must be used to add snapshot content.
				</para>
			</note>

			<para>
				Clicking on the <guibutton>Finish</guibutton> button adds the selected files to the Guvnor repository and creates an association between the local and Guvnor repository files.
			</para>

			<note>
				<title>Note:</title>
				<para>Note that the wizard will not allow existing Guvnor repository files to be overwritten. Another target location must be chosen.</para>
			</note>
		</section>

		<section id="commit_action">
			<title>Commit Action</title>

			<para>
				The <guilabel>Commit</guilabel> action is enabled for one or more Guvnor repository associated files that have local changes. The <guilabel>Commit</guilabel> action will write the local changes back to the associated Guvnor repository files, and update the association for the new revision created.
			</para>

			<para>
				If a local change is based on an older revision of a file than is currently in the Guvnor repository (for example, someone else changed the same file), then the <guilabel>Commit</guilabel> action will ask whether you wish to overwrite the current version in the Guvnor repository with the local content. When such conflicts occur, however, you should use the Eclipse Guvnor version tools, along with Eclipse standard tools, to determine the differences and merge content based on the current version in the Guvnor repository.
			</para>
		</section>

		<section id="show_history_action">
			<title>Show History Action</title>

			<para>
				The <guilabel>Show History</guilabel> action is enabled for one Guvnor repository associated file, and populates the <xref linkend="guvnor_history_view"/> with revision history for the selected file.
			</para>
		</section>

		<section id="compare_with_version">
			<title>Compare with Version Action</title>

			<para>
				The <guilabel>Compare with Version</guilabel> action is enabled for one Guvnor repository associated file. This action first opens a wizard asking for the version for comparison (with the local file contents):
			</para>
	
			<figure>
				<title>Compare with Version Wizard</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/compare_with_version.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>

			<para>Once the revision is selected, the action opens the Eclipse <guilabel>Compare editor</guilabel> (in a read-only mode):</para>
			<figure>
				<title>Eclipse Compare Editor</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/compare_with_version2.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>

			<para>
				This editor uses the standard Eclipse comparison techniques to show the differences in the two versions. In cases where there are no differences, the editor will not open, and instead a dialog saying that there are no differences will be displayed.
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>Alert Dialog</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/compare_with_version3.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</section>

		<section id="switch_to_version">
			<title>Switch to Version Action</title>

			<para>The <guilabel>Switch to Version</guilabel> action is enabled for one Guvnor repository associated file.</para>
			<para>First the <guilabel>Switch to Version</guilabel> action prompts for the selection of a version:</para>
	
			<figure>
				<title>Select Version Window</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/compare_with_version.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>

			<para>
				Once the version is selected, the <guilabel>Switch to Version</guilabel> action replaces the local file contents with those from the revision selected.
			</para>
		</section>

		<section id="delete_action">
			<title>Delete Action</title>

			<para>
				The <guilabel>Delete</guilabel> action is enabled for one or more Guvnor repository associated files. After the action has been confirmed using the dialog shown below, the <guilabel>Delete</guilabel> action removes the files in the Guvnor repository and deletes local metadata for the Guvnor repository association.
			</para>
 	
			<figure>
				<title>Confirm Delete Dialog</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/confirm_delete.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</section>

		<section id="disconnect_action">
			<title>Disconnect Action</title>

			<para>
				The <guilabel>Disconnect</guilabel> action is enabled for one or more Guvnor repository associated files, and removes local metadata for the Guvnor repository association.
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
   

</chapter>
