<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<chapter id="overview">
   <title>JBoss BPEL editor project Overview</title>

   <para>JBoss BPEL editor project is a WS-BPEL 2.0 editor that give a way to create, edit, validate and deploy BPEL files into JBoss BPEL runtime. It is based on the Eclipse 
        <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/bpel/">BPEL</ulink>
   project. </para>
   
   <para>It improves the Eclipse BPEL project in the following way: </para>
   <itemizedlist>
       <listitem> Tight integration with JBoss BPEL runtime. Add a new project type for the deployment to JBoss BPEL runtime</listitem>
       <listitem> Support two ways to deploy: one is deploy a bpel project directly into JBoss BPEL runtime. The other is deploy bpel files in the JBoss ESB project into JBoss BPEL runtime. </listitem>
       <listitem> Improve the BPEL validator and the Eclipse BPEL editor's quality. </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   
   <para>
   <ulink url="http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsbpel/2.0/OS/wsbpel-v2.0-OS.html">WS-BPEL 2.0</ulink> 
   stands for Web Service Business Process Execution Language. Like EAI, BPEL is an XML-based language, but BPEL is more specific and targeted. Specifically, a programmer uses BPEL to join sometimes disparate functions into an integrated process, resulting in a seamless use of the Internet to conduct business transactions ranging from simple money exchanges to complex calculations and asset reallocation.
   </para>

<section>
    <title>Key Features of JBoss BPEL editor project</title>
    <para>For a start, we propose you to look through the table of main features of JBoss BPEL editor project: </para>
    
    <table>
        
        <title>Key Functionality for JBoss BPEL editor project</title>
        <tgroup cols="2">          
            <colspec colnum="1" align="left" colwidth="2*"/>
            <colspec colnum="2" colwidth="4*"/>
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry>Feature</entry>
                    <entry>Benefit</entry>
                  
                </row>
            </thead> 
            <tbody>            
                <row>
                    <entry><para>WS-BPEL 2.0 support</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>JBoss BPEL editor project supports the newest WS-BPEL 2.0 specifications. </para></entry>   
                </row>          
                <row>
                    <entry><para>Tight integration with JBoss BPEL runtime</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>There are two ways to deploy BPEL files into JBoss BPEL runtime. User can deploy a BPEL project as a whole and can deploy BPEL files in JBoss ESB project into JBoss BPEL runtime. </para></entry> 
                </row>               
                <row>
                    <entry><para>A BPEL file editor</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>User can use the editor freely to edit a BPEL file. </para></entry>  
                </row>               
                <row>
                    <entry><para>A BPEL file validator</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>The validator can give the error messages about BPEL files to user. </para></entry>  
                </row>                              
            </tbody>           
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
</section>

</chapter>