    <preface id="preface" revision="1">
        <title>Preface</title>
        <section>
        	<title>Foreword</title>
        	<para>
        		JBoss-IDE started with an XDoclet plug-in for eclipse in the middle of 2002.
        		Then Hans Dockter met Marc as he participated at a JBoss training in Mallorca and they talked about the possibility of developing a JBoss-IDE.
        	</para>
        </section>
        <section>
        	<title>About the Authors</title>
        	<para>
        		<itemizedlist>
        			<listitem>Marshall Culpepper is the project lead of JBoss-IDE. Marshall is a full time employee of JBoss, Inc. And lives in Dallas, Texas.</listitem>
        			<listitem>Laurent Etiemble, is an active contributor to the JBoss-IDE project. Laurent works as a consultant and lives in Paris, France.</listitem>
        			<listitem>Hans Dockter, was the founder and lead architect of the Jboss-IDE project. Hans works as an independent consultant and lives in Berlin, Germany.</listitem>
        		</itemizedlist>
        	</para>
        </section>
        <section>
        	<title>About JBoss</title>
        	<para>
        		JBoss Project, headed by Marc Fleury, is composed of over 100 developers worldwide who are working to deliver a full range of J2EE tools,
        		making JBoss the premier Enterprise Java application server for the Java 2 Enterprise Edition platform.
        	</para>
        	<para>
				JBoss is an Open Source, standards-compliant, J2EE application server implemented in 100% Pure Java.
				The JBoss/Server and complement of products are delivered under a public license. With a huge amount of downloads per month, JBoss is the most downloaded J2EE based server in the industry.
			</para>
        </section>
        <section>
        	<title>Acknowledgements</title>
        	<para>
	        	We would like to thank Thomas Deichsel and Frank Henze from media-style.com for their wonderful interface design. We would also like to thank all the JBoss-IDE community for their support and their feedback.
        	</para>
        </section>
    </preface> 