<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "JBoss_Tools_Reference_Guide_Template.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<chapter id="template_overview">
  <title>Template overview</title>
  	<para>
	This template originated from a request to create JBoss Tools reference material in a format similar to the Dali User Guide. The template serves as an example for the consistent generation of material by writers and developers with standards introduced for the reuse of material.
	</para> 
	<para>
	The Dali User Guide is based on the DITA format, however, this document deviates from the DITA format in a number of areas. These modifications were applied to assist in the production of the material in DocBook XML and to improve the useability of the document.
	</para>
	<orderedlist>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Sections titles are repeated throughout the Concepts, Tasks, Error messages and Hints sections.
	    </para>
	    <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
	      <listitem>
	        <para>
	          The base document can be produced following researching the topic by categorising information according to the features implemented by the Tool (where a feature is a "Concept" which is implemented by the tool).
	        </para>
	      </listitem>
	      <listitem>
	        <para>
	          When writing the material, the author can easily identify related material and update the relevant sections as tasks are performed.
	        </para>
	      </listitem>
	      <listitem>
	        <para>
	          Identifying related material for the generation of links is simplified when a information is categorised.
	        </para>
	      </listitem>
	      <listitem>
	        <para>
	          The reader is aware of the tasks, error messages and hints that relate to a particular concept which orientates the reader and reinforces the concepts.
	        </para>
	      </listitem>
	    </orderedlist>    
	  </listitem>
	  <listitem>
	    <para>
	      Field description tables are included with the related dialog within a task.
	    </para>
	      <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
	        <listitem>
	          <para>
	            While performing a task, information about a field within a dialog can be obtained without having to refer to the reference section.
	          </para>
	        </listitem>
	        <listitem>
	          <para>
	            Options in dropdown lists are presented in secondary tables immediately following the parent table within the relavant task.
	          </para>
	        </listitem>  
	      </orderedlist>
	  </listitem>
	 <listitem>
	   <para>
	     A single document navigation chapter is included to simulate a DITA "related concepts tasks and references" for context sensitive help.
	   </para>
	   <orderedlist numeration="loweralpha">
	     <listitem>
	       <para>
	         Links to related tasks and concepts are stored in a single chapter minimising document maintenance.
	       </para>
	     </listitem>
	     <listitem>
	       <para>
	         Related material such as tasks and concepts can be bundled with the relevant document navigation section for reuse.
	       </para>
	     </listitem>
	   </orderedlist>
	 </listitem>  	
	</orderedlist>
	<para>
		  Procedures have been extracted into separate file for reuse. Those procedures (tasks) which relate to Eclipse generally are denoted as proc-jbt-*.xml. Any procedure relating to a particlar tool, such as Java Server Faces (jsf) is denoted as proc-jsf-*.xml. Images and tables are named according to the same conventions for reuse. Design notes and procedure template descriptions have been included to assist writers and developers in the use of this template. These are denoted by "***Title***" within a "Notes" visual alert. 
    </para>
	<!-- 
	 a) 
	 </para>
	 <para>
     * 
     </para>
     <para>
     * 
     </para>
     <para>
     * identifying related material for the generation of links is simplified when a repeated structure is used
     </para>
     <para>       
     * the reader is aware what tasks, error messages and hints relate to particular concepts which assists in orientating the reader and understanding the material
     </para>
     <para>
      
     b) field description tables are included with the related dialog within a task
     </para>
     <para>
     * while performing a task, obtaining information about a field within a dialog can be achieved without referring to the reference section
     </para>
     <para>
       
     c) a single document navigation chapter is included to simulate a DITA "related concepts tasks and references" for context sensitive help.
     </para>
     <para>
     * links to related tasks and concepts are stored in a single chapter minimising document maintenance
     </para>
      -->
</chapter>
