<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<section id="Issues-fixed-in-this-release">
    <title>
        Features added and issues fixed in version 4.1.1
    </title>
<!--    <para>
        The following list highlights new features that have been added to this release, as well as listing notable bug fixes. You can find a complete list of bug fixes <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/browse/JBIDE">here</ulink>.
	</para> -->
	<formalpara>
      <title>BPEL</title>
        <para>
			<itemizedlist>					
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1806">JBDS-1806</ulink>: Validation within the BPEL editor would not show malformed XML and unknown extensions as errors. This would cause code to fail without prior warning. In this release these issues are correctly flagged as validation errors in the BPEL editor, allowing for prior warning before publishing the code.
					</para>
				</listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
	</formalpara>
<!--    <formalpara>
      <title>Contexts and Dependency Injection (CDI)</title>
        <para>
			<itemizedlist>					
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
					</para>
				</listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
	</formalpara> -->
	<!-- Deltacloud is only shipped with JBoss.org -->
	<!--
	<formalpara>
		<title>Deltacloud</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
 <!--   <formalpara>
        <title>Drools</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
	</formalpara> -->
<!--    <formalpara>
        <title>ESB</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
	</formalpara> -->
	<!-- Google Web Toolkit is only shipped with JBoss.org -->
    <!--
    <formalpara>
        <title>Google Web Toolkit</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:				
                    </para>
				</listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </formalpara> -->
    <!--<formalpara>
        <title>Hibernate</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
                    <para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </formalpara>-->
    <formalpara>
        <title>jBPM</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-3727">JBIDE-3727</ulink>: When editing the name of a node in source view (and more than one node is present), performing backspace or delete actions would not work correctly, missing characters and when typing a new name it would appear backwards. These issues have been corrected in this release by using the <classname>org.eclipse.swt.widgets.Display</classname> class and updating semantic element variables to be <property>final</property>. The results from editing node names is now as expected.
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </formalpara>
	<!--<formalpara>
		<title>JBoss Enterprise Portal Platform</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>-->
   <!-- <formalpara>
        <title>JavaServer Faces (JSF)</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </formalpara>-->
   <!-- <formalpara>
        <title>JBoss Application Server</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
            	<listitem>
                    <para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </formalpara>-->
    <!-- Include in JBT Release Notes only!!! -->
    <!--	
	<formalpara>
		<title>Maven</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
					</para>
				</listitem>
	        </itemizedlist>
		</para>
    </formalpara> -->
    	
	<formalpara>
		<title>Portlet</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-9103">JBIDE-9103</ulink>: When creating a JSF portlet project on a 64bit operating system, the <guilabel>Installing JSF Facet</guilabel> process would hang and project creation would fail. This issue has been corrected by modifying the <filename>AbstractLibraryProviderInstallOperationConfig.java</filename> file by implementing a facet project listener and correcting an error of an extra bracket in a section of code.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-9013">JBIDE-9013</ulink>: An issue existed that would not allow the Seam Portlet example to be deployed to JBoss Enterprise Portal Platform (EPP) 4.3. The problem was caused by a change in how Web Tools Platform (WTP) deployment is undertaken. Where this used to be done through the Java build path, WTP now deploys source folders based on the WTP <filename>component.xml</filename> file. The example has now been updated to support this change.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>RichFaces</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
	<formalpara>
        <title>Seam</title>
        	<para>
          	<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1818">JBDS-1818</ulink>: Drools libraries were upgraded in Enterprise Application Platform 5.1.1 and the Seam tooling did not take this into account. As a result, the Seam Project wizard needed to be updated to replace the JAR <filename>core.jar</filename> to be <filename>ecj.jar</filename> in the project classpath. This update has been applied in this release and allows the Seam Project wizard to use Drools libraries correctly.
					</para>	
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </formalpara>	
	<!--<formalpara>
		<title>Smooks</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>-->
   <!-- <formalpara>
		<title>Struts</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>-->
	<formalpara>
		<title>Teiid Designer</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1065">TEIIDDES-1065</ulink>: The Salesforce translator included with Teiid Designer has been upgraded from version 17 of the API to version 22. This update has also seen modifications made to the <filename>modelgenerator.salesforce</filename> plug-in to work correctly with the new API. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1064">TEIIDDES-1064</ulink>: When attempting to override a property on the translator, after saving the VDB and deploying it to the server, an error would occur informing <errorname>VDB Not Deployed</errorname>. The consequence of this was that a user had to manually copy the VDB to the server. To correct the issue Teiid Designer has been updated to validate a VDB against a list of translators that also include overrides. This ensures that a VDB that contains a translator override will still deploy correctly.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1058">TEIIDDES-1058</ulink>: When importing a VDB file into a different project than the one it was created in, a <errorname>java.lang.IllegalArgumentException</errorname> would occur upon double-clicking a model in the <guilabel>VDB Editor</guilabel>. To fix the issue a check for any null path values has been added prior to opening the editor. This ensures that the error is no longer seen and instead double-clicking a model within the <guilabel>VDB Editor</guilabel> that is not in the workspace will not produce any outcome. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1044">TEIIDDES-1044</ulink>: An interface error existed once the <guilabel>Dependency Diagram</guilabel> view had been opened that disallowed a user to return to the previous view. The consequence was that a user would have to close the model or search to find a way to go to another view. To correct the problem the <classname>ShowParentDiagramAction</classname> class is utilized through a new toolbar and context menu to allow a user a way to easily switch between views. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1042">TEIIDDES-1042</ulink>: The path to the ModeShape connection profile icon was incorrect, causing a red icon to appear in its place. The issue was fixed by correcting the path to the ModeShape icon within the correct <filename>plug-in.xml</filename> file.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1041">TEIIDDES-1041</ulink>: There was confusion with the Teiid driver called <guilabel>Teiid Preview Driver</guilabel>. The name of the driver allowed an assumption that it was only used when previewing a VDB, however it is also used when executing a VDB from the workspace. To better capture the role of the driver it has been renamed to <guilabel>Teiid Driver (default)</guilabel>. This renaming also ensures that as a user creates their own driver instances it is easy to identify the default.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1039">TEIIDDES-1039</ulink>: The VDB dialog contained columns of defined widths causing some columns to need manual width adjustment in order to see all the text contained within it, while other columns contained nothing but were assigned a large allowance of space. To fix this usability issue the <filename>VdbEditor.java</filename> has been edited to utilize the <code>getColumn().pack()</code> command that adjusts column widths for best readability, depending on the text within them. By incorporating this change it ensures an improved user experience when using the VDB dialog.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1035">TEIIDDES-1035</ulink>: Within the <guilabel>Create Data Source</guilabel> wizard, the <guilabel>Connection Properties</guilabel> table contains a column called <guilabel>Data Source Name</guilabel>. The column should actually only be called <guilabel>Name</guilabel>. The column name has been changed in this version to ensure consistency across wizards. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1032">TEIIDDES-1032</ulink>: An error in the code when a web service data source was created meant that the <property>Endpoint</property> would not be set. This was because the <property>Endpoint</property> property was incorrectly named as <property>WSUrl</property>. Correcting this error within the <filename>IWSProfileConstants.java</filename> file has fixed the issue.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1026">TEIIDDES-1026</ulink>: A bug existed where only DBO schemas could be selected when importing from an SQL server using <guilabel>Import from JDBC</guilabel>. This meant that any other type of schemas in the server database could not be imported although they are supported by Teiid Designer. To correct the issue the code that asks for all the different schemas available in an SQL server database has been modified to allow for multiple types of schemas.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1017">TEIIDDES-1017</ulink>: A new feature has been added that allows for a Teiid Source file to be imported through an import wizard called <guilabel>Metadata from Teiid Metadata File</guilabel>. Once a source file is imported a relational model is generated that contains standard file connector procedures and a virtual model is created or selected for use that contains the file functions required by the table. For further information see the Teiid Designer User Guide for this release.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1016">TEIIDDES-1016</ulink>: Working towards the removal of the relationship metamodel, all non-essential user interface components have been removed and only the relationship diagram is now displayed. The relationship metamodel is being removed as it is no longer be used by Teiid or ModeShape.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-1013">TEIIDDES-1013</ulink>: A bug existed where the RESTful properties of <property>REST-METHOD</property> and <property>URI</property> that are required for RESTful procedures required the names to be all upper-case. This caused errors when users would provide these properties but not all letters were upper-case. Resolving this issue has seen the modification of the <classname>ModelObjectAnnotationHelper</classname> and <classname>GenerateRestWarAction</classname> classes to check that the properties exist regardless of the case-type used.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-992">TEIIDDES-992</ulink>: A new feature has been added that allows the use of <emphasis>Pushdown</emphasis> functions without Java programming. A <emphasis>Pushdown</emphasis> function refers to SQL code that contains a function call as part of the final query, acts upon the actual source or database and is exposed in Teiid Designer as a <emphasis>Source Function</emphasis> (a function that exists or is known by a database source).
					</para>
					<para>
						The addition of this feature ensures that creating a <emphasis>Pushdown</emphasis> function is simpler than it was before, improving usability.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-990">TEIIDDES-990</ulink>: Previously generated RESTEasy WARs accepted only a Uniform Resource e Identifier (URI) and XML parameters and produced only XML. JavaScript Object Notation (JSON) support as input and output has been added for this release and the URI for JSON methods contain <property>json</property> (for example, http://host:port/warname/modelname/json/pathinfo). To utilize XML instead, remove <property>json</property> from the path.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-982">TEIIDDES-982</ulink>: If a SOAP <property>EndPoint</property> was entered for a connection profile it would cause a connection error when exiting the dialog. The error occurred because the key value for the <property>EndPoint</property> was incorrect and never added to the <property>TeiidDataSourceProperty</property> object, which meant the connection could not be referenced correctly. This issue has been corrected through the modification of the <classname>SOAPConnectionInfoProvider</classname> class to correctly contain the <property>EndPoint</property> value and add it to the <property>TeiidDataSourceProperty</property> object for later recall by the connection.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-981">TEIIDDES-981</ulink>: An enhancement has been made to the <guilabel>Preview Data</guilabel> action that asks if a user wants to enable the preview preference and if they wish to create a server (if one does not already exist). The <guilabel>Deploy</guilabel> action has also been updated to ask a user if they wish to create a server, if one does not already exist. These enhancements improve the user experience for Teiid Designer.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-971">TEIIDDES-972</ulink>: New behavior has been implemented when a user imports a model that already exists. Previously importing an existing model would result in a warning message noting that it exists and the update checkbox would not be checked. For this release the behavior has changed so that the update checkbox is checked by default. This change ensures that the <guilabel>Import</guilabel> wizard works as expected.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-971">TEIIDDES-971</ulink>: When a user imported a table with one or more foreign keys, all tables with matching primary keys would also be imported. This could mean that when only one table was necessary, an import could also bring in numerous unnecessary tables for what the user wished to do. In order to allow for a table to be imported regardless of foreign key relationships, an option has been added to the <guilabel>Import Database</guilabel> wizard where a user can select to not import tables that have an incomplete foreign key and primary key relationship amongst the tables selected for import. By allowing the user to make this decision, the number of unnecessary tables that are imported is decreased.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-965">TEIIDDES-965</ulink>: The ability to generate a WAR archive with Message Transmission Optimization Mechanism (MTOM) support has been added for generated SOAP web services. A user can now avoid manually modifying a generated WAR archive to contain MTOM support by generating one that does, straight from the tooling.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-958">TEIIDDES-958</ulink>: A new menu item has been added under <guimenuitem>Metadata</guimenuitem> called <guimenuitem>Show SQL Reserved Words</guimenuitem>. By clicking on this option a new view will open in the workspace that allows a user to search and see if a word they wish to use is within the reserved words list. By exposing this list to the user to makes it easier to identify a reserved word.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-843">TEIIDDES-843</ulink>: The <guilabel>Build XML Documents from XML Schema</guilabel> dialog was larger than necessary, obscuring content below it. To correct this design error the left width hint has been modified within the <filename>AccumulatorPanel</filename> file. This allows for improved size judgment, reducing the dialog size.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-597">TEIIDDES-597</ulink>: An issue in the <classname>TableNotificationHandler</classname> class caused inserted rows of a relational column to appear in reverse order within the table editor. This meant that the tree view and table editor displayed the rows in inconsistent ways. The issue has been corrected by modifying the <filename>TableNotificationHandler.java</filename> file so that rows inserted are displayed correctly within the table editor. This results in both the tree view and table editor displaying the information in the same way.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-369">TEIIDDES-369</ulink>: A new feature has been added that places a green arrow beside any objects that are previewable by a user. The implementation of this new feature ensures that a user does not need to click an object to identify if performing the click action will do anything.		
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/TEIIDDES-332">TEIIDDES-332</ulink>: When creating a new virtual procedure a user was required to remember to insert prologue and postlogue code into the transformation editor. This allowed for common mistakes to occur when a user forgot to insert the correct code. For ease of use prologue and postlogue code is now inserted into the transformation editor automatically when creating a new virtual procedure. The change has reduced the amount of code required to be display on screen and created an improved user experience. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<!--<formalpara>
		<title>Usage</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
				    <para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
				    </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>-->
   <!-- <formalpara>
        <title>Visual Page Editor</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </formalpara>-->
	<formalpara>
		<title>Webservices</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1710">JBDS-1710</ulink>: When using a WSDL (Web Service Definition Language) file to create a new web service, the wizard would not work correctly if the WSDL file contained similar wording to an error that can be generated by the component. By modifying the code within the <classname>AbstractGenerateCodeCommand</classname> class that checks for non-compilation errors from searching for errors based on <property>error:</property> instead of only <property>error</property>, it allows for the word <emphasis>error</emphasis> to now appear in a WSDL without causing issue. Using a WSDL file to create a new web service now works as expected.  
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-9516">JBIDE-9516</ulink>: When creating a Sample RESTful Web Service, the wizard referenced a JAR file that did not exist and an error would occur. The issue has been fixed by ensuring that the wizard looks for a file that has a name starting with <filename>jaxrs-api</filename> and ends with <filename>.jar</filename>. This also allows for the JBoss Developer Studio to automatically use newer versions of the the file in the future. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			</para>
	</formalpara>
<!--    <formalpara>
        <title>Web Tools Platform</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
	</formalpara> -->
    <!--<formalpara>
		<title>XHTML Editor</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>-->
   <!-- <formalpara>
        <title>XML Structured Editor</title>
        <para>
            <itemizedlist>
                <listitem>
                    <para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-0000">JBIDE-0000</ulink>:
                    </para>
                </listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </para>
    </formalpara>-->
    <formalpara>
        <title>General Issues</title>
        <para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-9514">JBIDE-9514</ulink>: Project Example ZIP files that contain empty folders, would not be imported correctly and the empty folders would be excluded, though they are necessary for the project to work (for example, the <filename>src</filename> folder). To fix this issue the <filename>NewProjectExamplesWizard.java</filename> has been modified to allow for empty folders within ZIP files to be imported correctly.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-9381">JBIDE-9381</ulink>: An issue existed that meant the runtime detector did not detect the SOA 5.2 runtime correctly, instead displaying it as 5.1. Correcting this issue has seen the modification of <filename>JBossASHandler.java</filename> to also include 5.2 as a runtime display option, and using the implementation and version properties from <filename>run.jar</filename>.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-9361">JBIDE-9361</ulink>: When importing a project, if it is not faceted or does not contain a primary runtime, the project will not be imported correctly. This could have lead to errors being displayed and projects referencing an incorrect runtime. The issue has been corrected within this release by updating the <filename>WTPRuntimeFix.java</filename> by adding in code to check and handle when a project is not faceted or does not contain a primary runtime. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-9344">JBIDE-9344</ulink>: When a user would import a project ZIP file using the project example framework, an empty sub-folder would appear that was unnecessary. This issue has been corrected in this release by modifying the <filename>NewProjectExamplesWizard.java</filename> file to check the files being imported and ensure the empty sub-folder no longer appears.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-9009">JBIDE-9009</ulink>: The option to create a WAR archive would produce an error and the archive would not be created. The user interface menu item to auto-create a WAR archive has been removed from this release.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-8919">JBIDE-8919</ulink>: A new feature has been added that allows for the ESB Runtime within the JBoss Service Oriented Architecture Platform to be separately identified and defined for individual use.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7052">JBIDE-7052</ulink>: An error existed where the optional dependency of <filename>org.hibernate.eclipse</filename> would not be resolved correctly within the BIRT component file <filename>ConsoleConfigurationOdaFactory.java</filename>. This caused any import of the plug-in to fail. The issue has been corrected by setting the <filename>org.hibernate.eclipse</filename> plug-in as required within the BIRT plug-ins <filename>MANIFEST.MF</filename> file.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
        </para>
	</formalpara>
</section>
