<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<section id="Issues-fixed-in-this-release">
	<title>
		Features added and issues fixed in this release
	</title>
	
	<para>
		Following is a list of new and noteworthy features and bug fixes in this release:
	</para>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Contexts and Dependency Injection (CDI)</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7025">JBIDE-7025</ulink>: OpenOn support has been added for the <filename>beans.xml</filename> editor. OpenOn support allows you to easily navigate around your project without the use of the <guilabel>Package Explorer</guilabel> or <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel>. This is achieved by using the class and method names in your code as links to those code segments.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6998">JBIDE-6998</ulink>: The <productname>Weld</productname> project extensions (beans_1_1.xsd) are now supported by the <filename>beans.xml</filename> editor.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6983">JBIDE-6983</ulink>: The <filename>beans.xml</filename> editor now correctly supports elements in other namespaces. This has been achieved by supporting any child element of the &lt;beans&gt; root element and providing dynamic extentions to <filename>beans.xml</filename> in order to support different namespaces.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				   <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6742">JBIDE-6742</ulink> and <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6743">JBIDE-6743</ulink>: Error messages have been rewritten to clarify the error that occured. For example, the error message <errorname>Session bean with a parameterized bean class declares any scope other than @Dependent</errorname> has been rewritten to say <errorname>Session bean with a parameterized bean class must have @Dependent scope</errorname>. For a list of all error messages affected view the associated JIRAs. 
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6728">JBIDE-6728</ulink>: Each field injection point that includes an <parameter>Event</parameter> type is now provided with a default bean. For example the injection field <code>@Inject @Any @Tame @Role("Master") Event<TamingCommand> tamingEvent</code> will now have a bean for injection.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6704">JBIDE-6704</ulink>: It is now possible to enable and disable the CDI validator at the project level. To enable project validator settings navigate to <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Project</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Properties</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>CDI Settings</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Validator</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Enable project specific settings</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6642">JBIDE-6642</ulink>: Validation has been added to ensure that <property>@Stereotype</property> annotation has the following annotation components: <property>@Target({TYPE, METHOD, FIELD})</property>, <property>@Target(TYPE)</property>, <property>@Target(METHOD)</property>, <property>@Target(FIELD)</property> or <property>@Target({METHOD, FIELD})</property>, and <property>@Retention(RUNTIME)</property>.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6641">JBIDE-6641</ulink> and <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6640">JBIDE-6640</ulink>: The OpenOn menu for injection points has been upgraded to present more information concerning eligible beans and indicates the class or classes that will be injected.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6639">JBIDE-6639</ulink>: Validation has been added to ensure that <property>@Scope</property> and <property>@NormalScope</property> annotation have the following annotation components: <property>@Target({TYPE, METHOD, FIELD})</property> and <property>@Retention(RUNTIME)</property>.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6637">JBIDE-6637</ulink>: Validation has been added to ensure that <property>@Qualifier</property> and <property>@NormalScope</property> annotation have the following annotation components: <property>@Target({METHOD, FIELD, PARAMETER, TYPE})</property> and <property>@Retention(RUNTIME)</property>.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6636">JBIDE-6636</ulink>: Errors in the <property>@Typed</property> annotation applied to the <classname>Bean</classname> class, <methodname>Producer</methodname> method and the <property>Producer</property> field were not reported on. If <property>@Typed</property> annotation errors are present in these circumstances, the errors are now reported to the user.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6635">JBIDE-6635</ulink>: A bug existed that would ignore the decorator of a class and take a user straight to the bean when choosing the <guimenuitem>Open Injected Class</guimenuitem> option. This issue has been corrected by expanding on the list of options to choose from. New options include <guimenuitem>Open Decorator NAME</guimenuitem> and <guimenuitem>Open Interceptor NAME</guimenuitem>
				   </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<formalpara>
	   <title>Deltacloud</title>
	   <para>
	      <itemizedlist>
		 <listitem>
		    <para>
		    <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6837">JBIDE-6837</ulink>: Deltacloud tooling has been added for this release.
		 </para>
	      </listitem>
	   </itemizedlist>
	</para>
	</formalpara>
	<formalpara>
		<title>ESB</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				 <listitem>
				    <para>
				       <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7193">JBIDE-7193</ulink>: New optional parameters <parameter>ruleMultithreadEvaluation</parameter> and <parameter>ruleMaxThreads</parameter> have been added to the <classname>BussinessRulesProcessor</classname> class. <parameter>ruleMultithreadEvaluation</parameter> enables or disables <classname>KnowledgeBase</classname> partitioning. <parameter>ruleMaxThreads</parameter> defines the numer of threads to use when <classname>KnowledgeBase</classname> partitioning is enabled. The default values for these parameters is null, disabling them by default.
				    </para>
				 </listitem>
				 <listitem>
					  <para>
					  <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7235">JBIDE-7235</ulink>: The ESB validator has been extended to cover the <classname>BussinessRulesProcessor</classname> class. This ensures that only one <methodname>ruleSet</methodname> is specified by the <classname>BussinessRulesProcessor</classname>, inhibiting conflicts.
					  </para>
				 </listitem>
				 <listitem>
				    <para>
				       <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7055">JBIDE-7055</ulink>: Eclipse Helios provides a new view called the <guilabel>Annotation Properties</guilabel> view that is focused on JAXB and JAX-WS annotations. The new view is now extended with support for ESB annotations for action definitions. 
				    </para>
				    <para>
					  To open the new <guilabel>Annotation Properties</guilabel> view, navigate to <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Window</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Show View</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Other</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>JAX-WS</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Annotation Properties</guimenuitem></menuchoice> and clicking <guibutton>OK</guibutton>. The view can be filtered to display only ESB annotations by selecting the <guimenuitem>Filters</guimenuitem> option from the <guilabel>Annotation Properties</guilabel> view menu and then selecting all annotation categories except for <guilabel>JBoss ESB</guilabel> and clicking <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
				    </para>
				 </listitem>
				 <listitem>
				    <para>
				       <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6908">JBIDE-6908</ulink>: Support for ESB 4.9 has been added to the ESB project editor.
				    </para>
				 </listitem>
				 <listitem>
				    <para>
				       <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6758">JBIDE-6758</ulink>: An existing <parameter>service</parameter> element without a child <parameter>security</parameter> element would not be be able to have the <parameter>security</parameter> element added through the user interface. To this issue, each <parameter>service</parameter> element now has a <parameter>security</parameter> element and a subsequent <guimenuitem>Security</guimenuitem> form automatically attached in the ESB editor. The <parameter>security</parameter> element can safely be deleted from the <parameter>service</parameter> element code without the <guimenuitem>Security</guimenuitem> form being removed in the ESB editor. This ensures that if a user wishes to re-add a <parameter>security</parameter> element at a later stage, the functionality will exist to do so within the user interface. 
				    </para>
				 </listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
        </formalpara>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Google Web Toolkit</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					   <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7092">JBIDE-7092</ulink>: Support has been added for the Google Web Toolkit (GWT) Designer. To use this functionality do the following:					
				       </para>
				       <orderedlist>
					  <listitem>
					     <para>
						Install the GWT Designer from <ulink url="http://dl.google.com/eclipse/inst/d2gwt/latest ">http://dl.google.com/eclipse/inst/d2gwt/latest</ulink>
					     </para>
					  </listitem>
					  <listitem>
					     <para>
						Create a dynamic web project and active the GWT facet
					     </para>
					  </listitem>
					  <listitem>
					     <para>
						Build the included GWT examples
					     </para>
					  </listitem>
					  <listitem>
					     <para>
						Right-click on <filename>Gwt_jboss.java</filename> and choose <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Open with</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>WindowBuilder Editor</guimenuitem></menuchoice> from the menu
					     </para>
					  </listitem>
					  <listitem>
					     <para>
						Switch the editor to the <guilabel>Designer</guilabel> tab
					     </para>
					  </listitem>
				       </orderedlist>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<formalpara>
		<title>Hibernate</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					  <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6988">JBIDE-6988</ulink>: Console configuration would not take into account the schema and catalog being specified for a JPA project. This meant that if two schemas existed for one databse when a user opened the created console confitguration, it would error indicating there was two database schemas. The expected result is that the schema that has been set for the project would be used.
					</para>
					<para>
					  Expected behavior has been implemented by setting a <property>default_schema</property> property in the properties for the project as if this was being set in the <filename>hibernate.properties</filename> file. However properties in the <filename>hibernate.properties</filename> file will overwrite project properties.
				        </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6974">JBIDE-6974</ulink>: Support for comments in the HQL editor has been added for this release. Comments are annotated with <emphasis>--</emphasis> at the beginning of each comment line.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6727">JBIDE-6727</ulink>: When a JPA project is created with Hibernate a console configuration is automatically created for it. However if a Hibernate JPA project did not have a console configuration associated with it an exception would occur due to the tooling assuming a console configuration existed. To avoid this situation, Hibernate JPA projects are now tested for an associated console configuration. If a console configuration is not found an error will appear in the <guilabel>Problems</guilabel> view.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6703">JBIDE-6703</ulink>: The <classname>QueryExporter</classname> has been added to the exporters for use in Hibernate code generation configurations. This is accomplished by allowing all Ant export tasks to be executed from the user interface.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6686">JBIDE-6686</ulink>: An error existed where the Hibernate platform to be used was not filtered based on the version of JPA being used. This meant that selecting the JPA version to use would present all Hibernate platforms to the user, with indistinct names. This issue has been corrected by only displaying the Hibernate platform that corresponds to the specified JPA version, and renaming these platforms for easier identification.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	     </formalpara>
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>jBPM</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
						</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
	<formalpara>
		<title>JavaServer Faces (JSF)</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7147">JBIDE-7147</ulink>: The validators create a marker for each problem found when conducting validation. An issue would arise where system performance would be drammatically decreased when an excesive amount of problems were discovered and subsequently marked. To ensure a system does not receive a performance hit, the <guimenuitem>Validator</guimenuitem> preferences screen now includes the ability to set the maximum number of problems reported per file. If there are more issues in a file than the maximum number to be reported, once the reported issues are corrected the others will be reported in subsequent validation attempts.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7086">JBIDE-7086</ulink>: MyFaces uses the library <filename>myfaces-metadata.xml</filename> to enable tag auto-completion, a plug-in that was not supported. MyFaces plug-in library support has been added, allowing for MyFaces tag auto-completion. 
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7021">JBIDE-7021</ulink>: Low performance issues existed for validation of web pages. Performance issues were caused by the XHTML syntax validator performing to slow if a DOCTYPE was not declared at the top of XHTML files, the <methodname>PageContextFactory.createPageContext</methodname> method created a SSE model for non-facelet pages, if a page contained Expression Language (EL) errors or warnings, a memory leak appeared in the <methodname>PageContextFactory.getSheetForTagAttribute</methodname> method by registerting <classname>ExtendedLinkElementAdapter</classname> and never releasing the memory allocated to it. These issues have been addressed in this release and the <classname>PageContextFactory</classname> class has been removed from the resource listeners since resources can be modified without changing their context in other places apart from the included validators. 
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6816">JBIDE-6816</ulink>: A template page for RichFaces has been added to the list of available XHTML templates.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6815">JBIDE-6815</ulink>: A template page has been added that does not incorporate Facelets.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	     </formalpara>
	     <formalpara>
		<title>JBoss Application Server</title>
		<para>
		   <itemizedlist>
		      <listitem>
			 <para>
			      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6973">JBIDE-6973</ulink>: A HTTP poller has been added for JBoss servers to detect if the server is running. This added feature will be useful for remote and local servers, being less resource-intensive than polling with JMX.
		      </para>
		   </listitem>
		   <listitem>
		      <para>
			 <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6796">JBIDE-6796</ulink>: Launch configuration of the server can now be altered to perform different tasks based on the server mode; sample modes include local and Remote System Explorer (RSE). This added functionality has been achieved by separating launch behaviour into seperate classes.
		      </para>
		   </listitem>
		   <listitem>
		      <para>
			 <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6707">JBIDE-6707</ulink>: The ability to <option>Explore</option> a specific resource on a server has now been expanded to encapsulate the entire server, allowing the deploy directory to be explored.
		      </para>
		   </listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
	     </para>
	</formalpara>
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>Portlet</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	     </formalpara> -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>RichFaces</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
	<formalpara>
		<title>Seam</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					   <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6877">JBIDE-6877</ulink> and <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6875">JBIDE-6875</ulink>: When a user writes code for the Seam component that won't compile, new quick fixes are now presented through annotations. Quick fixes include the ability to quickly add a <property>Name</property> annotation to the class and delete a <property>Create</property>, <property>Unwrap</property> or <property>Observer</property> annotation from the method.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6876">JBIDE-6876</ulink>: The quick fix annotation suggestions for the <methodname>Destroy</methodname> method have been updated to remove <guimenuitem>Set Seam properties</guimenuitem> option. This option should not have been presented in this situation. 
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6874">JBIDE-6874</ulink>: Quick fix now offers to delete any <property>Remove</property> annotation. 
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6873">JBIDE-6873</ulink> and <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6871">JBIDE-6871</ulink>: For <property>Scope</property> annotation, quick fix now offers to change a component's scope. 
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6870">JBIDE-6870</ulink>: Quick fix now offers to create a new method with <property>Remove</property> or <property>Destroy</property> annotation. These annotations are also offered as additions to existing methods.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6869">JBIDE-6869</ulink>: Quick fix now offers to rename a component if it is a duplicate and to delete <property>Name</property> annotation.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>Smooks</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>Struts</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
	
<!-- Only for JBT Release Notes -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>Usage</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
				    <para>
				       <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7144">JBIDE-7144</ulink>: A preference page is provided that details all settings currently being reported. 
				    </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				    <para>
				       <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7142">JBIDE-7142</ulink>: Originally usage reporting only reported an operating system version if it was either Macintosh or Windows, missing Linux. Support for reporting Linux operating system versions was added through completion of this issue.
				    </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7082">JBIDE-7082</ulink>: Originally usage reporting would only report on components that started with <filename>org.jboss.tools</filename>, excluding components such as the application server and Hibernate. Reporting of these components has been achieved by the modification of the <filename>JBossToolsComponents.java</filename> file.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7041">JBIDE-7041</ulink>: Originally usage reporting would not report on the version of the application being used. This information is useful to us as it gives an indication of how fast users move to a newly released version. Functionality for this is now included in the usage plug-in.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7034">JBIDE-7034</ulink>, <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-">JBIDE-</ulink> and <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-">JBIDE-</ulink>: New reporting fields were added to the usage plug-in for the gathering of user data. See the individual JIRAs for specific field details.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->	
	
	<formalpara>
		<title>Visual Page Editor</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7059">JBIDE-7059</ulink>: XulRunner (XR) has become an optional install of the Visual Page Editor. This decision has meant that the buttons of the Visual Page Editor plug-in have been moved to be apart of the Eclipse icon bar.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6981">JBIDE-6981</ulink>: Functionality has been added that provides a drop-down menu in the tag breadcrumbs that enables easy selection of any child element to the selected tag. If there are no children to be expanded, the last tag will remain highlighted.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6805">JBIDE-6805</ulink>: New templates have been added, supporting most docbook tags.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6721">JBIDE-6721</ulink> and  <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6711">JBIDE-6711</ulink>: Spring support has been added to the Visual Page Editor through the addition of a new plug-in. The plug-in is available as <filename>org.jboss.tools.vpe.spring</filename>.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<formalpara id="Fixed_Issues-Web_Tools_Platform">
		<title>Web Tools Platform</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					    <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-7106">JBIDE-7106</ulink>: Annotations have been added for JAX-RS (Java API for RESTful Web Services). This addition has been accomplished by modifying the <guilabel>Annotation Properties</guilabel> view.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6904">JBIDE-6904</ulink>: A new wizard is available for creating JAX-WS and JAX-RS services from annotated class files. If the classes do not exist upon creation of the services, they will be created during service creation, the same as if the user had used the <guilabel>Create a Sample Web Service</guilabel> or <guilabel>Create a Sample RESTful Web Service</guilabel> wizards.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6851">JBIDE-6851</ulink> and <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6850">JBIDE-6850</ulink>: A new feature has been added providing the ability to read Web Service Definition Language (WSDL) over HTTPS. This ensures that secured <methodname>GET</methodname> and <methodname>POST</methodname> methods are usable and will not produce a <exceptionname>com.sun.xml.internal.ws.wsdl.parser.InaccessibleWSDLException: 2 counts of InaccessibleWSDLException</exceptionname> exception.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6797">JBIDE-6797</ulink>: A new <guimenuitem>Options</guimenuitem> menu item has been added to the Web Services interface for JAX-RS. The <guimenuitem>Options</guimenuitem> menu item allows a user to test RESTful web services for allowed HTTP methods such as <methodname>POST</methodname> and <methodname>GET</methodname>. Results from the <guimenuitem>Options</guimenuitem> operation are viewable in the <property>Response Headers</property> list.
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6753">JBIDE-6753</ulink>: In JBoss Application Server 6 no entries are required in the <filename>web.xml</filename> file, however entries remain mandatory for earlier releases. To reflect this upgrade, the <guilabel>Generate a Sample RESTful Web Service</guilabel> wizard now contains a checkbox to <guilabel>Update web.xml</guilabel>. By default the update option is enabled. If a user is aware that JBoss Application Server 6 is being utilized and they do not wish to update the <filename>web.xml</filename> file, this checkbox can be unchecked. 
				   </para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
				   <para>
				      <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6660">JBIDE-6660</ulink>: A bug existed in the Web Services tooling such that when a user attempted to connect with a password protected URL (for example, a deltacloud) a dialog would appear requesting a username and password combination, however when the information was submitted it would not persist; this ensured the user would be asked for login details continually. This issue has been fixed by the creation of a new dialog that remembers the authentication information last used, however login information is not currently persisted between sessions (for example, closing and then reopening a workbench).
				   </para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	     </formalpara>
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>XHTML Editor</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>XML Structured Editor</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
	<formalpara>
		<title>General Issues</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
			   <!-- This issue only in release notes for JBT -->
		<!--	   <listitem>
			      <para>
				 <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6836">JBIDE-6836</ulink> and <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6695">JBIDE-6695</ulink>: Google Web Toolkit features are available for JBoss Tools through the update site as experimental. 
			      </para>
			   </listitem> -->
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	     </formalpara>
</section>
