<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<section id="Issues-fixed-in-this-release">
    <title>
        Enhancements and fixed issues in version 5.0.1
    </title>
	<variablelist>
		<!-- JBIDE-12177 -->
		<varlistentry>
		<term>
			<ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12177">JBIDE-12177</ulink>
		</term>
		<listitem>
			<para>
				The feature to auto-complete code tags was broken in the Visual Editor. When attempting to auto-complete a code tag, invalid code would be generated. This has been corrected by modifying the content assist file XmlTagCompletionProposalComputer.java to ensure partner code tags are generated correctly when using auto-completion.
			</para>
		</listitem>
	</varlistentry>
	
	<!-- JBIDE-12158 -->
	<varlistentry>
	<term>
		<ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12158">JBIDE-12158</ulink>
	</term>
	<listitem>
		<para>
			An issue existed when creating a Dynamic Web Project and modifying the project to include the JBoss Core Portlet facet to the project. The portlet-api library was not detected in the target runtime, forcing the user to manually specify it via the user library. This has been corrected by adding the option, Portlet Target Runtime Provider, to the combo-box on the JBoss Portlet Capabilities wizard page.
		</para>
	</listitem>
</varlistentry>

   <!-- JBIDE-12111 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12111">JBIDE-12111</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   The version of Java to be used was hard coded in the pom.xml file of Maven projects. This caused errors when adding Maven configuration to a Seam 2.3 project since Maven projects were created to use Java 1.5, however Seam 2.3 requires Java 1.6. Maven tooling has been updated to allow the maven-compiler-plugin settings that are in the parent project to be dynamically inferred from the converted web project's original settings. This ensures the correct Java version is retained when Maven integration is added to an existing project.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   <!-- JBIDE-12071 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12071">JBIDE-12071</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   Previously, when a user performed a drag-and-drop action to publish a project it was ignored. This occurred because the code to publish a project only accepted direct user-initiated actions and not those considered to be a shell action. The ExpressPublishMethod.java and ExpressBehaviour.java files have been updated to handle shell actions correctly. As a result, incremental publishes initiated by the user are now also handled correctly.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   <!-- JBIDE-12046 -->
   <varlistentry>
   <term>
	   <ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12046">JBIDE-12046</ulink>
   </term>
   <listitem>
	   <para>
		   When a user tried to start or deploy to a remote server that was no longer reachable, various errors would be returned, however no adequate description of the issue was communicated. This issue has been resolved by returning a descriptive error when the remote server is unreachable and checking for file system responsiveness before attempting to publish.
	   </para>
   </listitem>
   </varlistentry>
   
   <!-- JBIDE-11310 -->
   <varlistentry>
      <term><ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-11310">JBIDE-11310</ulink></term>
      <listitem>
         <para>
         An issue in the OpenShift tooling meant that if a user logged into OpenShift and created an application, then went back to the login screen and signed in as a different user, the previous application parameters would still be available. This meant the second user was not able to create an application with the same parameters, and was also able to view what the previous user had created, causing a potential security issue. OpenShift tooling has been updated to reset  when a new user connects, triggering a refresh of the targets and parameters.
         </para>
      </listitem>
   </varlistentry>

</variablelist>



</section>
