<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<section id="Issues-fixed-in-this-release">
	<title>
		Features added and issues fixed in this release
	</title>
	
	<para>
		Following is a list of new and noteworthy features and bug fixes in this release:
	</para>
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>Contexts and Dependency Injection (CDI)</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>ESB</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>jBPM</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
						</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
	<formalpara>
		<title>Hibernate</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-6075">JBIDE-6075</ulink>: In the Hibernate reverse engineering editor it was impossible to add a parameter as the button to do so was missing. This update corrects the user interface to include the <guibutton>Add parameter</guibutton> button under the <guilabel>Id Generator details</guilabel> <guilabel>Class</guilabel> section.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-5960">JBIDE-5960</ulink>: A new <guibutton>Details ...</guibutton> button has been added to the <guilabel>Hibernate Settings</guilabel> section within the project properties. This added button displays the configuration wizard for the selected console (this wizard is also still available through the <guilabel>Console Configuration</guilabel> view). With the addition of this new button, a consoles configuration wizard is now more easily accessable to the user.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>
	<formalpara>
		<title>JavaServer Faces (JSF)</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-5941">JBIDE-5941</ulink>: A new JSF2 feature has been added that allows a user to type <code>#{cc.attrs.|</code> and have an attribute list returned.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>RichFaces</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>Seam</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-">JBDS-</ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>Smooks</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>Struts</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>Visual Page Editor</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>XHTML Editor</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
<!--	<formalpara>
		<title>XML Structured Editor</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBIDE-"> </ulink>
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara> -->
	<formalpara>
		<title>General Issues</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1215">JBDS-1215</ulink>: The installer was unable to locate the Seam runtimes within the JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 4.3. This occurred because the Seam runtime locations bundled within the JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 4.3 had recently changed from <filename>jboss-eap-4.3/seam</filename> and <filename>jboss-eap-4.3/seamfp</filename> to being <filename>jboss-eap-4.3/seam1</filename> and <filename>jboss-eap-4.3/seam2</filename>. This version of the JBoss Developer Studio includes an updated installer that contains the new Seam runtime locations. The installer is now able to find the Seam runtimes for the latest versions of the JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 4.3.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1187">JBDS-1187</ulink>: An empty URL tag (&lt;url&gt;) caused the <guimenuitem>Classic Update</guimenuitem> option under <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>General</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Capabilities</guimenuitem></menuchoice> to error upon installation of a plug-in. To fix this issue the unused URL element has been removed. The <guimenuitem>Classic Update</guimenuitem> option is now usable and installs plug-ins correctly.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1168">JBDS-1168</ulink>: The JBoss Developer Studio Installer was missleading in terms of system requirements. The consequence of this was that some users were unsure if the JBoss Developer Studio supported Java 6 even though it was required for the JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 5 and which JDK distributions were supported. The text in Step 4 of installation has been updated to inform the user that the JBoss Developer Studio works with both Java 5 and 6 (though Java 6 is required for JBoss Enterprise Application Platform 5), has been tested with the OpenJDK, SunJDK and IBM JDK distributions and the misspelt <emphasis>gij Java</emphasis> has been corrected to <emphasis>gcj Java</emphasis>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1155">JBDS-1155</ulink>: A regression existed in the Eclipse 3.5.2 Web Tools Platform (WTP) 3.1.2. The bug would break EAR deployments that used classpath variables by deploying dependent artifacts to <filename>&lt;root_ear&gt;/lib/lib/lib</filename> instead of <filename>&lt;root_ear&gt;/lib</filename>. The issue has been corrected with these updated packages so that the regression no longer exists and EAR deployments function correctly.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1147">JBDS-1147</ulink>: An incorrect link to the Guvnor Rules repository was included in the JBoss Developer Studio. This bug caused the repository to become unreachable. This has been fixed by correcting the link to be <ulink url="http://localhost:8080/drools-guvnor/org.drools.guvnor.Guvnor/webdav">http://localhost:8080/drools-guvnor/org.drools.guvnor.Guvnor/webdav</ulink>. The JBoss Developer Studio is now able to connect to the Guvnor Rules repository.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1091">JBDS-1091</ulink>: Two bugs were found. A problem was found in the <filename>org.jboss.tools.runtime_1.1.0</filename> plug-in and the visibility of the <property>Instance</property> field was changed from public to private. These bugs respectively caused the JBoss Developer Studio <guilabel>Server View</guilabel> to not display all available servers on occasion after using the installer and jBPM runtimes to not be initialized correctly. The <filename>org.jboss.tools.runtime_1.1.0</filename> plug-in has now been updated to force a refresh of the <guilabel>Server View</guilabel> post installation, which can be verified by a refresh message appearing in the log file and the <filename>org.jboss.tools.jbpm.common</filename> plug-in has been updated to set <code>public static final PreferencesManager INSTANCE = new PreferencesManager();</code>. By correcting the <filename>org.jboss.tools.runtime_1.1.0</filename> plug-in, all installed servers now appear in the <guilabel>Server View</guilabel> directly after installation of the JBoss Developer Studio through the installer. Fixing the <filename>org.jboss.tools.jbpm.common</filename> plug-in now allows for jBPM runtimes to be initialized correctly. Both issues are fixed with this update.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1088">JBDS-1088</ulink>: When installing the JBoss Developer Studio, if a previous installation was detected a dialog box would ask if you wished to overwrite the existing directory. If a user continued with installation they would then have a mixture of the old and new product versions. To better assist users a new warning is displayed in this situation, which indicates that you cannot upgrade by installing a new version over an old version. This new dialog box ensures that a user is informed of what will happen.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>
</section>
