<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<section id="Known_Issues_with_this_release">
	<title>
			Known Issues in version 5.0.0
	</title>
<!--	<para>
		There were no known issues at the time of release.
	</para> -->
	<para> 
			Following is a list of known issues at the time of release.
		</para>
		<variablelist>
			<!-- JBDS-2212 -->
			<varlistentry>
				<term>
					<ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBDS-2212">JBDS-2212</ulink>
				</term>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Features of JBoss Developer Studio may show incorrect version numbers when viewing installation information. Under <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Help</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>About JBoss Developer Studio</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Installation Details</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Features</guimenuitem></menuchoice> some features will display a version number older than the previous release of JBoss Developer Studio. These numbers are incorrect and will be incremented correctly in the future.  
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</varlistentry>
			<!-- JBDS-2180 -->
		<varlistentry>
			<term>
				<ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBDS-2180">JBDS-2180</ulink>
			</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					When installing JBoss Developer Studio 5 on Mac OS X, if you are running Java 7 you will only be able to install the 64bit version of JBoss Developer Studio. The current workaround o install the 32bit version is to use Java 6. 
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<!-- JBIDE-12202 -->
		<varlistentry>
			<term>
				<ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12202">JBIDE-12202</ulink>
			</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					When deploying a project as an exploded archive to a remote server, the publishing process can be slow. It is recommended that users deploy projects as compressed archives to remote servers. This can be enbled by double-clicking the server in the Servers view, navigating to the Deployment page and clicking the checkbox beside the option to Deploy projects as compressed archives. 
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
		<!-- JBIDE-12071 -->
		<varlistentry>
			<term>
				<ulink url="https://issues.jboss.org/jira/browse/JBIDE-12071">JBIDE-12071</ulink>
			</term>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					When adding a project to an OpenShift server using the context menu, or you remove a project from the OpenShift server, no dialog appears to publish or unpublish the project. The current workaround is to manually publish and unpublish a project after performing one of the above actions. 
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</varlistentry>
	</variablelist>
</section>
