<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<section id="Known_Issues_with_this_release">
	<title>
			Known Issues in version 4.1.0
	</title>
	<para> 
			Following is a list of known issues at the time of release.
	</para>
	<formalpara>
		<title>General Known Issues</title>
		<para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
					<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1685">JBDS-1685</ulink>: Upon installing Subclipse from the JBoss Developer Studio Extras site and restarting your JBoss Developer Studio installation, an error exists that sets a default SVN property incorrectly. The workaround for this issue is to navigate to <menuchoice>
                            <guimenuitem>Window</guimenuitem>
                            <guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem>
							<guimenuitem>Team</guimenuitem>
							<guimenuitem>SVN</guimenuitem>
                        </menuchoice>.
					</para>
					<para>
						If you then see an error window, click the <guibutton>OK</guibutton> button. 
					</para>
					<para>
						On the SVN Preferences page, in the <guilabel>SVN interface</guilabel> section, change the drop-down list value of <guilabel>Client</guilabel> to <guimenuitem>SVNKit (Pure Java) SVNKit v1.3.5.7406</guimenuitem>.
					</para>
					<para>
						Click the <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> button and then the <guibutton>OK</guibutton> button.
					</para>
					<para>
						Subclipse will now function correctly.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/JBDS-1643">JBDS-1643</ulink> and <ulink url="http://jira.jboss.com/jira/browse/SOA-3051">SOA-3051</ulink>: JBoss Developer Studio 4.1 assumes the use of Drools 5.0 or above for project creation. If using an earlier version of Drools or JBoss Rules, code compatibility must be set to your version of Drools or JBoss Rules in the last page of the project creation wizard.
					</para>
					<para>
					If you need to set code compatibility to an older version of Drools or JBoss Rules, you may notice multiple warnings when creating a project relating to the new Drools 5 API. These warnings will not affect your project and can be turned off by navigating to <menuchoice>
                            <guimenuitem>Window</guimenuitem>
							<guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem>
							<guimenuitem>Drools</guimenuitem>
						</menuchoice> and setting the <guilabel>Internal Drools classes are</guilabel> drop-down box to <guilabel>Accessible</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</formalpara>
</section>
