<chapter id="using">
	<title>Using the JBossIDE Build System</title>
	
	<section>
		<title>Quick Start</title>
		<para>The quickest way to get started is to try a nightly build of the entire JBossIDE product. Be warned though, this can take upwards of 20-30 minutes on slower machines, and even longer if publishing is enabled.
		To run a nightly build, from the builders directory, execute:</para>

		<para>On Windows:</para>
		<programlisting>build-nightly.bat product</programlisting>
		<para>On Unix (or cygwin/mingw):</para>
		<programlisting>./build-nightly.sh product</programlisting>
		
		<para>After the build is complete, you should see various zip files in various folders in your build output directory.</para>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Builders and Build Types</title>
		<para>The JBossIDE Build system breaks down builds into 3 seperate types. Integration, Nightly, and Release builds.
		Both integration and nightly builds will append the Ixxxx or Nxxxx string to the end of the current release version of each plugin and feature being built.</para>
		
		<section>
			<title>Nightly builds</title>
			
			<para>Nightly builds will by default pull everything from the "HEAD" of the corresponding CVS repository for each builder. The built archives will all look something like
			JBossIDE-Nxxxxxx.zip</para>
		</section>

		<section>
			<title>Integration builds</title>
			<para>An integration build is mainly used to do a final test of a release before it is deemed "release" quality. An integration build, like a release build, uses a properties file
			that follows the same syntax as below.  Built archives will all look something like JBossIDE-Ixxxxxx.zip</para>
			
			<para>When building an integration build, the build-integration script requires an extra argument; the name of the tag properties file, i.e:</para>
			<programlisting>./build-integration.sh product -tags product/versionTags/1.5RC2.tags</programlisting>
		</section>
		
		<section>
			<title>Release builds</title>
			
			<para>Release builds are special in that they have a "tags" file which maps each builder to a specific sub-version. The name of the tags file is ${release-name}.tags,
			and it lives under builders/product/versionTags. Here is an example from the JBossIDE 1.5RC2 release (1.5RC2.tags):</para>
			
			<programlisting>
#component versions
aop=1.1.0.RC2
ejb3=1.0.0.RC2
core=1.5.0.RC2
hibernate-tools=beta2
jbpm=3.0.5.2
tests=1.0.0

#cvs tags
hibernate-tools.cvs=TOOLS_3_1_0_BETA1JBIDERC2
jbpm.cvs=jbpm_gpd_3_0_5_2
core.cvs=IDE_CORE_1_5_RC2
aop.cvs=IDE_AOP_DEVELOPER_1_1_0_RC2
ejb3.cvs=IDE_EJB3_TOOLS_1_0_RC2
tests.cvs=HEAD</programlisting>
		
			<para>When building a release build, the build-release script requires an extra argument; the release name. i.e:</para>
			<programlisting>./build-release.sh product 1.5RC2</programlisting>
		
		</section>
		
		<section>
			<title>Builders</title>
			
			<para>The build system also supports building standalone builders seperately from the entire product.
			It should be noted that building seperately does not currently support scp publishing, or email notification.
			For example, to do an nightly build of Hibernate Tools:</para>
			<programlisting>./build-nightly.sh hibernate-tools</programlisting>
			
			<para>You can find a list of builders by looking at the directories under the builders directory (everything except common).</para>
		
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>