<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="debugging_rules" xreflabel="debugging_rules">
	<chapterinfo>
		<keywordset>
			<keyword>JBoss Tools</keyword>
			<keyword>Drools Tools</keyword>
		</keywordset>
	</chapterinfo>

	<title>Debugging rules</title>
	
	<para>This chapter describes how to debug rules during the execution of your Drools application.</para>

	<section id="creating_breakpoints">
		<title>Creating Breakpoints</title>
		
		<para>At first, we&apos;ll focus on how to add
		breakpoints in the consequences of your rules.</para>
		
		<para>Whenever such a breakpoint is uncounted
			during the execution of the rules, the execution is halted. It&apos;s possible then inspect the
			variables known at that point and use any of the default debugging actions to decide what
			should happen next (step over, continue, etc). To inspect
			the content of the working memory and agenda the Debug views can be used.</para>

		<para>You can add/remove rule breakpoints in <emphasis>
				<property>.drl</property>
			</emphasis> files in two ways, similar to adding breakpoints to Java files:</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Double-click the ruler in the <property>Rule editor</property> at the line
					where you want to add a breakpoint.</para>
				<tip>
					<title>Tip:</title>
					<para>Note that rule breakpoints can only be created in the consequence of a
						rule. Double-clicking on a line where no breakpoint is allowed will do
						nothing.</para>
				</tip>
				<para>A breakpoint can be removed by double-clicking the ruler once more. </para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>Right-click the ruler. Select <emphasis>
						<property>Toggle Breakpoint</property>
					</emphasis> action in the appeared popup menu. Clicking the action will add a
					breakpoint at the selected line or remove it if there is one already.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<figure>
			<title>Adding Breakpoints</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/debugging_rules/debugging_rules1.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>The <property>Debug perspective</property> contains a <property>Breakpoints
				view</property> which can be used to see all defined breakpoints, get their
			properties, enable/disable or remove them, etc. You can switch to it by navigating to <emphasis>
				<property>Window > Perspective > Others > Debug</property>.</emphasis></para>
	</section>

	<section id="debugging">
		<title>Debugging</title>

		<para>Drools breakpoints are only enabled if you debug your application as a Drools
			Application. To do this you should perform one of the actions:</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select the main class of your application. Right click it and select <emphasis>
						<property>Debug As > Drools Application</property>.</emphasis></para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<figure>
			<title>Debugging Drools Application</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/debugging_rules/debugging_rules2.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Alternatively, you can also go to <emphasis>
						<property>Debug As > Debug Configuration</property>
					</emphasis> to open a new dialog for creating, managing and running debug
					configurations.</para>

				<para>Select the <emphasis>
						<property>Drools Application</property>
					</emphasis> item in the left tree and click the <emphasis>
						<property>New launch configuration</property>
					</emphasis> button (leftmost icon in the toolbar above the tree). This will
					create a new configuration and already fill in some of the properties (like the
					Project and Main class) based on main class you selected in the beginning. All
					properties shown here are the same as any standard Java program.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<figure>
			<title>New Debug Configuration</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/debugging_rules/debugging_rules3.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<tip>
			<title>Tip:</title>
			<para>Remember to change the name of your debug configuration to something meaningful.</para>
		</tip>
		
		<para>Next
			click the <emphasis>
				<property>Debug</property>
			</emphasis> button on the bottom to start debugging your application. </para>

		<para>After enabling the debugging, the application starts executing and will halt if
			any breakpoint is encountered. This can be a Drools rule breakpoint, or any other
			standard Java breakpoint. Whenever a Drools rule breakpoint is encountered, the
			corresponding <emphasis>
				<property>.drl</property></emphasis> file is opened and the active line is highlighted. The Variables view
			also contains all rule parameters and their value. You can then use the default Java
			debug actions to decide what to do next (resume, terminate, step over, etc.). The debug
			views can also be used to determine the contents of the working memory and agenda at
			that time as well (you don't have to select a working memory now, the current executing
			working memory is automatically shown).</para>
		
		
	</section>
</chapter>
