<chapter id="installation">
    <title>Install &amp; Upgrade</title>
    <para>Eclipse offers an easy way to install/upgrade features. It is done by hand the first time and then, Eclipse can check whether updates are available, download them and install them.</para>
    <para>This chapter describes how to install JBoss-IDE with the install/update features of Eclipse, and how to stay up-to-date automatically.</para>
    <section>
    	<title>Eclipse 3.0.x series</title>
    	<para>
    		Follow these steps :
    		<itemizedlist>
    			<listitem>Start Eclipse.</listitem>
    			<listitem>Select <literal>Help</literal> &gt; <literal>Software Updates</literal> &gt; <literal>Find and Install...</literal></listitem>
    			<listitem>Select <literal>Search for new features to install</literal></listitem>
    			<listitem>
    				Select <literal>Add Update Site</literal> from the right menu. In the dialog fill the name with <literal>JBossIDE</literal>
    				and the URL with <ulink url="http://jboss.sourceforge.net/jbosside/updates">http://jboss.sourceforge.net/jbosside/updates</ulink>
    			</listitem>
    			<listitem>
    				Expand the <literal>JBossIDE</literal> tree, and check the feature named <literal>JBoss-IDE 1.0/Eclipse 3.0</literal>.
    				Click Next, and Eclipse will scan for the current releases. After the scan is complete, select the 1.4.0 release and click <literal>Finish</literal>.
    			</listitem>
    			<listitem>At the end of the installation, you will be prompted to restart Eclipse. Click yes.</listitem>
    		</itemizedlist>
    		
			<tip>If you are behind a proxy you have to go to <literal>Window</literal> &gt; <literal>Preferences</literal> &gt; <literal>Install/Update</literal>,
			select <literal>Enable HTTP Proxy Connection</literal> and insert values for <literal>Host Address</literal> and <literal>Port</literal>.</tip>
			
			<tip>You can be notified when new updates are available. You can also configure Eclipse to fetch new updates and make them ready to install.
			All this configuration can be done through the  <literal>Window</literal> &gt; <literal>Preferences</literal> &gt; <literal>Install/Update</literal> &gt; <literal>Automatic Updates</literal> preferences page.</tip>
		
    		Have a look at the Eclipse documentation to get more information about the Install/Update Manager.
			<figure id="jbosside.update">
            <title>Overview of the update search result.</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata align="center" fileref="images/jbosside-update.jpg"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
    	</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
