<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="reference">
    <?dbhtml filename="reference.html"?>
    <chapterinfo>
        <keywordset>
            <keyword>JBoss Tools</keyword>
        </keywordset>
    </chapterinfo>
    <title>Reference</title>
	<para>
		Described are the user interface controls of BPEL Designer, and how they relate to the OASIS standard. If you are new to BPEL it is recommended that you first become familiar with the concepts surrounding the technology, detailed in <xref linkend="concepts"/>.
	</para>
    <section>
        <title>Wizards</title>
        <section>
            <title>New BPEL project</title>
			<para>The New BPEL Project wizard creates a faceted project which allows it to be deployed to the JBoss Riftsaw runtime engine. It is available by selecting <menuchoice>
                <guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem>
                <guimenuitem>New</guimenuitem>
                <guimenuitem>Other</guimenuitem>
                <guimenuitem>BPEL 2.0</guimenuitem>
				<guimenuitem>BPEL Project</guimenuitem>
            </menuchoice>.</para>
            <figure>
                <title>New BPEL Project Wizard</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/reference/New_BPEL_Project.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>The wizard consists of a single page:</para>
            <para>
				Enter the project name and select its location. When the wizard is completed the following files would have been created:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<filename>bpelContent</filename> folder
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						Project facet metadata
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			<para>
				The <filename>bpelContent</filename> folder contains all the files necessary for your project. This includes all WSDL and XSD files.
			</para>
          </section>
     <!-- <section>
            <title>Apache ODE Deployment Descriptor Wizard</title>
            <para>This wizard can be used to create an ODE deployment descriptor (<filename>deploy.xml</filename>) file and place it in the temporary directory. It is available by selecting <menuchoice><guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>New</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Other</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Apache ODE Deployment Descriptor Wizard</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.</para>
            <figure>
                <title>New BPEL Project Wizard</title>
                <mediaobject>
                    <imageobject>
                        <imagedata fileref="images/deploy_createdeploy_2.png"/>
                    </imageobject>
                </mediaobject>
            </figure>
            <para>
            		On this page you can adjust the name of the deployment descriptor and the directory where it will be created. Note that you should use <filename>/PROJECT_NAME/bpelContent</filename> directory for the output.
            </para>
                                   
		</section> -->
        <section>
            <title>New BPEL Process file</title>
            <para>
				The <guilabel>New BPEL Process File Wizard</guilabel> will create a BPEL process based on one of several templates defined by the wizard. The wizard assumes the new BPEL process is to be created in the curently selected project of the <guilabel>Project Explorer</guilabel> or <guilabel>Navigator</guilabel> view. If a BPEL process of the same name already exists within the project, a warning message will be displayed before any action is performed.
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>New BPEL Process</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Create_a_BPEL_Process_File_01.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<itemizedlist>
                <listitem><para>The first page includes the following options:</para>
                    <table>
                        <title>New BPEL Process file wizard. First page options.</title>   
                        <tgroup cols="3">
                            <colspec colnum="1" align="left" colwidth="1*"/>
                            <colspec colnum="2" align="left" colwidth="3*"/>
                            <colspec colnum="3" align="left" colwidth="1*"/>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>									
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                    <entry>Default</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Name</entry>
                                    <entry>Enter the process name.</entry>
                                    <entry>no default value</entry>
                                </row>     
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Namespace</entry>
									<entry>Enter the namespace URL. All namespaces should follow the W3C recommendation (<ulink url="http://www.w3.org/1999/10/nsuri">
										http://www.w3.org/1999/10/nsuri</ulink>). </entry>
                                    <entry>no default value</entry>
                                </row> 
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Template</entry>
                                    <entry>Select one of the provided templates: 
                                        <itemizedlist>
                                            <listitem><para><emphasis>Asynchronous BPEL Process</emphasis>  - 
                                                generates the basis of orchestration logic:  receive and reply activities
                                                are included into the process; client WSDL is generated, 
                                                service is defined in the <property>parentlink</property> of the process.
                                                The caller is notified asynchronously when the process completes.
                                            </para></listitem>
                                            <listitem><para><emphasis>Empty BPEL Process</emphasis>  - list of services participating in this BPEL process together
                                                with the one of messages used within the process is empty.There are no any orchestration logic.</para></listitem>
                                            <listitem><para><emphasis>Synchronous BPEL Process</emphasis>  - 
                                                similar to Asynchronous BPEL Process template except the fact that here
                                                the caller is notified synchronously when the process completes.</para></listitem>
                                        </itemizedlist></entry>
                                    <entry>Asynchronous BPEL Process</entry>
                                </row>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Abstract Process</entry>
                                    <entry>Specifies the created process as an abstract one -partially
                                        specified processes that are not intended to be executed.</entry>
                                    <entry>unchecked</entry>
                                </row>
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>  
					<para>
						The second page of the wizard defines the process interface (WSDL file) including the web service address, port definition and protocol. The wizard will populate all of these fields with appropriate default values based on the information provided on the previous page.
					</para>
                    <figure>
                        <title>New BPEL Process</title>
                        <mediaobject>
                            <imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Create_a_BPEL_Process_File_02.png"/>
                            </imageobject>
                        </mediaobject>
                    </figure>
                    
                </listitem>
                <listitem><para>The second page includes the following options:</para>
                    <table>
                        <title>New BPEL process file wizard. Second page options.</title>   
                        <tgroup cols="3">
                            <colspec align="left" colnum="1" colwidth="1*"></colspec>
                            <colspec align="left" colnum="2" colwidth="3*"></colspec>
                            <colspec align="left" colnum="3" colwidth="1*"></colspec>
                            <thead>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Field</entry>
                                    <entry>Description</entry>
                                    <entry>Default</entry>
                                </row>
                            </thead>
                            <tbody>
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Service Name</entry>
                                    <entry>Enter a WDSL service name for the BPEL process.</entry>
                                    <entry>The process name</entry>
                                </row>                                                                      
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Port Name</entry>
                                    <entry>Enter a WDSL port name for the BPEL process.</entry>
                                    <entry>The process name + 'Port'</entry>
                                </row> 
                                <row>
                                    <entry>Service Address</entry>
                                    <entry>Enter an address of the WDSL service for the BPEL process.</entry>
                                    <entry>http://localhost:8080/ + process name </entry>
                                </row>

                                <row>
                                    <entry>Binding Protocol</entry>
                                    <entry>Choose the binding protocol that you use in the WDSL: SOAP or HTTP</entry>
                                    <entry>SOAP</entry>
                                </row>                                
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>  
				</listitem>
				<!--	<important>
						<para>
							The JBoss Riftsaw engine currently only supports the SOAP binding protocol
						</para>
					</important> -->
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The final page allows you to select the target project and folder for the new process artifacts. If a process with the name you provided already exists in that project and folder, the wizard will display an error message. 
						</para>
						<para>
							If the project is not a BPEL Project (does not define a BPEL facet) the wizard will display a warning message. You can still create the BPEL process, however it will not be deployable to a BPEL runtime engine until the BPEL facet has been added to the project (see the <guimenuitem>Help</guimenuitem> menu for more information about project facets).
						</para>
						<important>
							<para>
								BPEL artifacts must be contained somewhere within the <filename>bpelContent</filename> folder hierarchy if you intend to deploy the process. Complex projects may be organized into a folder hierarchy, but these folders must be contained within <filename>bpelContent</filename>.
							</para>
							<para>
								The <filename>Deployment Descriptor</filename> file must be contained within the <filename>bpelContent</filename> folder and at the root of any folder hierarchy.
							</para>
						</important>
						<figure>
							<title>New BPEL Process</title>
							<mediaobject>
								<imageobject>
									<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Create_a_BPEL_Process_File_03.png"/>
								</imageobject>
							</mediaobject>
						</figure>
						<para>
							You will be asked if you wish for the BPEL persepective to be opened once this wizard completes.
						</para>
				</listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
        </section>
		<section>
			<title>New BPEL Deployment Descriptor</title>
			<para>
				Use this wizard to create a <filename>Deployment Descriptor</filename> file. This file is a manifest for the web service and is required if the BPEL process is to be deployed to a runtime engine.
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>BPEL Deployment Descriptor</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/reference/BPEL_Deyployment_Descriptor_01.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>The page includes the following options:</para>
				<table>
					<title>New BPEL Process file wizard. First page options.</title>   
					<tgroup cols="2">
						<colspec colnum="1" align="left" colwidth="1*"/>
						<colspec colnum="2" align="left" colwidth="3*"/>
						<thead>
							<row>
								<entry>Field</entry>									
								<entry>Description</entry>
							</row>
						</thead>
						<tbody>
							<row>
								<entry>BPEL Project</entry>
								<entry>Select the project and folder where the new <filename>Deployment Descriptor</filename> will be created. This must also be the root folder that contains the BPEL processes.</entry>
							</row>
							<row>
								<entry>File name</entry>
								<entry>This field is automatically filled and cannot be edited.</entry>
							</row>  
                            </tbody>
                        </tgroup>
                    </table>
					<para>
						The BPEL Deployment Descriptor Editor will open once this wizard completes.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</section>
    </section>
	<section>
		<title>Perspectives</title>
		<section>
			<title>BPEL Perspective</title>
			<para>
			The BPEL Perspective is designed to facilitate the development and deployment of BPEL processes and their artifacts. To open this perspective navigate to <menuchoice>
                    <guimenuitem>Window</guimenuitem>
					<guimenuitem>Open Perspective</guimenuitem>
					<guimenuitem>Other</guimenuitem>
					<guimenuitem>BPEL</guimenuitem>
                </menuchoice> and click <guibutton>OK</guibutton>.
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>BPEL Perspective default layout</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/reference/BPEL_Perspective_01.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</section>
	</section>
	<section id="Reference-Views">
		<title>Views</title>
		<section>
			<title>Outline</title>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Outline</guilabel> view provides a structural layout of the BPEL process. You can view the process as either a hierarchical tree-structured outline (<inlinemediaobject><imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/reference/View_Outline_icon_01.png"/>
					</imageobject>
            </inlinemediaobject>) or as a thumbnail view (<inlinemediaobject>
            <imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/reference/View_Outline_icon_02.png"/>
					</imageobject>
            </inlinemediaobject>), by pressing the associated button.
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>Outline view</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/reference/View_Outline_01.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Palette</title>
			<para>
				The primary editing, creation and viewing tools of the BPEL Designer are accessed from the <guilabel>Palette</guilabel>. The <guilabel>Palette</guilabel> can be docked either at the right or left edge of the BPEL Designer main window, or it can be detached and displayed in its own view.
		</para>
		<figure>
			<title>Palette</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Palette_01.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<formalpara>
			<title>Selection Tools</title>
			<para>
				The <guilabel>Selection Tool</guilabel> is used to select individual activities in the editors drawing canvas. Multiple activities can be selected by holding the <keycap>CTRL</keycap> or <keycap>SHIFT</keycap> keys in combination with left mouse click. The <guilabel>Marquee Tool</guilabel> allows selection of groups of activities by dragging a selection rectangle around them.
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<formalpara>
			<title>Tool Drawers</title>
			<para>
				BPEL activities are created by dragging icons from the labeled <guilabel>Actions</guilabel>, <guilabel>Controls</guilabel> and <guilabel>Faults</guilabel> palette sections (or drawers), onto the editor’s drawing canvas. These sections can be collapsed and expanded by clicking on individual palette section titles. They can also be <emphasis>pinned</emphasis> to prevent them from collapsing if another section is expanded.
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<formalpara>
			<title>Zoom Tools</title>
			<para>
				The tools at the bottom of the <guilabel>Palette</guilabel> are used to expand or shrink the drawing canvas.
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		</section>
		<section>
			<title>Dashboard</title>
			<para>
				This panel is embedded in the BPEL Designer canvas and provides a quick overview of the BPEL elements that are defined for the currently selected activity or BPEL process.
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>Palette</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Dashboard_01.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>
				The process name appears at the top of the Dashboard. The main Dashboard area lists all of the <guilabel>Partner Links</guilabel>, <guilabel>Variables</guilabel>,<guilabel>Correlation Sets</guilabel> and <guilabel>Message Exchanges</guilabel> currently defined for the process. The green plus symbol and grey x symbol allow you to add and delete each of these elements. In-line editing of all element names works by selecting the name and then clicking again to enable the editor.
			</para>
		</section>
		<section id="Reference-Property_sections">
			<title>Property sections</title>
			<section>
				<title>Common property section tabs</title>
				<para>
					This section describes the Property Sheet tabs that are common to many activities.
				</para>
				<section>
					<title>Description tab</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Description tab</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Common_Property_Tabs_01.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Description</guilabel> tab contains the activity name. Names must follow XML element naming conventions, limiting characters to letters, numbers and certain special characters only (spaces are not permited). For further information on XML element naming conventions, see <ulink url="http://www.w3.org/TR/xml/">http://www.w3.org/TR/xml/</ulink>
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Join Behavior tab</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Join Behavior tab</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Common_Property_Tabs_02.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						Join conditions are evaluated by the target activities of links. With the drop-down <guilabel>Expression language</guilabel> menu, enter an XPath expression that defines the condition of the join. The <guilabel>Suppress Join Failure</guilabel> behavior defined by the process or a containing scope can be overridden with the radio buttons at the bottom.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Correlation tab</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Correlation tab</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Common_Property_Tabs_03.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Correlation</guilabel> tab lists all correlations that are used by the currently selected <guilabel>Receive</guilabel>, <guilabel>Reply</guilabel> or <guilabel>Invoke</guilabel> activity. Correlations can be added to or removed from the activity through this tab.<!-- See <xref linkend=""/> --> <!--Correlation Sets section--><!-- for more information. -->
					</para>
				</section>
				<section id="Common_Property_sheet_tabs-Namespaces_tab">
					<title>Namespaces tab</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Namespaces tab</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Common_Property_Tabs_04.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						Namespaces are URIs (Uniform Resource Identifiers) that uniquely identify a set of resources on the Internet. Because URIs can be very lengthy, shorthand aliases called prefixes are typically defined and used in XML files to make the XML more readable.
					</para>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Namespaces</guilabel> tab lists all of the namespace URIs and their prefixes in scope for the currently selected activity. Whenever you create a reference to an external property (an element defined in an XSD) whose namespace has not yet been assigned a prefix, the BPEL Designer will prompt you to create a prefix. This can also be done beforehand through the <guilabel>Namespace</guilabel> tab of the <guilabel>Properties</guilabel> sheet for the property by clicking the <guibutton>Assign Prefix</guibutton> button.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Message Exchange tab</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Message Exchange tab</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Common_Property_Tabs_05.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						Message exchanges are used to associate a <property>Reply</property> activity with an <property>inbound message</property> activity and can be either a <property>Receive</property>, <property>OnMessage</property> or <property>OnEvent</property>. These are descriptive names given to a request-response conversation between two parties and must conform to XML element naming conventions. For further informaiton on XML element naming conventions, see <ulink url="http://www.w3.org/TR/xml/">http://www.w3.org/TR/xml/</ulink>.
					</para>
				</section>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Process Property sheet tabs</title>
				<para>
					This section describes the Property Sheet tabs that are unique to process activities.
				</para>
				<section>
					<title>Description tab</title>
				<figure>
					<title>Description tab</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Property_Sheet_01.png"/>
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
				<para>
					The <guilabel>Description</guilabel> tab allows you to change the process name and its namespace URI. All namespaces should follow the W3C recommendation (<ulink url="http://www.w3.org/2005/07/13-nsuri">http://www.w3.org/2005/07/13-nsuri</ulink>.
				</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Details tab</title>
				<figure>
					<title>Details tab</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Property_Sheet_02.png"/>
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
				<para>
					The <guilabel>Process Details</guilabel> tab allows you to select the default <guilabel>Expression</guilabel> and <guilabel>Query</guilabel> language. If you set <guilabel>Exit on Standard Fault</guilabel> to <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>, it will cause the process to terminate if a WS-BPEL standard fault, other than a join failure, is encountered.
				</para>
				<note>
					<para>
						Currently only XPath 1.0 is supported.
					</para>
				</note>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Join Behavior tab</title>
				<figure>
					<title>Join Behavior tab</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Property_Sheet_03.png"/>
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
				<para>
					The <guilabel>Process Join Behavior</guilabel> tab determines how the process will handle join failures. When set to <guilabel>Yes</guilabel>, any <exceptionname>JoinFailure</exceptionname> fault (detailed in the WS-BPEL Standard Faults section of the OASIS specification: <ulink url="http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsbpel/2.0/OS/wsbpel-v2.0-OS.html#_Toc164738543">http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsbpel/2.0/OS/wsbpel-v2.0-OS.html#_Toc164738543</ulink>) will be ignored for all activities in the process. An activity is able override this value, or inherit the value from its parent.
				</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Imports tab</title>
				<figure>
					<title>Imports tab</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Property_Sheet_04.png"/>
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
				<para>
					The <guilabel>Imports Detail</guilabel> tab lists all of the imported service interfaces (WSDL) and XML Schemas (XSD) used by the process. Additional WSDL and XSD files can be added to the imports on this page. After a new resource has been imported, you may assign a prefix to the namespace URI from the <guilabel>Namespaces</guilabel> tab.
				</para>
				<note>
					<para>
						Imported resources must be located in the project root folder (<filename>bpelContent</filename> by default) or in a sub-folder.
					</para>
				</note>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Namespaces</title>
					<para>
						For information on the <guilabel>Namespaces</guilabel> tab, see <xref linkend="Common_Property_sheet_tabs-Namespaces_tab" />
					</para>
				</section>
			</section>
			<section>
				<title>Details tab</title>
				<para>
					This section describes the <guilabel>Details</guilabel> tab and its attributes as they will appear for individual activities. Several activities share common detail elements, but all are presented here for your reference.
				</para>
				<section>
					<title>Partner Links</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Partner Links</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_01.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						<property>Partner Links</property> help define the conversations between two services. They define the roles each partner plays in the conversation and the types of messages that can be exchanged between them.
					</para>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Details</guilabel> tab allows you to choose the <guilabel>Expression language</guilabel> and <guilabel>Query language</guilabel> for selecting elements of a <property>Partner Link</property>. 
					</para>
					<note>
						<para>
							Currently only XPath 1.0 is supported.
						</para>
					</note>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Variables</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Variables</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_02.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						<property>Variables</property> are used in BPEL to store inbound and outbound messages for examination and manipulation by the business logic; they can also be used to save intermediate results and the process state. There are three kinds of variable declarations: messages types, XML Schema types and XML Schema elements.
					</para>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Details</guilabel> tab allows you to define the variable declared type and its structure by selecting from known types. Once a variable type has been defined, the structure of the variable is shown. Clicking on the hyperlink will open the WSDL or XML Schema editor for the selected type or element. <!--See the Type Selection dialogs section for more information.-->
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Empty</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Empty</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_03.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <property>Empty</property> activity is a placeholder for any undefined <property>Basic Activity</property> and is intended to eventually be replaced by a real activity before the process can actually be executed. If the BPEL engine encounters an <property>Empty</property> activity, it is ignored.
					</para>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Details</guilabel> tab allows you to select one of four basic actions: <property>Invoke</property>, <property>Receive</property>, <property>Reply</property> and <property>Assign</property>. Hovering the mouse over one of the selection buttons displays a brief description of that activity.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Invoke</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Invoke</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_04.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <property>Invoke</property> activity requires a <property>Partner Link</property> name and an <property>Operation</property> as defined in the WSDL for that service. You can use the <guilabel>Quick Pick</guilabel> tree control at the right to select the <property>Partner Link</property> and <property>Operation</property>. For one-way invocations of the service, specify only an <property>Input Variable</property>; for request-response invocations you must also specify an <property>Output Variable</property>.
					</para>
					<para>
						The checkbox labeled <guilabel>Use WSDL Message Parts Mapping</guilabel> provides an alternative to using variables for the request message.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Receive</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Receive</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_05.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						A <property>Receive</property> activity requires a <property>Partner Link</property> name and an Operation as defined in the WSDL for this service. You can use the <guilabel>Quick Pick</guilabel> tree control at the right to select the <property>Partner Link</property> and <property>Operation</property>. A previously defined variable can be used to hold the message data, or the <guilabel>Use WSDL Message Parts Mapping</guilabel> checkbox can be set to store the incoming message in an anonymous WSDL message variable.
					</para>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Create a new Process Instance</guilabel> checkbox, when enabled, will cause the BPEL engine to start a new process. This will start a new conversation with a client.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Reply</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Reply</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_06.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						A <property>Reply</property> activity requires a <property>Partner Link</property> name and an <property>Operation</property> as defined in the WSDL for this service. You can use the <guilabel>Quick Pick</guilabel> tree control at the right to select the <property>Partner Link</property> and <property>Operation</property>. A previously defined variable can be used to provide the response message data, or the <guilabel>Use WSDL Message Parts Mapping</guilabel> checkbox can be set to use the data from the anonymous WSDL message variable.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Opaque</title>
					<para>
						<property>Opaque</property> activities are only used in abstract processes, and are meant as placeholders for other activities or complex business logic that has not yet been determined. When you drag and drop an <property>Opaque</property> activity onto the drawing canvas, the process will be converted to a non-executable, abstract process. The BPEL Designer will inform you about this by displaying a warning dialog.
					</para>
					<figure>
						<title>Opaque</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_07-Opaque_Warning.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Assign</title>
					<para>
						The <property>Assign</property> section is probably one of the more complex pages in the BPEL Designer, due to the nature of the BPEL <property>Assign</property> activity. The figure below shows the detail tab of an empty <property>Assign</property> activity with callouts describing each component:
					</para>
					<figure>
						<title>Assign</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_08.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<orderedlist>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								List (initially empty) of assignment operations currently defined.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								<guilabel>From</guilabel> combo box for selecting the source element category.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								<guilabel>To</guilabel> combo box for selecting the target element category.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								Contents and order management buttons. The <guibutton>New</guibutton> button adds a new assignment operation to the list. When clicked, the <guilabel>From</guilabel> and <guilabel>To</guilabel> combo boxes become active and display <property>Variable</property>. These allow you to select the source and categories for target items.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								<guilabel>Validate checkbox</guilabel>; when enabled will cause the BPEL engine to validate the data after the assignment. If an error is detected it will cause a fault, which can be caught by a fault handler in the BPEL process.
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								<guilabel>Ignore Missing Source Data checkbox</guilabel>; When enabled, missing source data is not considered an error (no fault will be generated).
							</para>
						</listitem>
						<listitem>
							<para>
								<guilabel>Keep Source Element Name checkbox</guilabel>; when enabled, the complex target variable element names will not be replaced by the source element names if they differ.
							</para>
						</listitem>
					</orderedlist>
					<para>
						The following figure shows the detail tab of an <property>Assign</property> activity which has an XPath expression as the source (<guilabel>From</guilabel>) and a process variable element as the target (<guilabel>To</guilabel>):
					</para>
					<figure>
						<title>Assign</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_08b.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
				<!--	<para>
						See XPath Expression Editor section for more information regarding the composition of XPath expressions.
					</para> -->
					<para>
						A requirement of the BPEL language is that all complex variables must be initialized with valid XML before they are referenced either as a target of an assignment, or in another BPEL activity. The BPEL Designer understands this and, once you have selected the target of an assignment operation, it will ask if you would like to have an XML fragment generated for the target variable:	
					</para>
					<figure>
						<title>Assign</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_08c-Initializer.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						Unless you are certain that the variable has been initialized during a previous assignment operation or other activity, you should click <guibutton>Yes</guibutton>. The figure below shows the <property>Assign</property> details tab after the initializer has been generated:
					</para>
					<figure>
						<title>Assign</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_08d.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<formalpara>
						<title>Assignment Operation Categories</title>
						<para>
							Additional type selection or data entry widgets will appear below the <guilabel>From</guilabel> and <guilabel>To</guilabel> combo boxes, depending on the source and target item categories selected in the combo boxes. Initially these will be controls for the selection of process variables, since the default combo box selection is <property>Variable</property>. The possible source and target categories are described in the following table:
						</para>
					</formalpara>
					<table>
						<title>Possible source and target categories</title>
						<tgroup cols='5' align='left' colsep='1' rowsep='1'>
							<colspec colname='c1'/>
							<colspec colname='c2'/>
							<colspec colname='c3'/>
							<colspec colname='c4'/>
							<colspec colname='c5'/>
							<thead>
								<row>
									<entry>Category</entry>
									<entry>Control type</entry>
									<entry>Can be source?</entry>
									<entry>Can be target?</entry>
									<entry>Further information</entry>
								</row>
							</thead>
							<tbody>
								<row>
									<entry>Variable</entry>
									<entry>Tree</entry>
									<entry>Yes</entry>
									<entry>Yes</entry>
									<entry>Select an in-scope variable or any portion if it is a complex variable. The target of the assignment must have the same type (for simple variables) or structure (for complex variables) as the source.</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Expression</entry>
									<entry>XPath</entry>
									<entry>Yes</entry>
									<entry>Yes</entry>
									<entry>Enter a valid XPath expression with the XPath editor. For targets, the expression must resolve to an L-Value; that is, it must be a variable reference.</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Fixed Value</entry>
									<entry>Text</entry>
									<entry>Yes</entry>
									<entry>No</entry>
									<entry>Enter a valid XML fragment that is compatible in structure and data type with the target.</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Property of a Variable</entry>
									<entry>List</entry>
									<entry>Yes</entry>
									<entry>Yes</entry>
									<entry>N/A</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Partner Link reference</entry>
									<entry>List</entry>
									<entry>Yes</entry>
									<entry>Yes</entry>
									<entry>N/A</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Endpoint reference</entry>
									<entry>List</entry>
									<entry>Yes</entry>
									<entry>No</entry>
									<entry>N/A</entry>
								</row>
								<row>
									<entry>Opaque</entry>
									<entry>None</entry>
									<entry>Yes</entry>
									<entry>No</entry>
									<entry>N/A</entry>
								</row>
							</tbody>
						</tgroup>
					</table>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Validate</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Validate</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_09.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <property>Validate</property> details tab contains a list of variables to be validated.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>While and RepeatUntil</title>
					<figure>
						<title>While and RepeatUntil</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_10.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						These activities have the same details tab, which allows you to specify an XPath expression to be evaluated for the conditional activity. <!-- See the XPath Expression Editor for more information. -->
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Link</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Link</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_11.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <property>Link</property> detail tab allows you to specify a condition that will cause <property>Flow</property> synchronization to be satisfied and allow the target activity to continue. This is similar to the details tab of the other conditional activities.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Pick</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Pick</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_12.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <property>Pick</property> details tab allows you to specify whether the event will create a new process instance. <!-- See also the discussion of the Pick Activity. -->
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>OnMessage</title>
					<figure>
						<title>OnMessage</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_13.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <property>OnMessage</property> activity is used in either a <property>Pick</property> or event handler.
					</para>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Details</guilabel> tab allows you to specify the <property>Partner Link</property>, <property>Operation</property> and <property>Message Type</property> expected by the activity, and the process variable that will contain the received message data.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>OnAlarm</title>
					<figure>
						<title>OnAlarm</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_14.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <property>OnAlarm</property> activity is used in either a <property>Pick</property> or event handler to handle timeouts while waiting for messages to arrive. This activity can be configured to wait for a certain period of time or until a specific date and time.
					</para>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Details</guilabel> tab allows you to specify the <property>Partner Link</property>, <property>Operation</property> and <property>Message Type</property> expected by the activity, and the process variable that will contain the received message data.
					</para>
					<para>
						<guilabel>Repeat</guilabel> conditions are only allowed for an <property>OnAlarm</property> in an event handler. This allows the activities enclosed in the activity to be executed repeatedly. <guilabel>Repeat</guilabel> duration is the amount of time the process will wait before each repetition. The <guilabel>Repeat</guilabel> screen follows:
					</para>
					<figure>
						<title>OnAlarm</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_14b.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>ForEach</title>
					<figure>
						<title>ForEach</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_15.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The details tab of the <property>ForEach</property> activity allows you to specify a counter variable to be used for keeping track of the loop iterations. The <guilabel>Parallel execution</guilabel> checkbox, when enabled, will execute all iterations in parallel. <!-- See the description of this activity for more information about its behavior. -->
					</para>
					<figure>
						<title>ForEach</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_15b.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Counter Values</guilabel> tab is where the required starting and ending counter values are specified.
					</para>
					<figure>
						<title>ForEach</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_15c.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The optional <guilabel>Completion</guilabel> tab allows you to specify the early termination condition for the loop.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Wait</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Wait</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_16.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The details tab of the <property>Wait</property> activity allows you set a delay (<property>Duration</property>) or specify a date and time (<property>Date</property>) for when to continue process execution.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Scope</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Scope</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_17.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The details tab for the <property>Scope</property> activity allows you to define whether the Scope is <guilabel>isolated</guilabel>.<!--  See the discussion of Scope and Flow activities for more information regarding isolated Scopes. -->
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>Throw</title>
					<figure>
						<title>Throw</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_18.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <property>Throw</property> activity will invoke a fault handler in an enclosing <property>Scope</property> activity. <property>Throw</property> requires the name of either a standard BPEL fault, or the name of a user-defined fault message. A variable is used to hold the value of the fault data.
					</para>
				</section>
				<section>
					<title>CompensateScope</title>
					<figure>
						<title>CompensateScope</title>
						<mediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/Details_tab_19.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</mediaobject>
					</figure>
					<para>
						The <property>CompensateScope</property> activity will invoke a compensation handler in the <property>Scope</property> or the <property>Invoke</property> activity given by the name of the <guilabel>Target Activity</guilabel>. 
					</para>
				</section>
			</section>
		</section>
	</section>
    <section>
        <title>Editors</title>
        <section>
			<title>BPEL Designer</title>
			<para>
				This section discusses the features of the BPEL Designer. See <xref linkend="Reference-Views" /> for a detailed discussion of each of these features.
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>BPEL Designer</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/reference/BPEL_Designer_01.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<orderedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis>Drawing Canvas</emphasis>: This contains the graphical representation of the BPEL process and is displayed when the <guilabel>Design</guilabel> tab at the bottom of the editor window is selected. The primary mouse click action (default is left mouse button) on any of the activity names activates an in-line editor, allowing you to edit the process name. To finish editing, simply press the <keycap>ENTER</keycap> key or change focus by clicking on a different window control. 
					</para>
					<para>
						The <guilabel>Source</guilabel> tab displays the XML (text) representation of the process. Any changes made in one view are immediately reflected in the other. The default layout of activities is top-to-bottom, but can be changed to horizontal layout from the context menu.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis>Palette</emphasis>: The primary editing, creation and viewing tools of the BPEL Designer are accessed from the tool <guilabel>Palette</guilabel>.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis>Dashboard</emphasis>: Provides an overview of the BPEL process.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis>Property Sheet</emphasis>: When an activity is selected in the drawing canvas, its properties are displayed in the tabbed <guilabel>Properties</guilabel> sheet. 
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						<emphasis>Outline</emphasis>: This panel provides a structural view of the BPEL process.
					</para>
				</listitem>
			</orderedlist>
			<para>
				The BPEL Designer will validate your business process every time it is saved. If an activity is found to be incomplete or incorrectly configured, it will be decorated with an error icon (red circle with an X) as for example the <property>Assign</property> activity below:
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>Assign error</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/reference/BPEL_Designer_02.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>
				Hovering your mouse over this icon will display an error message in a tooltip:
			</para>
			<figure>
				<title>Assign error with tooltip</title>
				<mediaobject>
					<imageobject>
						<imagedata fileref="images/reference/BPEL_Designer_03.png"/>
					</imageobject>
				</mediaobject>
			</figure>
			<para>
				The remainder of this section discusses some basic BPEL concepts and how they relate to the BPEL Designer.
			</para>
			<section>
				<title>Basic activities</title>
				<para>
					Basic activities are represented on the drawing canvas as rounded rectangles containing an icon and the user-defined name of the activity. The <guilabel>Actions</guilabel> section of the <guilabel>Palette</guilabel> contains all of the basic activities. For example: <property>Assign</property>, <property>Invoke</property> and <property>Receive</property>.
				</para>
				<para>
					Most basic activities will require some additional configuration. See <xref linkend="Reference-Property_sections" /> for more information.
				</para>
				<section>
					<title>Start and End</title>
					<para>
						Every BPEL process has implicit <property>Start</property> <inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/BPEL_Designer_04.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> and <property>End</property> <inlinemediaobject>
							<imageobject>
								<imagedata fileref="images/reference/BPEL_Designer_05.png"/>
							</imageobject>
						</inlinemediaobject> activities. These do not correspond to actual BPEL elements however, and are simply placeholders for visualizing the beginning and end of the process flow:
					</para>
				</section>
			</section>
      </section>
    </section>
</chapter>

