<chapter id="tutorial.preparation">
	<title>Tutorial Preparation</title>
	
	<section>
		<title>Introduction</title>
		<para>
			The goal of this tutorial is to demonstrate how simple it is to develop J2EE applications with JBossIDE.
			The sample application that will be built is a J2EE application with one session EJB and one Servlet, which computes the Fibonacci suite.
		</para>
		<para>
			The tutorial is split into several parts:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem><link linkend="the.project">The Project</link>: this part shows how the project is prepared (source and build path)</listitem>
				<listitem><link linkend="the.ejb">The EJB</link>: this part shows how to write an EJB class with its XDoclet javadoc tags.</listitem>
				<listitem><link linkend="ejb.file.generation">Generation of EJB files</link>: this part shows how to configure the XDoclet generation configuration to generate all the EJB related files</listitem>
				<listitem><link linkend="servlet">The Servlet and the Web-App</link>: this part shows how to write a Servlet class with its XDoclet javadoc tags.</listitem>
				<listitem><link linkend="servlet.file.generation">Generation of Servlet files</link>: this part shows how to configure the XDoclet generation configuration to generate all the Web related files</listitem>
				<listitem><link linkend="j2ee.app">The J2EE application</link>: this part shows how to create the missing files.</listitem>
				<listitem><link linkend="packaging">Packaging</link>: this part shows how to package the J2EE application</listitem>
				<listitem><link linkend="jboss.config">JBoss configuration</link> : this part shows how to define debug configuration to launch JBoss inside Eclipse.</listitem>
				<listitem><link linkend="deployment">Deployment</link> : this part shows how to deploy by copy the J2EE application</listitem>
				<listitem><link linkend="debugging">Debugging</link>: this part shows how to set up breakpoints to debug the deployed application.</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Requirements</title>
		<para>
			For this tutorial you need:
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>Java Development Kit 1.3.0 or higher (a JDK is needed to launch JBoss 3.x)</listitem>
				<listitem>Eclipse 3.0 (from <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org">eclipse.org</ulink>) or higher.</listitem>
				<listitem>JBoss Application Server 3.x-4.x</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>
			
			You also will need to know about developing and debugging applications in Eclipse. Refer to the <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org">Eclipse website</ulink> for further informations.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section>
		<title>Notes</title>
		<para>
		This tutorial has been written using the Eclipse 3.0 series. If you are using the Eclipse 3.1 series, the screens may be slightly different.
		</para>
	</section>
	
</chapter>