<?xml version="1.0" encoding="ISO-8859-1"?>
<chapter id="overview">
   <title>JBoss BPEL project Overview</title>

   <para>JBoss BPEL project is a WS-BPEL 2.0 project that gives a way to create, edit, validate and deploy BPEL files to JBoss BPEL runtime. It is based on Eclipse 
        <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/bpel/">BPEL
            project </ulink>. </para>
   
   <para>It improves the Eclipse BPEL project in the following way: </para>
   <itemizedlist>
       <listitem><para> Implements close integration with JBoss BPEL runtime. Adds a new project type for the deployment to JBoss BPEL runtime.</para></listitem>
       <listitem><para> Supports two ways of deployment: one way is to deploy a bpel project directly to JBoss BPEL runtime. The other way is to deploy bpel files in JBoss ESB project to JBoss BPEL runtime. </para></listitem>
       <listitem><para> Improves the BPEL validator and increases Eclipse BPEL editor's quality. </para></listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   
   <para>
   <ulink url="http://docs.oasis-open.org/wsbpel/2.0/OS/wsbpel-v2.0-OS.html">WS-BPEL 2.0</ulink> 
   stands for Web Service Business Process Execution Language. Like EAI, BPEL is an XML-based language,
   but BPEL is more specific and targeted. A programmer uses BPEL to join sometimes 
   disparate functions into an integrated process, resulting in a seamless use of the Internet to 
   conduct business transactions ranging from simple money exchanges to complex calculations and 
   asset reallocation.
   </para>

<section>
    <title>Key Features of JBoss BPEL project</title>
    <para>Let's start with looking through the table of the main features of JBoss BPEL editor project: </para>
    
    <table>
        
        <title>Key Functionality for JBoss BPEL editor project</title>
        <tgroup cols="2">          
            <colspec colnum="1" align="left" colwidth="2*"/>
            <colspec colnum="2" colwidth="4*"/>
            <thead>
                <row>
                    <entry>Feature</entry>
                    <entry>Benefit</entry>
                  
                </row>
            </thead> 
            <tbody>            
                <row>
                    <entry><para>WS-BPEL 2.0 support</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>JBoss BPEL project supports the newest WS-BPEL 2.0 specifications. </para></entry>   
                </row>          
                <row>
                    <entry><para>Close integration with JBoss BPEL runtime</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>There are two ways to deploy BPEL files to JBoss BPEL runtime.
                        The user can deploy a BPEL project as a whole and can deploy BPEL files in
                        JBoss ESB project to JBoss BPEL runtime. </para></entry> 
                </row>               
                <row>
                    <entry><para>BPEL file editor</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>The user can use the editor separately to edit a BPEL file. </para></entry>  
                </row>               
                <row>
                    <entry><para>BPEL file validator</para></entry>
                    <entry><para>The validator can give the error messages about BPEL files to the user. </para></entry>  
                </row>                              
            </tbody>           
        </tgroup>
    </table>
    
</section>

</chapter>