<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="further_reading" xreflabel="further_reading">
  <?dbhtml filename="further_reading.html"?>
  <chapterinfo>
    <keywordset>
      <keyword>JBoss Developer Studio</keyword>
      <keyword>Eclipse</keyword>
      <keyword>Deploy</keyword>
      <keyword>Deployment</keyword>
      <keyword>JBoss</keyword>
    </keywordset>
  </chapterinfo>

  <title>Further Reading</title>
<itemizedlist>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Seam Dev Tools Reference Guide</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para> This guide helps you to understand what Seam is and how to install Seam plug-in into
      Eclipse. It tells you the necessary steps to start working with Seam Framework and assists in a
      simple Seam Project creation. Also you will learn how to create and run the CRUD Database
      Application with Seam as well as find out what Seam Editors Features and Seam Components are. </para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Visual Web Tools Reference Guide</emphasis>
</para>
<para>
	provides general orientation and an overview of JBDS visual web tools functionality. This guide discusses the following topics: editors, palette, web properties view, openOn, content assist, RichFaces support.  
    </para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">JBoss Server Manager Reference Guide</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para> This guide covers the basics of working with the JBoss server manager. You will read how to
      install runtimes and servers and quickly learn how to configure, start, stop the server and know
      how deployment and archiving process. You will find out how to manage installed JBoss Servers
      via JBoss AS Perspective. You will also read how to deploy modules onto the server. </para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">jBPM Tools Reference Guide</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>With jBPM Tools Reference Guide we&apos;ll help you to facilitate a cross-product
      learning and know how you can speed your development using special editors and visual designers.
      We&apos;ll also guide you through the steps on how to create a simple process and test it
      within jBPM jPDL perspective.</para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Hibernate Tools Reference Guide</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>Throughout this guide you will learn how to install and use Hibernate Tools bath via Ant and
      through Eclipse. We&apos;ll supply you with the information on how to create mapping files,
      configuration file as well as a file for controlling reverse engineering by using specific
      wizards that Hibernate tooling provides. Also you will know about Code Generation and
      peculiarities of work within Hibernate Console Perspective.</para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">ESB Editor Reference Guide</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>This guide provides you with the information on ESB Editor and all necessary wizards for ESB
      files development.</para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">JBoss Portal Tools Reference Guide</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>The guide gives a detail look at how you can easily build a Portlet Web Application with
      JBoss Tools and deploy it onto JBoss Portal.</para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">JBoss WS User Guide</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>This guide gives you practical help on JBossWS usage. You will learn how to create a web service using JBossWS runtime, find out how to create a web service client from a WSDL document using JBoss WS and also see how to set your development environment.</para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Smooks Tools Reference Guide</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>This guide is packed with useful and easy-to-understand information about graphical, configuration and source editor pages.</para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Drools Tools Reference Guide</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>The guide help you to discover how to create a new Drools project, use debugging rules and work with different editors.</para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">JMX Tools Reference Guide</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>With the help of this guide you'll explore the best practices to follow when working with MBean Explorer, MBean Editor, Connections and etc.</para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem>
    <para>
      <emphasis role="bold">Eclipse Guvnor Tools Reference Guide</emphasis>
    </para>
    <para>The purpose of this guide is to describe briefly the functionality present in the Eclipse Guvnor Tools (EGT) for Drools 5.</para>
  </listitem>
  
  
  
  <listitem>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="bold">JSF Tools Tutorial</emphasis>
  </para>
  <para> This tutorial will describe how to deal with classic/old style of JSF development and how
    to create a simple JSF application using the JBoss Developer Studio. </para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem> <para>
    <emphasis role="bold">JSF Tools Reference Guide</emphasis>
    
  </para>
    <para> From this guide you'll discover all peculiarities of work at a JSF project. You&apos;ll
      learn all shades that cover the process of project creation and take a closer look at the JSF
      configuration file. Also you&apos;ll get to know managed beans and how to work with them and
      find out, how to create and register a custom converter, custom validator and referenced beans
      in a JSF project. </para>
  </listitem>
  
  <listitem> <para>
    <emphasis role="bold">Struts Tools Reference Guide</emphasis>
  </para>
  <para> In Struts Tools Reference Guide you will learn how to create and work with a new struts
    project. This guide also provides information about graphical editor for struts configuration
    files, tiles files, and struts validation files. </para>
  </listitem>

<listitem>
  <para>
    <emphasis role="bold">Struts Tools Tutorial</emphasis>
  </para>
  <para> This tutorial will describe the classical style of Struts development, and will
  step-by-step show you how to create a simple Struts application in JBoss Developer Studio.</para>
</listitem>


    <listitem> 
  <para>
    <emphasis role="bold">Exadel Studio Migration Guide</emphasis>
  </para>
  <para>This document is intended to help you to migrate an existing Exadel JSF or Struts projects
  from Exadel Studio into JBoss Developer Studio. </para>
    </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
<para>If there&apos;s anything we didn&apos;t cover in this guide, please feel free to visit our <ulink url="http://www.jboss.com/index.html?module=bb&amp;op=viewforum&amp;f=258">JBoss Developer Studio Users Forum</ulink> or <ulink url="http://www.jboss.com/index.html?module=bb&amp;op=viewforum&amp;f=201">JBoss Tools Users Forum</ulink> to ask questions. There we are also looking for your suggestions and comments.</para>

</chapter>
