<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="getting_started">
 <?dbhtml filename="getting_started.html"?>
 <chapterinfo>
  <keywordset>
   <keyword>JBoss Developer Studio</keyword>
   <keyword>Eclipse</keyword>
   <keyword>Java</keyword>
   <keyword>JBoss</keyword>
  </keywordset>
 </chapterinfo>
 <title>Getting Started with JBoss Developer Studio</title>

 <section id="intro1">
  <title>What is JBDS?</title>
  <para><property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> is a set of eclipse-based development tools that
   have been pre-configured for JBoss Enterprise Middleware Platforms and Red Hat Enterprise Linux.
   Developers are not required to use <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> to develop on
   JBoss Enterprise Middleware and/or Red Hat Linux. But, many find these pre-configured tools offer
   significant time-savings and value, making them more pra JSPoductive reducing deployment times.</para>
  <para>This guide covers the first steps required to get started with <property>JBoss Developer
    Studio</property>. You will learn how to install and configure the software necessary for your OS
   (currently Linux, Microsoft Windows or Mac OSX), including detailed information on how to install, configure and use JDK, JBDS and JBoss
   Tools.</para>
 </section>

<section>
	<title>Key Features of JBoss Developer Studio  and Requirements</title>
 <para>The table below lists the main features of JBoss Developer Studio:</para>

 <table>
  
  <title>Key Functionality of JBoss Developer Studio</title>
  <tgroup cols="2">
   
   <colspec colnum="1" align="left" colwidth="2*"/>
   <colspec colnum="2" colwidth="4*"/>
  
   
   <thead>
    <row>
     <entry>Feature</entry>
     <entry>Benefit</entry>
     
    </row>
   </thead>
   
   <tbody>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>JBoss Enterprise Application Platform</para></entry>
     <entry><para>JBoss Developer Studio includes and integrates JBoss Enterprise Application Platform, the same version of the middleware platform that Red Hat supports in production for 5 years.</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>New Seam Tools</para></entry>
     <entry><para>JBoss Developer Studio includes brand new tools for Seam. They provide wizards for creating new Seam projects, validation tools, expression language code completion, testing tools, and wizards for generating entity objects.</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>Visual Page Editor</para></entry>
     <entry><para>JBoss Developer Studio includes a Visual Page Editor for combined visual and source editing of Web pages. The Visual Page Editor even renders AJAX-enabled RichFaces components.</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>AJAX Capabilities</para></entry>
     <entry><para>JBoss Developer Studio includes a Technology Preview of JBoss RichFaces. RichFaces provides nearly 70 skinnable components, including calendar, tree, dropdown menu, drag-and-drop components, and more. JBoss Developer Studio’s Visual Page Editor can render RichFaces components.</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>JBoss Tools Palette</para></entry>
     <entry><para>The JBoss Tools Palette contains a developer’s project tag libraries and enables inserting tags into a JSP file with one click. The Tools Palette supports custom and 3rd party tags.</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>JBoss jBPM Tools</para></entry>
     <entry><para>JBoss Developer Studio includes jBPM tooling for defining Seam page flows.</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>Spring Tools</para></entry>
     <entry><para>JBoss Developer Studio includes Spring IDE for developing Spring applications.</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>Struts Tools</para></entry>
     <entry><para>JBoss Developer Studio includes Struts tools for Struts 1.x applications.</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>Optimized JBoss Application Server adapter</para></entry>
     <entry><para>JBoss Developer Studio’s advanced JBoss AS adapter includes features like incremental deployment for fast development and is pre-configured for the included JBoss Application server.</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>Red Hat Enterprise Linux and RHN Access</para></entry>
     <entry><para>JBoss Developer Studio includes access to Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Linux development tools, and Red Hat Network for development purposes.</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para> Project Examples</para></entry>
     <entry><para> Tooling for easy installation of Examples.</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>JBossWeb Service</para></entry>
     <entry><para>JBoss WS is a web service framework developed as a part of the JBoss Application Server. It implements the JAX-WS specification that defines a programming model and run-time architecture for implementing web services in Java, targeted at the Java Platform, Enterprise Edition 5 (Java EE 5).</para></entry>
    </row>
    
    <row>
     <entry><para>Usage reporting</para></entry>
     <entry><para>The usage plug-in anonymously gathers information on how you use the provided tools. This information is used to improve and shape the JBoss Developer Studio product to better cater to your needs. For more information refer to <xref linkend="Usage_Reporting"/>.</para></entry>
    </row>
   </tbody>
  </tgroup>
 </table>
 
 <para><property>JBDS</property> requires JDK 5+ (JDK 6 in case of EAP 5.0). Also it&apos;s important that 
 	the JVM&apos;s architecture matches the particular <property>JBDS</property> build, i.e. if you&apos;re on a 
 	64-bit system and use the 64-bit JVM, you need the 64-bit JBDS.</para>
 	
	<para>For the 32-bit version of JBDS use the 32-bit JVM or just use <literal>-vm</literal> flag to 
	tell JBDS to use 32-bit java if the 64-bit one is found as the default.</para>
	
	<note>
		<title>Note:</title>
		<para>On Linux system with 64-bit JVM the visual editor may fail to start. In this case you need the <literal>libstdc++.so.5</literal> library.
			See also the <link linkend="question_1">FAQ</link>.</para>
	</note>
</section>
 
 <section id="ConfigJavaEnvironment">
  <?dbhtml filename="ConfigJavaEnvironment.html"?>
  <title>Configuring Your Java Environment</title>
  <para>You must have a working installation of JDK before you install <property>JBoss Developer
    Studio</property>. Thus in this
   guide we will show you how to install a 32-bit Sun JDK 5.0 on a Linux Platform and Microsoft
   Windows Platform.</para>

  <section id="InstallJDK50onLinux">
   <title>Installing and Configuring 32-bit Sun JDK 5.0 on Linux</title>
   <para>To install 32-bit Sun JDK 5.0 on Linux and configure it, you should follow the next steps:</para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
     <para>Download the <ulink url="http://java.sun.com/javase/downloads/index_jdk5.jsp">Sun JDK 5.0
       (Java 2 Development Kit)</ulink> from Sun&apos;s website. Choose &quot;JDK 5.0 Update
      &lt;x&gt;&quot; (where &quot;x&quot; is the latest update number) for
      download and then select &quot;Red Hat Package Manager in self-extracting&quot; file
      for Linux. Read the instructions on Sun&apos;s website for installing the JDK.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>If you don&apos;t want to use SysV service scripts you can install the
      &quot;self-extracting file&quot; for Linux instead of choosing the &quot;RPM in
      self-extracting&quot; file. In that case you can skip the next step mentioned here. But it
      is recommended to use the SysV service scripts for production servers.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Download and install the appropriate -compat RPM from JPackage <ulink  url="ftp://jpackage.hmdc.harvard.edu/JPackage/1.7/generic/RPMS.non-free/">here</ulink>.
      Please ensure you choose a matching version of the -compat package to the JDK you've
      installed.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Create an environment variable that points to the JDK installation directory and call it
      JAVA_HOME. Add <emphasis>
       <property>$JAVA_HOME/bin</property>
      </emphasis> to the system path to be able to run java from the command line. You can do this
      by adding the following lines to the .bashrc file in your home directory.</para>
     <programlisting><![CDATA[#In this example /usr/java/jdk1.5.0_11 is the JDK installation directory.
export JAVA_HOME=/usr/java/jdk1.5.0_11
export PATH=$PATH:$JAVA_HOME/bin]]></programlisting>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>

   <note>
    <title>Note:</title>

    <para>﻿If you have JDK already installed and added in your system path, you should add
      <emphasis>$JAVA_HOME/bin</emphasis> before the old <emphasis>$PATH</emphasis> (not after it)
     so that the new version of JDK can be found first, i. e. <emphasis>
      <emphasis>export PATH=$JAVA_HOME/bin:$PATH</emphasis>
     </emphasis> This way, the machine will pick up the new JVM first. You only need to run
     "alternative" as a safe guard for the right JVM. </para>
   </note>

   <para>Set this variable for your account doing the installation and also for the user account
    that will run the server.</para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
     <para>If you have more than one version of JVM installed on your machine, make sure you are
      using the JDK 1.5 installation as the default java and javac. You can do this using the
      alternatives system. The alternatives system allows different versions of Java from different
      sources to co-exist on your system.</para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   <section id="SelectAlternativesforJava">
    <title>Select alternatives for java, javac and java_sdk_1.5.0</title>
    <itemizedlist>
     <listitem>
      <para>As a root user, type the following command at the shell prompt and you should see
       something like this:</para>
     </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <programlisting><![CDATA[[root@vsr ~]$ /usr/sbin/alternatives --config java
There are 2 programs that provide 'java'.
Selection    Command
-----------------------------------------------
   1           /usr/lib/jvm/jre-1.4.2-gcj/bin/java
*+ 2           /usr/lib/jvm/jre-1.5.0-sun/bin/java
Enter to keep the current selection[+], or type selection number:]]></programlisting>
    <para>Make sure the Sun version [jre-1.5.0-sun in this case] is selected (marked with a
     &apos;+&apos; in the output), or select it by entering its number as prompted.</para>
    <itemizedlist>
     <listitem>
      <para>Repeat the same for javac and java_sdk_1.5.0.</para>
     </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <programlisting><![CDATA[[root@vsr ~]$ /usr/sbin/alternatives --config javac
There is 1 program that provides 'javac'.
	Selection   Command
-----------------------------------------------
*+ 1           /usr/lib/jvm/java-1.5.0-sun/bin/javac
Enter to keep the current selection[+], or type selection number:

[root@vsr ~]$ /usr/sbin/alternatives --config java_sdk_1.5.0
There is 1 program that provide 'java_sdk_1.5.0'.
	Selection   Command
-----------------------------------------------
*+ 1           /usr/lib/jvm/java-1.5.0-sun
Enter to keep the current selection[+], or type selection number:]]></programlisting>
    <para>You should verify that java, javac and java_sdk_1.5.0 all point to the same manufacturer
     and version.</para>
    <note>
     <title>Note:</title>
     <para>You can always override this step by setting the JAVA_HOME environment variable as
      explained in the previous step.</para>
    </note>
    <itemizedlist>
     <listitem>
      <para>Make sure that the java executable is in your path and that you are using an appropriate
       version. To verify your Java environment, type &quot;java -version&quot; at the shell
       prompt and you should see something like this:</para>
     </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
    <programlisting><![CDATA[[root@vsr ~]$ java -version
java version "1.5.0_11"
Java(TM) 2 Runtime Environment, Standard Edition (build 1.5.0_11-b03)
Java HotSpot(TM) Client VM (build 1.5.0_11-b03, mixed mode, sharing)]]></programlisting>
   </section>

  </section>
  <section id="InstallJDK50onWindows">
   <title>Installing and Configuring 32-bit Sun JDK 5.0 on Microsoft Windows</title>

   <para>To install and configure 32-bit Sun JDK 5.0 on Microsoft Windows, follow these steps:</para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
     <para>Download the <ulink url="http://java.sun.com/javase/downloads/index_jdk5.jsp">Sun JDK 5.0
       (Java 2 Development Kit)</ulink> from Sun&apos;s website. Choose &quot;JDK 5.0 Update
      &lt;x&gt;&quot; (where &quot;x&quot; is the latest update number) for
      download and then select your Windows Platform options to perform the installation.</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Create an environment variable called JAVA_HOME that points to the JDK installation
      directory, for example:
        <emphasis>C:\Program Files\Java\jdk1.5.0_11\</emphasis>
     </para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>

   <para>In order to run java from the command line, add the <emphasis>jre\bin</emphasis> directory
    to your path, for example:</para>
   <para>
    <emphasis>C:\Program Files\Java\jdk1.5.0_11\jre\bin</emphasis>
   </para>
   <para>To do this, open the <emphasis>
     <property>Control Panel</property>
    </emphasis> from the <emphasis>
     <property>Start</property>
    </emphasis> menu, switch to Classic View if necessary, open the System Control Panel applet (<emphasis>
     <property>System</property>
    </emphasis>), select the <emphasis>
     <property>Advanced</property>
    </emphasis> Tab, and click on the <emphasis>
     <property>Environment Variables</property>
    </emphasis> button.</para>
   <para>Now, when 32-bit Sun JDK 5.0 has been successfully installed, we can pass on to the next
    step.</para>
  </section>

 </section>

 <section id="InstallingJBDS">
  <?dbhtml filename="InstallingRHDS.html"?>
  <title>JBoss Developer Studio Installation</title>

  <para>This chapter will provide you with detailed information on how to install <property>JBoss
    Developer Studio</property>.</para>

  <para>JBDS comes with a simple installer, bundled with tested and pre-configured versions of Eclipse,
   WTP, JBossEAP, Seam, and SpringIDE. The following steps show you how to install JBDS:</para>

  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>First of all you need the appropriate installation file for your platform from 
     <ulink  url="https://www.redhat.com/apps/store/developers/jboss_developer_studio.html">Red Hat
     website</ulink>.</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Run the following command in a terminal window:</para>
    <programlisting role="JAVA"><![CDATA[java -jar jbdevstudio-eap-linux-gtk-4.0.0.GA.jar
]]></programlisting>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Follow the instructions presented by the installation wizard:</para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <figure>
   <title>JBoss Developer Studio Installation Wizard</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_1.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>

  <itemizedlist>
  	<listitem>
  		<para>Provide the installation path</para>
  	</listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Select the appropriate Java Virtual Machine</para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  
  <note>
   <title>Tip:</title>
   <para>By selecting <emphasis>
     <property>Default Java VM</property>
    </emphasis> you set default Java VM of your system (to verify your Java environment, type
    &quot;java -version&quot; in console).</para>
  </note>

  <para>Selecting <emphasis>
    <property>Specific Java VM</property>
   </emphasis> you can provide the path to non-default Java VM.</para>

  <note>
   <title>Note:</title>
   <para>JBoss Developer Studio 4.0 comes integrated with JBoss EAP 5.1 that requires JDK 6.0 to run 
         and &quot;gij&quot; isn&apos;t available on every platform.</para>
  </note>

  <figure>
   <title>Select Java VM</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_2.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>

  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>As part of the installation you can choose to install <ulink url="http://www.jboss.com/products/platforms/application">JBoss Enterprise Application
    	Platform</ulink>. Select  <emphasis>
    		<property>Yes</property></emphasis> to use it in JBoss Developer Studio.</para>
    	<note>
    		<title>Note:</title>
    	 <para>Like in the previous version of JBDS, JBDS 4.0.0.GA comes integrated with JBoss EAP 5.1 that supports EAP 5 adapter and Seam 2.2.</para>
    	</note>
    	
    	<para>This step lets you configure locally available JBoss Application Servers: </para> 
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <figure>
   <title>JBoss Enterprise Application Platform Installing</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_3.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>

<itemizedlist>
 <listitem><para>You can fill the list automatically using the <guibutton>Find</guibutton> button. When the <guibutton>Find</guibutton> button is clicked you are propmpted to select the folder from which to search for available JBoss Application Servers. Click the <guibutton>OK</guibutton> button to select the chosen folder. </para> </listitem>
</itemizedlist>
  
  <figure>
   <title>Finding Servers in the Selected Directory</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_3_3_1.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <para/>
  
  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem><para> All available servers in the selected directory  will be added to the list with the following details: Name, Type, Version and Location.  
   </para></listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  
  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem><para>You can also add servers one by one using the <guibutton>Add</guibutton> button:</para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
 
  <figure>
   <title>Add Server to be Configured</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_3_1.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <para/>

<para>Click on the <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> button and select the server location. Fields Name, Type and Version will be filled in automatically:</para>
  
  <figure>
   <title>Specify Server Location</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_3_2.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <para/>
  
  
  <para>When you click the <guibutton>OK</guibutton> button the server will be added to the list with the details on its type, version and location.</para>

  <para>The <guibutton>Remove</guibutton> button will the remove the selected server from the list. If necessary, you can edit the server details clicking on the <guibutton>Edit</guibutton> button:</para>
  
  <figure>
   <title>Edit Server</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_3_4.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>
  <para/>
    
  <!--  <note>
   <title>Note:</title>
   <para>The installer installs JBoss Enterprise Application Platform for running your applications
    if you select this option during the installation process. If you want to use a different server
    than ours, you can change the setting in JBoss Developer Studio.</para>
    </note>-->

  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>Click the <guibutton>Next</guibutton> button to bring up a summary page where you can check your installation paths and see the components that will be installed. If you'd like to change something, press the <guibutton>Previous</guibutton> button. Click the <guibutton>Next</guibutton> button to start installation. </para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <para/>

  <figure>
   <title>Summary Information</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_4.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>

 </section>

 <section id="jbds_jbosstools">

  <title>JBoss Developer Studio and JBoss Tools</title>

  <para>This section highlights the differences between <property>JBoss Developer
   Studio</property> and <property>JBoss Tools</property>, and provides the steps on the <property>JBoss
    Tools</property> installation process.</para>

  <section id="WhatDifferenceBetweenJBDSAndJBossTools">
   <title>What is the difference?</title>

   <para><property>JBoss Tools</property> is a component of <property>JBoss Developer
    Studio</property>, which is designed to be an easy-to-install Eclipse based IDE, fully configured and ready
    to run with the bundled <property>JBoss Enterprise Application Platform</property>.</para>

   <para>In short <property>JBoss Tools</property> are just a set of Eclipse plugins and
     <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> adds:</para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
     <para>An installer</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Eclipse and Web Tools preconfigured</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>JBoss EAP with JBoss AS and Seam preconfigured</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>3rd party plugins bundled and configured</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Access to RHEL and Red Hat Network</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Access to the JBoss/Red Hat supported software</para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   <para> For additional information see <ulink url="http://www.jboss.com/products/devstudio"
     >JBoss.com</ulink></para>
  </section>

  <section id="JBossToolsInstall">
   <title>JBoss Tools Installation and Update</title>
   <para>This section covers the installation of the <property>JBoss Tools</property> modules.</para>
   <para><property>JBoss Tools</property> is an umbrella project for the JBoss developed plugins
    that are part of <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property>. The JBoss Tools modules are:</para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
     <para>JBoss AS Tools</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Seam Tools</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Hibernate Tools</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Visual Page Editor</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>JST Tools</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>JBPM Tools</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Smooks Tools</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Deltacloud Tools</para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   
   <note>
   	<title>Note</title>
   	<para>The JBoss Tools Deltacloud component is not included with JBoss Developer Studio in this release.</para>
   </note>

   <para>To install the JBoss Tools plugins for Eclipse, you need the following:</para>

   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
    	<para>A copy of Eclipse and Web Tools (make sure you have the 
    		<ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/community/wiki/MatrixofsupportedplatformsruntimesandtechnologiesinJBossToolsJBDS">appropriate version of Eclipse</ulink>).</para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   <para>The current version of JBoss Tools (3.2.0.GA) targets at Eclipse 3.6.1 Helios JEE Bundle which is available from <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/">eclipse.org</ulink>.</para>

   <note>
    <title>Tip:</title>
    <para>We recommend you do not use Eclipse.org update site to go from old version of Eclipse to new one.
    	Instead we suggest that you download the full binary from <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/">here</ulink>.</para>
   </note>

   <para>If you can only use Eclipse 3.3 use <ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/tools/download.html">JBoss Tools 2.1.2</ulink>, but
    JBoss Tools 2.x will not have any of the new features.</para>

   <note>
    <title>Note:</title>
    <para>Remember to choose the download that matches your OS and use Java 6 when you run
    it.</para>
   </note>
   <para>If you need to install any standalone plug-in from JBoss Tools visit a <ulink url="http://community.jboss.org/wiki/InstallingJBossTools">JBoss Tools Wiki</ulink> page to read
    about dependencies between standalone plug-ins.</para>  
   <para>For more information about how to install JBoss Tools 3.0 and JBoss Tools 3.1 please read the following docs:
   </para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para><ulink url="https://www.jboss.org/tools/download/installation/update_3_0.html">JBoss Tools 3.0 Installation</ulink></para></listitem>
    <listitem><para><ulink url="https://www.jboss.org/tools/download/installation/update_3_1.html">JBoss Tools 3.1 Installation</ulink></para></listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   
   <section>
    <title>Installation From Update Site</title>
   
   
   <para>Instead of downloading installation and updating manually, it&apos;s also possible to
    get the latest release of <property>JBoss Tools</property> from one of our update sites: 
    <itemizedlist id="sites">
     <listitem>
      <para>Stable Updates: <ulink url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/updates/stable"
        >http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/updates/stable</ulink></para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
      <para> Development Updates: <ulink url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/updates/development"
        >http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/updates/development</ulink></para>
     </listitem>
     <listitem>
      <para> Nightly Builds: <ulink url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/updates/nightly/trunk/"
       >http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/updates/nightly/trunk/</ulink></para>
     </listitem>
    </itemizedlist>
   </para>
<itemizedlist>
 <note>
  <title>Note:</title>
  <para>During the JBT installation and updating process using some of Jboss 
   update sites the <emphasis>No repository found containing...</emphasis> error
   can appear. This is an Eclipse P2 bug. To work around it try: 1.Restarting Eclipse. 2.   
   Add the update site again. 3. Performing the update again.</para>
 </note>
 <para>To install and/or update JBoss Tools from one of the update sites you should follow the steps:</para>
 <listitem><para>First, download the correct version of Eclipse 
  for your platform which is compatible with the version of JBoss
  Tools you plan to install. For example if you want to install
  3.2.0.GA Eclipse 3.6.1 Helios JEE Bundle is required.</para></listitem>
 <listitem><para>If you do not already have Java 5 or 6 installed and in your path,
  download and install it.</para></listitem>
 <listitem><para>When Eclipse is started, go to <itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para><menuchoice><guimenuitem>Help</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Software Updates...</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Available Software</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Manage Sites...</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Add...</guimenuitem></menuchoice><emphasis> (Eclipse 3.4)</emphasis></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para><menuchoice><guimenuitem>Help</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Install New Software</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Add...</guimenuitem></menuchoice><emphasis> (Eclipse 3.5, 3.6)</emphasis></para></listitem>
 </itemizedlist>
 </para></listitem>
 <listitem><para>After clicking the <guibutton>Add</guibutton> button the <property>Add Site</property> View should appear.
  In the <property>Location</property> field you should paste one of the update sites described
  <link linkend="sites">above</link>. On some platforms,
  you can also drag and drop the link from your browser directly into Eclipse. In the <property>Name</property> field you can enter any name you like.
  In the end press the <guibutton>OK</guibutton> button.</para>
  <figure>
   <title>Add Update Site</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_4a.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>
 </listitem>
 <listitem id="from_point"><para>In the <property>Install</property> View select features to install, then click the <guibutton>Next</guibutton> button.</para>
  <figure>
   <title>JBoss Tools installation</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_4b.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>
 </listitem>
 <listitem> 
  <para>And the system checks whether all necessary requirements and
  dependencies are installed on your Eclipse.</para>
  <figure>
   <title>Requirements and
    dependencies check</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_10.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure> 
  <para>If some of the dependencies are missing an error message will appear and
   the installation process will be terminated.
  </para>
  <note>
   <title>Note:</title>
   <para>Sometimes when a user changes the list of plugins for download and clicks
    <guibutton>Next</guibutton>, after the required dependences have been checked, 
    the list of missing dependencies from the previous attempt is showed. 
    In this case completely closing the <emphasis>Install New Software</emphasis> dialog can help.</para>
  </note>
  <para>If JBoss Tools are already installed on your Eclipse and you are performing an update (and not installing new components) the following messages may appear in your <emphasis>Details</emphasis> section.
  Ignore them and press the <guibutton>Next</guibutton> button.</para>
  <figure>
   <title>Possible messages</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_4c.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>
 </listitem>
 <listitem><para>When you click the <guibutton>Finish</guibutton> button the Installation and/or Updating process will commence.</para></listitem>
 <listitem><para>Once the installation is complete, restart Eclipse when prompted.</para>
  <figure>
   <title>Message dialog</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_4d.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure> 
 </listitem>
 <listitem><para>After fetching all the features and plugins for installation,
  you may be warned that your selection contains unsigned jars.
  This is normal, simply accept the warning and continue. </para>
  <figure>
   <title>Warning Message</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_4e.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure> 
 </listitem>
</itemizedlist>

    <note>
     	<title>Note:</title>
  	<para>While installing JBoss Tools on GNU/Linux (64-bit) through the eclipse installation manager you may run into some problems which can interrupt your installation process.
  		Please, read the 
  		<ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/community/wiki/ManualinstallationofJBossTools31xonEclipse35onGNULinux64-bit">Manual installation of JBoss Tools 3.1.x on Eclipse 3.5 on GNU/Linux (64-bit)</ulink> 
  		wiki article which provides you with the necessary steps to do it correct.</para>
     </note>
 </section>
 <section>
  <title>Installation From Zip file</title>
  
  <para>It is also possible to install JBoss Tools using the Eclipse P2 update manager and a common zip file which provides a single installer for all platforms.</para>
   <para>You can download JBoss Tools in a zip file from one of the pages below:</para>
  <itemizedlist id="zip_sites">
   <listitem>
    <para>Stable Releases: <ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/tools/download/stable.html"
     >http://www.jboss.org/tools/download/stable.html</ulink></para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para> Development Updates: <ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/tools/download/dev.html"
     >http://www.jboss.org/tools/download/dev.html</ulink></para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para> Nightly Builds: <ulink url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/updates/nightly/"
     >http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/updates/nightly/</ulink></para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>When you downloaded Jboss Tools Zip please <emphasis>DO NOT UNZIP IT</emphasis> and follow the steps described below:</para>
 <itemizedlist>
  <listitem><para>When Eclipse is started, go to <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Help</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Install New Software...</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Add...</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Archive...</guimenuitem></menuchoice></para></listitem>
  <listitem><para>Browse for the update site zip. In the <emphasis>Name</emphasis> field you can write any name you like.
   Then click the <guibutton>OK</guibutton> button.</para>
   <figure>
    <title>Installation from a zip file</title>
    <mediaobject>
     <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_4f.png"/>
     </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
   </figure> 
  </listitem>
  <listitem><para>The remaining steps are the same as described in the section <link linkend="from_point">
   Installation From Update Site section</link>. </para>
  </listitem> 
 </itemizedlist>
  
 </section>
   
  </section>
 </section>

 <section id="Welcome">
  <title>Welcome to JBoss Developer Studio</title>
  <para>In this section we'll show you how to work with the welcome page of the <property>JBoss
    Developer Studio</property>.</para>
  <para>The welcome page is the first page you see when you first launch <property>JBoss Developer
    Studio</property>. </para>

  <figure>
   <title>Welcome to JBoss Developer Studio</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_5.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>

  <para>With the help of its page you will be able:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>to get quick access to Getting Started Documentation (guides, tutorials and
    viewlets)</para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <figure>
   <title>Getting Started Documentation</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_6.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>

  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>to create new Seam projects, jBPM Process, JSF or Struts projects using JBDS
    wizards</para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <figure>
   <title>Create New...</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_7.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>

  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>to get short descriptions of the perspectives that JBDS provides</para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <figure>
   <title>Perspectives</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_8.png"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>

  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>to visit JBoss Developer Studio web resources.</para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>

  <figure>
   <title>Web Resources</title>
   <mediaobject>
    <imageobject>
     <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/getting_started_9.png" scale="90"/>
    </imageobject>
   </mediaobject>
  </figure>

  <para>You can start working with <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> by clicking on <emphasis>
    <property>Workbench</property>
   </emphasis> button or simply closing the Welcome page.</para>

 </section>

 <section id="Upgrading">
  <?dbhtml filename="Upgrading.html"?>
  <title>Upgrading</title>
  <para>Because JBDS 3.0x and 4.0 use different versions of Eclipse, it is not possible to directly upgrade from an older version to JBDS 4.0.</para>
  <note>
  	<title>Tip</title>
  	<para>It is possible to run JBDS 3.0x and 4.0 side by side, as long as they have been installed into separate directories.</para>
  </note>

 </section>

 <section id="Uninstalling">
  <?dbhtml filename="Uninstalling.html"?>
  <title>Uninstalling</title>
  <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>Make sure <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> is not running</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Uninstall your current version of <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> by running the Uninstaller</para>
   </listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
 </section>

 <section id="Usage_Reporting">
   <title>Usage Reporting</title>
   <para>
      The JBoss Developer Studio now includes a usage plug-in that anonymously reports information back to JBoss. The plug-in is not enabled by default. To enable, make sure the <guilabel>Report usage of JBoss Tools to JBoss Tools team.</guilabel> box is ticked.
  </para>
  
  <figure>
    <title>Usage plug-in pop-up</title>
    <mediaobject>
     <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/usage_plug-in_1_JBDS.png"/>
     </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
   </figure> 

   <para>
      Once enabled, the plug-in will remain active until turned off. To turn the active plug-in off, navigate to <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Window</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>JBoss Tools</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Usage Reporting</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
   </para>
   <para>
     The gathered data allows JBoss to see how the tools are being used and where they are being used geographically. Currently we are looking into the operating systems being used, screen resolution and how often the tooling environment is started. In the future geographic information will assist in focussing translation resources to areas where the developer environment is most used.
   </para>
   <para>
     The plug-in uses Google Analytics to track and report data by acting as if you were visiting the site http://jboss.org/tools/usage/. To view the type of information being collected, refer to <xref linkend="Collected_usage_information_guide"/>.
   </para>
   <para>
     To view the source code of the usage plug-in visit <ulink url="http://anonsvn.jboss.org/repos/jbosstools/trunk/usage/">http://anonsvn.jboss.org/repos/jbosstools/trunk/usage/</ulink>.
   </para>
      <section id="Collected_usage_information_guide">
	 <title>Collected usage information guide</title>
	 <para>
	    Outlined is the information type being reported and the Goolge Analytics fieds implemented to gather this information.
	 </para>
	 <variablelist>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Version</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		     The <guilabel>Content</guilabel> field has been modified to report the installed JBoss Developer Studio version. Sample returned values include: jbdevstudio-linux-gtk-x86_64-4.0.0.v201009301221R-H20-Beta1.jar and jbdevstudio-linux-gtk-3.0.2.v201009161622R-H138-GA.jar.
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Installed components</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		     The <guilabel>Keyword</guilabel> field has been modified to report the installed JBoss Developer Studio components. Sample returned values include: JBoss AS, Drools, Teiid and ModeShape.
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Visitor type</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		     The <guilabel>Visitor type</guilabel> field reports if the current user is new or returning.
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Language</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		     The <guilabel>Language</guilabel> field reports the localized language the product is being used in. Sample returned values include: en-US, de-DE and fr-FR.
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Location fields</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		     The location fields report the geographical location where the product is being used based on the continent, country and city. Sample returned values include: Europe (continent), Germany (country) and Munich (city).
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Eclipse interface and version</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		     The <guilabel>Browser</guilabel> field has been modified to report the Eclipse interface and version being used. Sample returned values include: JBoss Developer Studio: 3.0.0 and JBoss Developer Studio: 3.0.1.
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Operating System</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		     The <guilabel>Operating System</guilabel> field reports the Operating System and its version that the product is running on (with Linux distribution version reporting conducted through the <guilabel>User Defined Value</guilabel> field). Sample returned values include: Linux, Macintosh 10.4, Macintosh 10.6,  Windows XP and Windows 7.
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Linux distribution version</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		      The <guilabel>User Defined Value</guilabel> field reports the distribution and version of Linux, if one is being used as the Operating System. Sample returned values include: Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5.4 and Fedora 13.
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Screen colors</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		     The <guilabel>Screen colors</guilabel> field reports the color depth being used. Sample returned values include: 32-bit and 24-bit. 
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Screen resolution</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		      The <guilabel>Screen resolution</guilabel> field reports the resolution being used. Sample returned values include: 2048x1536 and 1920x1080.
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Java version</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		     The <guilabel>Flash version</guilabel> field has been modified to report the Java version used. Sample returned values include: 1.6.0_20 and 1.5.0_9.
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	    <varlistentry>
	       <term>Connection speed</term>
	       <listitem>
		  <para>
		     The <guilabel>Connection speed</guilabel> field reports the type of internet connection being used. Sample returned values include: T1, Cable and DSL.
		  </para>
	       </listitem>
	    </varlistentry>
	 </variablelist>
      </section>
 </section>

 <section id="Support">
  <?dbhtml filename="Support.html"?>
  <title>Support</title>
  <para>If you have comments or questions, you can discuss them at our <ulink url="http://www.jboss.com/index.html?module=bb&amp;op=viewforum&amp;f=258">JBoss
    Developer Studio Forum</ulink>.</para>
  <para>When writing to the forum for questions, please include the following information:</para>
  <orderedlist>
   <listitem>
    <para>JBoss Developer Studio version</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Exact error message</para>
   </listitem>
   <listitem>
    <para>Steps to reproduce the issue</para>
   </listitem>
  </orderedlist>

  <para><property>JBDS</property> subscribers can get necessary support on our <ulink url="https://network.jboss.com/jbossnetwork/login.html">Support Portal</ulink>.</para>
 </section>


 <section id="OtherRelevantResourcesOnTheTopic33">
  <?dbhtml filename="OtherRelevantResourcesOnTheTopic33.html"?>
  <title>Other relevant resources on the topic</title>
  <para>JBDS on RedHat: <ulink url="http://www.redhat.com/developer_studio">JBoss Developer
   Studio</ulink></para>
  <para>Forum: <ulink url="http://www.jboss.com/index.html?module=bb&amp;op=viewforum&amp;f=258">JBoss
   Forum</ulink></para>
	<para>
	Wiki: <ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/community/wiki/JBossTools">  JBossToolsWiki </ulink>  
   </para>  
  <para>Subscription: <ulink url="https://www.redhat.com/apps/store/developers/jboss_developer_studio.html">JBDS
   Subscription</ulink></para>
   
  <para>The latest documentation builds are available <ulink url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/nightly-docs/">here</ulink>.</para>
 	
 	<para>
 		<ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/community/wiki/MatrixofsupportedplatformsruntimesandtechnologiesinJBossToolsJBDS">Matrix of supported platforms, runtimes and technologies in JBossTools/JBDS</ulink></para>
 </section>

</chapter>
