<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<chapter id="gsg_faq" role="updated">
	<?dbhtml filename="gsg_faq.html"?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<keywordset>
			<keyword>JBoss Developer Studio</keyword>
			<keyword>Eclipse</keyword>
			<keyword>Java</keyword>
			<keyword>JBoss</keyword>
		</keywordset>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>FAQ</title>

	<para>Refer to the following FAQ to get the answers on the most &quot;popular&quot; questions concerning <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property>.</para>

	<section id="question_1">
		<title>What should I do if the Visual Page Editor does not start under Linux</title>

		<para>Linux users may need to do the following to get the <property>Visual Page Editor</property> to work correctly on their machines.</para>

		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>On Red Hat based Linux distributions install the libXp.i386 package</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Type</para>
				<programlisting role="JAVA"><![CDATA[ln -s libstdc++.so.5.0.7 libstdc++.so.5
]]></programlisting>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>and/or use</para>
				<programlisting role="JAVA"><![CDATA[yum install libXp
]]></programlisting>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Open the JBoss Developer Studio perspective. If you see the Help view open, close it and restart JBoss Developer Studio</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> If it doesn't help and you use Fedora with Eclipse Version: 3.4.1, the issue can be produced because the <filename>libswt-xulrunner-gtk-3449.so</filename> file doesn't present in <filename>eclipse-swt-3.4.1-5.fc10.x86_64.rpm/eclipse/plugins/org.eclipse.swt.gtk.linux.x86_64_3.4.1.v3449c.jar</filename>. To add this file to eclipse you should: 
            </para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Decompress <filename>eclipse/plugins/org.eclipse.swt.gtk.linux.x86_3.4.1.v3449c.jar</filename> form <filename>eclipse-SDK-3.4.1-linux-gtk-x86_64.tar.gz</filename></para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Copy <filename>libswt-xulrunner-gtk-3449.so</filename> file to your Fedora Eclipse location.</para>
					</listitem>

					<listitem>
						<para>Open the file <filename>jbdevstudio.ini</filename>, which can be found in your JBoss Developer Studio location and add the following line: </para>
						<programlisting role="JAVA"><![CDATA[-Dswt.library.path=/usr/lib/eclipse]]></programlisting>
						<para>,where <code>/usr/lib/eclipse</code> is the path to your eclipse folder.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>If none of these work, do the following:</para>
				<itemizedlist>
					<listitem>
						<para>Clear the Eclipse log file,<filename>&lt;workspace&gt;\.metadata\.log</filename>
						</para>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Start Eclipse with the -debug option:</para>
						<programlisting role="JAVA"><![CDATA[eclipse -debug]]></programlisting>
					</listitem>
					<listitem>
						<para>Post the Eclipse log file(<filename>&lt;workspace&gt;\.metadata\.log</filename>) on the forums.</para>
					</listitem>
				</itemizedlist>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
	</section>
	
	<section id="question_0x2">
		<title>Visual Editor starts OK, but the Missing Natures dialog appears</title>
			
		<figure>
			<title>Missing Nature</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/faq/missingnauture.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	
	
		<para>
	
	Some functionality of Visual Editor may not work if a project doesn't have <property>org.jboss.tools.jsf.jsfnature</property> or <property>org.jboss.tools.jst.web.kb.kbnature</property> in <property>.project</property> configuration. To fix this problem and turn off the message box execute next steps:
		</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
   Right mouse button click on a project in Package Explorer.
   </para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para> Select <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Configure</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Add JSF Capabilities</guimenuitem></menuchoice> from the context menu.
	</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
    Configure your project using Add JSF Capabilities wizard and press Finish.
</para>
			</listitem>

		</orderedlist>
		<para>
If you are sure that your project does not need JSF capabilities, just disable this message box by checking <property>Do not show this dialog again!</property> checkbox.
	</para>
	
	</section>

	<section id="question_2">
		<title>Do I need to have JBoss Server installed to run JBoss Developer Studio?</title>

		<para>No. <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> already comes bundled with JBoss Server. We bundle it together so that you don&apos;t need to download any additional software and can test your application in a Web browser right away.</para>
		<para>If you want to use a different JBoss server installation, after <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> is installed open Servers View (select <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Window</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Show View</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Others</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Server</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Servers</guimenuitem></menuchoice>), then right click and select <menuchoice><guimenuitem>View</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>New</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Server</guimenuitem></menuchoice> and follow the wizards steps to point to another Jboss Server installation.</para>
		<para>
			<property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> works with any servlet container, not just JBoss. For more information on deployment, please see the Deploying Your Application section.</para>
	</section>

	<section id="question_3">
		<title>I have an existing Seam 1.2.1 project. Can I migrate or import the project into a JBoss Developer Studio Seam project?</title>

   <para>Use the following steps to manually transfer an existing Seam 1.2.1 project into a new JBoss Developer Studio Seam project:</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Create a Seam Web project to get the JBoss tools structure</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>Then from your Seam 1.2.1 seam-gen project start doing the following:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Copy <filename>src</filename> to <filename>src</filename>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Copy <filename>view</filename> to <filename>Web content</filename>
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Copy resources individual files to where they are in the seam web project etc.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

	</section>
	<section id="questio_4">
		<title>I have an existing Struts or JSF project. Can I open the project in JBoss Developer Studio?</title>

		<para>Yes. From main menu select <menuchoice><guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Import</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Other</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>JSF Project (or Struts Project)</guimenuitem></menuchoice> and follow wizards steps.</para>

	</section>

	<section id="question_5">
		<title>Can I import a WAR file?</title>

		<para>Yes. Select <menuchoice><guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Import</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Web</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>WAR file</guimenuitem></menuchoice> then follow importing steps.</para>
	</section>

	<section id="question_6">
		<title>Is it possible to increase the performance of Eclipse after installing your product?</title>

		<para>
			<property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> configures eclipse via the <filename>jbdevstudio.ini</filename> file to allocate extra memory, but if you for some reason need more memory then by default, you can manually make adjustments in this file. For example:</para>
		<programlisting role="XML"><![CDATA[-vmargs -Xms128m -Xmx512m -XX:MaxPermSize=128m]]></programlisting>
	</section>

	<section id="question_7">
		<title>How can I add my own tag library to the JBoss Tools Palette?</title>

		<para>See the section on Adding Tag Libraries in the Visual Web Tools Guide.</para>
	</section>

	<section id="question_8">
		<title>How to get Code Assist for Seam specific resources in an externally generated project?</title>

		<para>To get Code Assist for Seam specific resources in an externally generated project, you should enable Seam features in Project Preferences. Right click an imported project and navigate
		
		<menuchoice><guimenuitem>Properties</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Seam Settings</guimenuitem></menuchoice>. Check <emphasis><property>Seam support</property>
			</emphasis> box to enable all available Seam Settings.</para>
	</section>

	<section id="question_9">
		<title>How to import an example Seam project from jboss-eap directory?</title>

		<para>To import an example Seam project from <emphasis><property>jboss-eap</property></emphasis> into your working directory, you should perform the following steps:</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Select <menuchoice><guimenuitem>New</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Other</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Java Project from Existing Buildfile</guimenuitem></menuchoice></para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>Point to the <filename>build.xml</filename> file of any chosen project by clicking the <guibutton>Browse</guibutton> button</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>Click the <guibutton>Finish</guibutton> button to open the project</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<para>
			As these seam examples are non WTP projects, next you should enable Seam support for them. To do that, right click the project and select <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Properties</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Seam Settings</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section id="question_10">
		<title>Is a cross-platform project import possible for JBoss Developer Studio?</title>

		<para>Yes. You can easily import created in Linux JSF, Struts or Seam project to Windows and vice versa.</para>

		<para>
			To do the transferring JSF, Struts or Seam project, select <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Menu</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Import</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>General</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Existing Projects into Workspace</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
		</para>
	</section>
</chapter>
