<chapter id="introduction">
	<?dbhtml filename="getting_started.html"?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<keywordset>
			<keyword>JBoss Developer Studio</keyword>
			<keyword>Eclipse</keyword>
			<keyword>Java</keyword>
			<keyword>JBoss</keyword>
		</keywordset>
	</chapterinfo>
	<title>Introduction to JBoss Developer Studio</title>

	<section id="intro1">
		<title>What JBoss Developer Studio is</title>
		<para>
			<property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> is a set of Eclipse based development tools that have been pre-configured for JBoss Enterprise Middleware Platforms and Red Hat Enterprise Linux. Developers are not required to use <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> to develop on JBoss Enterprise Middleware and/or Red Hat Linux. Many do find these preconfigured tools save time and offer significant value, making them more productive and reducing deployment times.
		</para>
		<para>
			This guide covers the first steps required to get started with <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property>. You will learn how to install and configure the software necessary for your OS (currently Linux, Microsoft Windows or Mac OSX), including detailed information on how to install, configure and use JDK, JBoss Developer Studio and JBoss Tools.
		</para>
	</section>

	<section>
		<title>Key Features of JBoss Developer Studio  and Requirements</title>
		<para>The table below lists the main features of JBoss Developer Studio:</para>

		<table>

			<title>Key Functionality of JBoss Developer Studio</title>
			<tgroup cols="2">

				<colspec colnum="1" align="left" colwidth="2*"/>
				<colspec colnum="2" colwidth="4*"/>

				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry>Feature</entry>
						<entry>Benefit</entry>

					</row>
				</thead>

				<tbody>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>JBoss Enterprise Application Platform</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>
								JBoss Developer Studio includes and integrates JBoss Enterprise Application Platform, the same version of the middleware platform that Red Hat supports in production for 5 years.
							</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>New Seam Tools</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>
								JBoss Developer Studio includes brand new tools for Seam. They provide wizards for creating new Seam projects, validation tools, expression language code completion, testing tools, and wizards for generating entity objects.
							</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>Visual Page Editor</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>
								JBoss Developer Studio includes a Visual Page Editor for combined visual and source editing of Web pages. The Visual Page Editor even renders AJAX-enabled RichFaces components.
							</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>AJAX Capabilities</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>
								JBoss Developer Studio includes a Technology Preview of JBoss RichFaces. RichFaces provides nearly 70 skinnable components, including calendar, tree, dropdown menu, drag-and-drop components, and more. JBoss Developer Studio’s Visual Page Editor can render RichFaces components.
							</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>JBoss Tools Palette</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>
								The JBoss Tools Palette contains a developer’s project tag libraries and enables inserting tags into a JSP file with one click. The Tools Palette supports custom and 3rd party tags.
							</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>JBoss jBPM Tools</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>JBoss Developer Studio includes jBPM tooling for defining Seam page flows.</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>Spring Tools</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>JBoss Developer Studio includes Spring IDE for developing Spring applications.</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>Struts Tools</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>JBoss Developer Studio includes Struts tools for Struts 1.x applications.</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>Optimized JBoss Application Server adapter</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>
								JBoss Developer Studio’s advanced JBoss AS adapter includes features like incremental deployment for fast development and is pre-configured for the included JBoss Application server.
							</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>Red Hat Enterprise Linux and RHN Access</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>
								JBoss Developer Studio includes access to Red Hat Enterprise Linux, Linux development tools, and Red Hat Network for development purposes.
							</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para> Project Examples</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para> Tooling for easy installation of Examples.</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>JBossWeb Service</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>
								JBoss WS is a web service framework developed as a part of the JBoss Application Server. It implements the JAX-WS specification that defines a programming model and run-time architecture for implementing web services in Java, targeted at the Java Platform, Enterprise Edition 5 (Java EE 5).
							</para>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>Usage reporting</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>
								The usage plug-in anonymously gathers information on how you use the provided tools. This information is used to improve and shape the JBoss Developer Studio product to better cater to your needs. For more information refer to <xref linkend="Usage_Reporting"/>.
							</para>
						</entry>
					</row>
				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>

		<para>
			<property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> requires JDK 5+ (JDK 6 in case of EAP 5.0). Also it&apos;s important that the JVM&apos;s architecture matches the particular <property>JBoss Developer Studio</property> build, i.e. if you&apos;re on a 64-bit system and use the 64-bit JVM, you need the 64-bit JBoss Developer Studio.
		</para>
	
		<para>
			For the 32-bit version of JBoss Developer Studio use the 32-bit JVM or just use <literal>-vm</literal> flag to tell JBoss Developer Studio to use 32-bit java if the 64-bit one is found as the default.
		</para>
	
		<note>
			<title>Note:</title>
			<para>
				On Linux system with 64-bit JVM the visual editor may fail to start. In this case you need the <literal>libstdc++.so.5</literal> library. See also the <link linkend="question_1">FAQ</link>.
			</para>
		</note>
	</section>
</chapter>
