<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<!DOCTYPE Book PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" []>
<section id="Usage_Reporting">
		<title>Usage Reporting</title>
		
		<!-- JBT Intro -->
		
		<para condition="jbt">
			JBoss Tools now includes a usage plug-in that anonymously reports information back to JBoss. The plug-in is not enabled by default. To enable, click the <guibutton>Yes</guibutton> button.
		</para>

		<figure condition="jbt">
			<title>Usage plug-in pop-up</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/installineclipse10.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<!-- JBDS Intro -->
		
		<para condition="jbds">
			The JBoss Developer Studio now includes a usage plug-in that anonymously reports information back to JBoss. The plug-in is not enabled by default. To enable, click the <guibutton>Yes</guibutton> button.
		</para>
		
		<figure condition="jbds">
			<title>Usage plug-in pop-up</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/getting_started/usage_plug-in_1_JBDS.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>
      Once enabled, the plug-in will remain active until turned off. To turn the active plug-in off, navigate to <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Window</guimenuitem>
				<guimenuitem>Preferences</guimenuitem>
				<guimenuitem>JBoss Tools</guimenuitem>
				<guimenuitem>Usage Reporting</guimenuitem>
			</menuchoice>.
		</para>
		<para>
     The gathered data allows JBoss to see how the tools are being used and where they are being used geographically. Currently we are looking into the operating systems being used, screen resolution and how often the tooling environment is started. In the future geographic information will assist in focussing translation resources to areas where the developer environment is most used.
    </para>
		<para>
     The plug-in uses Google Analytics to track and report data by acting as if you were visiting the site http://jboss.org/tools/usage/. To view the type of information being collected, refer to <xref linkend="Collected_usage_information_guide"/>.
    </para>
		<para>
     To view the source code of the usage plug-in visit <ulink url="http://anonsvn.jboss.org/repos/jbosstools/trunk/usage/">http://anonsvn.jboss.org/repos/jbosstools/trunk/usage/</ulink>.
    </para>
		<section id="Collected_usage_information_guide">
			<title>Collected usage information guide</title>
			<para>
	    	Below you will find an outline of the information that is reported and the Goolge Analytics fields that are used to gather this information.
	    </para>
			<variablelist>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Version</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Content</guilabel> field has been modified to report the installed JBoss Developer Studio version. Sample returned values include: jbdevstudio-linux-gtk-x86_64-4.0.0.v201009301221R-H20-Beta1.jar and jbdevstudio-linux-gtk-3.0.2.v201009161622R-H138-GA.jar.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Installed components</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Keyword</guilabel> field has been modified to report the installed JBoss Developer Studio components. Sample returned values include: JBoss AS, Drools, Teiid and ModeShape.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Visitor type</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Visitor type</guilabel> field reports if the current user is new or returning.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Language</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Language</guilabel> field reports the localized language the product is being used in. Sample returned values include: en-US, de-DE and fr-FR.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Location fields</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The location fields report the geographical location where the product is being used based on the continent, country and city. Sample returned values include: Europe (continent), Germany (country) and Munich (city).
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Eclipse interface and version</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Browser</guilabel> field has been modified to report the Eclipse interface and version being used. Sample returned values include: JBoss Developer Studio: 3.0.0 and JBoss Developer Studio: 3.0.1.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Operating System</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Operating System</guilabel> field reports the Operating System and its version that the product is running on (with Linux distribution version reporting conducted through the <guilabel>User Defined Value</guilabel> field). Sample returned values include: Linux, Macintosh 10.4, Macintosh 10.6,  Windows XP and Windows 7.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Linux distribution version</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>User Defined Value</guilabel> field reports the distribution and version of Linux, if one is being used as the Operating System. Sample returned values include: Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5.4 and Fedora 13.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Screen colors</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Screen colors</guilabel> field reports the color depth being used. Sample returned values include: 32-bit and 24-bit. 
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Screen resolution</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Screen resolution</guilabel> field reports the resolution being used. Sample returned values include: 2048x1536 and 1920x1080.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Java version</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Flash version</guilabel> field has been modified to report the Java version used. Sample returned values include: 1.6.0_20 and 1.5.0_9.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
				<varlistentry>
					<term>Connection speed</term>
					<listitem>
						<para>
							The <guilabel>Connection speed</guilabel> field reports the type of internet connection being used. Sample returned values include: T1, Cable and DSL.
						</para>
					</listitem>
				</varlistentry>
			</variablelist>
		</section>
	</section>
