<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<chapter id="project_examples" xreflabel="project_examples" role="new">
    <?dbhtml filename="project_examples.html"?>
    <chapterinfo>
        <keywordset>
            <keyword>JBoss Developer Studio</keyword>
            <keyword>Eclipse</keyword>
            <keyword>Java</keyword>
            <keyword>JBoss</keyword>
        </keywordset>
    </chapterinfo>
    <title>Project Examples</title>
    
    <para><emphasis><property>JBoss Developer Studio</property></emphasis> provides an option to download and import a ready-made 
    project that you can explore and derive some useful technology implementation lessons from. </para>
    
    <para>
        To adjust the settings of the Project Examples feature you need to navigate to <property>Windows&gt; Preferences &gt; JBoss Tools &gt; Project Examples 
    </property>. </para>
    
    <figure>
        <title>Project Examples Preferences</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/project_examples/preferences.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    
    <para>The <property>Show experimental sites</property> checkbox serves to enable/disable representing the user sites in the <property>Project Example</property> dialog ( <property>Help &gt; Project Examples</property>).  </para>

    
    <section id="UserSites">
        <title>User Sites</title>
        <para>
            As you can see from the  <emphasis role="bold">Project Examples Preferences</emphasis> image you can add a custom project example that can be provided by anyone. 
            This feature can, for example, facilitate project testing.
            
        </para>
        <para>
            In oder to add a new project example you need to select the <property>User sites</property>
            option and press the <property>Add</property> button to the right.
        </para>
        <para>When the <property>Add</property> button is pressed the
            <property>Add Project Example Site</property> dialog is displayed. The dialog contains 2 
            input fields: <property>Name</property> where you need to specify the name of the new entry and <property>URL</property> 
           that has to point to the xml file that contains example project(s) properties. 
           In more detail the structure of the xml file is discussed further in the chapter of the guide.
           Alternatively, if the xml is stored on your local machine, you can hit the <property>Browse</property> button to select the file in the file system.</para>
        <para>Here is an example of the xml file that holds  project example settings:</para>
    
    <programlisting role="XML"><![CDATA[
<projects>
    <project>
		<category>User Examples</category>
		<name>User Project Example</name>
		<shortDescription>
		Short project description.
		</shortDescription>
		<description>
    	Full project description.
		</description>
		<size>10900</size>
		<url>
		http://projectexample.org/projectexample.zip
		</url>
	</project>
</projects>
]]></programlisting> 
        
        <para>Once you define the location of the xml file with projects settings you will see a new user site entry added. 
            Please note  now if you select the entry you can edit and remove it with the corresponding buttons to the right. 
            You can not do such operations with the <property>Plugin provides sites</property>.</para>
        
        <para>When the user sites location is set up you can download and install the project(s). 
            Please see the next chapter of the guide. </para>
    </section>
    
    
    
    <section id="DownloadingProjectExample">
        <title>Downloading a Project Example</title>
        
        <para>To download a project example and  start working with it you need to take a few steps:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Go to the menu bar and select <emphasis><property>File &gt; New &gt; Other...</property></emphasis>
                </para></listitem>
            
            <listitem><para>Select <emphasis><property>Jboss Tools &gt; Project Examples</property></emphasis>(You can also call the <emphasis><property>Project Examples</property></emphasis> from menu bar: <property>Help &gt; Project Examples...</property>)</para></listitem>
            
            
        </itemizedlist>
        
        <figure>
            <title>Project Examples</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/project_examples/pr_example_1.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        
        <para>
            Alternatively, you should navigate to <property>New &gt; Other..</property>, scroll down to find the <property>JBoss Tools</property> option (or just type in the first letters of the word &quot;JBoss&quot; for quick search), expand the option and select <property>Project Examples</property>, click <property>Next</property>.
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>Now in the <property>New Project Example</property> dialog you can select a project you would like to explore and a site to download it from</para>
                <para>Project Examples Wizard  provides a filter field to more easily locate the project examples you want, so you can type in the project you would like to explore in the field.</para></listitem>
            
        </itemizedlist>
        
        
        <figure>
            <title>Selecting a Project Example</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/project_examples/pr_example_2.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        
        <para>If you have previously specified user sites (see the <link linkend="UserSites">User Sites</link> chapter) they also will be  displayed in the list of project examples  in the category that was defined in the xml file with user sites settings.  </para>
       <figure>
           <title>User Site</title>
           <mediaobject>
               <imageobject>
                   <imagedata fileref="images/project_examples/pr_example_user_site.png"/>
               </imageobject>
           </mediaobject>
       </figure>
        
        <para>
            Pleas note that to view the user sites you need to have <property>Show experimental sites</property> checked.
        </para>
        
        <note>
            <title>Note:</title>
            <para>
                The <emphasis><property>Show the Quick Fix Dialog</property></emphasis> option is described in the <link linkend="QuickFixes">Quick Fixes</link> section.
            </para>
        </note>
        
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>Press <emphasis><property>Finish</property></emphasis> to start downloading the project from the repository
            </para></listitem>
            
        </itemizedlist>
        
        <para>When downloading is finished the project will be imported automatically and you will be able to see it in the Package Explorer.</para>
        
        <para>Now you can run the application on the server.
        
        </para>
  
       
        <figure>
            <title>Seam Demo Application run on the Server</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/project_examples/pr_example_3.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>

    </section>
    
    <section id="QuickFixes">
        <title>Quick Fixes</title>
        <para>
            Project Examples Wizard has an option for making quick fixes 
            for the imported project to easily fix possible issues like  missing servers, Seam runtimes etc.
        </para>
        <para>To enable quick fixing option you need to check the
            <emphasis><property>Show the Quick Fix dialog</property></emphasis> while choosing the <link linkend="DownloadingProjectExample">Project Example</link>.</para>
        
        <para>When the project you selected is downloaded it will be checked for missing dependences and if there are some you will see a dialog listing the problems.</para>
        <figure>
            <title>Quick Fix Dialog box</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/project_examples/pr_example_4.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>To fix the problem you need to:</para>
        
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem><para>Select the problem from the list</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Click <emphasis><property>Quick Fix</property></emphasis> button</para></listitem>
        </itemizedlist>
        
        <para>You will be offered a solution or a number of solutions to the problem.</para>
        
        <figure>
            <title>Quick Fix Dialog box: Selecting a Fix</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata fileref="images/project_examples/pr_example_5.png"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
        <para>In this case(see the image above), when the <emphasis><property>Finish</property></emphasis> button is pressed, Seam Settings dialog box will be displayed where you need to provide a path to the Seam environment to fix the issue.</para>
        
        <para>When the problem is fixed you will be returned to the Quick Fix dialog box with the remaining problems to be fixed.</para>
        
    </section>
    
    
</chapter>
