<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="GettingStartedWithRHDS" xreflabel="GettingStartedWithRHDS">
  <?dbhtml filename="GettingStartedWithRHDS.html"?>
  <chapterinfo>
    <keywordset>
      <keyword>Red Hat Developer Studio</keyword>
      <keyword>Eclipse</keyword>
      <keyword>Java</keyword>
      <keyword>JBoss</keyword>
    </keywordset>
  </chapterinfo>
 <title>Getting Started with Red Hat Developer Studio</title>
 <section id="Prerequisites">
  <?dbhtml filename="Prerequisites.html"?>
  <title>Prerequisites</title>
  <para>Before installation Red Hat Developer Studio make sure you have an appropriate JDK version installed on your Linux system.  Studio will properly work with the next JDK's:</para>
  <itemizedlist>
  <listitem>JDK 1.5</listitem>
  <listitem>JDK 1.6</listitem>
  </itemizedlist>
  <para>If your Linux comes with no proper JDK you should install it.</para>
  <para>For proper installation the java from Sun there is need to install the java from .rpm file or after installing it from .bin it is need to tune the java with command "alternative".</para>
     <para>Red Hat Enterprise Linux includes several JDK&apos;s from Sun, IBM, and BEA. For RHEL 4, they are in the &quot;Extras&quot; RHN Channel. For RHEL 5, they are in the &quot;Supplementary&quot; RHN channel.
</para>
    <section id="HowToInstallJDK">
     <title>How to setup and install a proper JDK on RHEL</title>
      <section id="RHEL_JDK_support">
      <title>What Java Development Kits (JDKs) are provided with Red Hat Enterprise Linux and what support does Red Hat offer for them?</title>
      <para>To make it as easy as possible for customers to install and run Java applications on Red Hat Enterprise Linux, third-party Java Development Kits
       (JDKs) from IBM and BEA are provided through the Red Hat Enterprise Linux Extras channel on Red Hat Network (RHN) and on the Red Hat Enterprise
       Linux Extras CD. Red Hat&apos;s current and planned availability of the IBM JDK is as follows:</para>
      
      <itemizedlist>
       <listitem><para>IBM JDK 1.4.2.3. (currently shipped with Red Hat Enterprise Linux 3 Update 8 and Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4 Update 4)</para></listitem>
       <listitem><para>IBM JDK 1.5.0 (currently shipped with Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4 Update 4)</para></listitem>
       <listitem><para>IBM JDK 1.4.2.6 (planned for Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4 Update 5 and Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5)</para></listitem>
       <listitem><para>IBM JDK 1.5.3 (planned for Red Hat Enterprise Linux 4 Update 5 and Red Hat Enterprise Linux 5)</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
      
      <para>Red Hat does not provide the special version "IBM JDK 1.4.2 for SAP"; this software is available directly from IBM.</para>
      <para>The IBM and BEA JDKs, along with the other packages on the Extras CD, are licensed separately (see http://www.redhat.com/licenses/thirdparty/eula.html) 
       and are not included under the Red Hat Enterprise Linux production-level Service Level Agreement (SLA).</para>
      <para>Customers who require enterprise-level support for either JDK package must purchase it directly from the Java vendor. Red Hat's support of the
      IBM and BEA JDKs included on the Red Hat Enteprise Linux Extra CD/RHN channel is limited to:</para>
      <itemizedlist>
       <listitem><para>Assistance with installation and configuration of the Red Hat provided Java Runtime environment.</para></listitem>
       <listitem><para>Verification of proper operation through the use of a Red Hat provided test program written in Java.</para></listitem>
      </itemizedlist>
            <para>Note that this support does not include assistance with the development of Java applications, which is available with Red Hat's Development 
             Support Services. In addition, the JDKs are not eligible for a "hotfix" through the Red Hat Hotfix process.</para>
            <para>If the customer problem lies in the Red Hat Enterprise Linux operating system, Red Hat provides full production-level support for problem resolution.
             If the problem lies in the JDK, Red Hat will escalate the problem to the appropriate Java vendor via bugzilla, but cannot guarantee response or problem 
             resolution by that vendor.</para>
     </section>

     <section id="Java-1.5.0-sun packages"><title>Java-1.5.0-sun packages</title>
  
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Details:</emphasis></para>
  <para>The following packages comprise Sun's 1.5.0 Java release: </para>
  <para>java-1.5.0-sun</para>
  <para>java-1.5.0-sun-demo</para>
  <para>java-1.5.0-sun-devel</para>
  <para>java-1.5.0-sun-jdbc</para>
  <para>java-1.5.0-sun-plugin</para>
  <para>java-1.5.0-sun-src </para>
  
  <para>These packages include the Sun Java 5 Runtime Environment, Sun Java
  5 Software Development Kit, and Sun's 1.5.0_11-b03 SDK release.</para>
    <para>The Java 5 Runtime Environment (JRE) consists of the Java virtual machine,
   the Java platform core classes and supporting files, and includes a Web
   browser plug-in for running Java applets. It is the runtime section of the
   Java 5 SDK, but without the development tools such as compilers and debuggers.</para>
  <para>The Java 5 Software Development Kit (SDK) is a development environment for
   building applications, applets, and components that can be deployed on the
   Java platform. The Java 5 SDK software includes tools useful for
   developing and testing programs written in the Java programming language.
   The Java 5 SDK software also includes a JDBC/ODBC bridge for Java
   applications that need to communicate with a database. </para>
  <para>Java users are advised to install these packages.</para>
  
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Solution:</emphasis></para>
  <para>Before applying this update, make sure all previously released errata
  relevant to your system have been applied.</para>
  <para>To update all RPMs for your particular architecture, run: </para>
  <programlisting><![CDATA[rpm -Fvh [filenames]]]></programlisting>
  <para>where [filenames] is a list of the RPMs you wish to upgrade. Only those
   RPMs which are currently installed will be updated. Those RPMs which are
   not installed but included in the list will not be updated. Note that you
   can also use wildcards (*.rpm) if your current directory *only* contains the
   desired RPMs.
  </para>
  <para>
   Please note that this update is also available via Red Hat Network. Many
   people find this an easier way to apply updates. To use Red Hat Network,
   launch the Red Hat Update Agent with the following command: </para>
  <programlisting><![CDATA[up2date]]></programlisting>
  <para>This will start an interactive process that will result in the appropriate
   RPMs being upgraded on your system.</para></section>
 
     <section id="RHEL 5"><title>RHEL 5</title>
      <para>The instructions for RHEL 5 are similar to RHEL 4, except that RHEL 5 uses &quot;yum&quot; instead of &quot;up2date&quot;, 
      and they are in the supplementary channel rather than the extras channel.</para>
      
      <para>Install the 32-bit Java plugin as shown below:</para>
      
      <programlisting><![CDATA[$ yum install java-1.4.2-ibm-plugin java-1.4.2-ibm.i386 libXp.i386 gtk+.i386]]></programlisting>
<para>or</para>
      <programlisting><![CDATA[$ yum install java-1.5.0-ibm-plugin java-1.5.0-ibm.i386 libXp.i386 gtk +.i386]]></programlisting>

      <para>Alternatively, download Java6 ( jdk-6u1-linux-i586-rpm.bin ) from http://java.sun.com, and install it. Once done, install the Java plugin as shown:</para>
      
      <programlisting><![CDATA[$ ln -s /usr/java/latest/jre/plugin/i386/ns7/libjavaplugin_oji.so /usr/lib/mozilla/plugins/]]></programlisting>
     
     </section>
     </section>
    </section>
    <section id="Installing">
  <?dbhtml filename="Installing.html"?>
  <title>Installation</title>
  <section id="Inst from down ver">
   <title>Installing from the downloaded version</title>
   <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
   <para>Download the appropriate installation file for your platform from www.exadel.com/web/portal/download</para>
   </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Run install.jar and follow the instructions presented by the installation wizard</para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   
   <figure>
    <title>Red Hat Developer Studio Installation Wizard</title>
    <mediaobject> 
     <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/install.png"/>
     </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
   </figure>
   
   <para>Installation process includes all required platforms to run Red Hat Developer Studio:</para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
     <para>Eclipse 3.3</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>JBoss J2EE Application Server</para>
     </listitem>
     </itemizedlist>
     <figure>
      <title>JBoss J2EE Application Server installing</title>
      <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/install2.png"/>
       </imageobject>
     </figure>
     <note>The installer will install JBoss J2EE Application Server for running your applications if you select this option during the installation process. 
      If you want to use a different server than ours, you can change the setting in Red Hat Developer Studio.</note>
    
  </section>  
  <section id="InstallingthroughTheUpdateSite">
  <?dbhtml filename="InstallingthroughTheUpdateSite.html"?>
   <title>Installing via update Site</title>
   TBD
  </section>
  </section>
 
   <section id="Upgrading">
   <?dbhtml filename="Upgrading.html"?>
   <title>Upgrading</title>
   <para>To upgrade, just uninstall your current version and install the new one.</para>
  </section>
 <section id="Uninstalling">
  <?dbhtml filename="Uninstalling.html"?>
   <title>Uninstalling</title>
  <itemizedlist>
  <listitem>Make sure Red Hat Developer Studio is not running</listitem>
  <listitem>Uninstall your current version of Red Hat Developer Studio by running uninstaller</listitem>
</itemizedlist>
 </section>
  <section id="Subscription">
   <?dbhtml filename="Subscription.html"?>
   <title>Subscription</title>
   <para>Enjoy the peace of mind that comes with knowing that you are just an email away from having the advice of our  development team at your fingertips to solve the problems that crop up during application development. Get the advice you need to ensure the success of your projects on time and on budget. Whether you are using JSF, RichFaces,  Ajax4jsf, Hibernate or Seam, the JBoss team is always available to help. Just subcribe to our subcription program:</para>
   <para>What You Get:</para>
   <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>Email access to the JBoss customer support team (responses within 48 hours)</listitem>
   <listitem>Application development consultation</listitem>
   <listitem>Sample code</listitem>
   <listitem>Code review</listitem>
   <listitem>General architectural review</listitem>
   <listitem>User interface design tips</listitem>
   <listitem>Overviews of JSF or AJAX technologies</listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
  </section>
  <section id="Support">
   <?dbhtml filename="Support.html"?>
   <title>Support</title>
    <para>If you have comments or questions, you can send them to 
    <ulink url="mailto:support@exadel.com">support@exadel.com</ulink> or 
    <ulink url="http://www.jboss.com/index.html?module=bb&amp;op=viewforum&amp;f=258">Red Hat Developer Studio Forum</ulink>.</para>
   <para>When writing to support, please include the following information:</para>
   <orderedlist>
    <listitem><para>Red Hat Developer Studio version</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Exact error message</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Exact steps you take to get the error</para></listitem>
   </orderedlist>
  </section>
<section id="FAQ">
 <?dbhtml filename="FAQ.html"?>
 <title>FAQ</title>
 <para>For easy reference to Red Hat Developer Studio related questions, our FAQ provides answers to our most &quot;popular&quot; questions.
  The sections of questions are organized by type. For further support, please contact <ulink url="mailto:support@exadel.com">support@exadel.com</ulink>.</para>
 <section id="Before_Installing">
  <title>Before Installing, Tutorials, Examples, Readme Files</title>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">I'm looking for examples, do you have any?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Yes, simply go to our <ulink url="http://exadel.com/web/portal/products/Tutorials">tutorials page</ulink></para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Where can I find the Red Hat Developer Studio readme file?</emphasis></para>
  <para>It's located at this page: <ulink url="http://www.exadel.com/web/portal/products/ReleaseNotes">Release Notes</ulink></para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Where can I find some documentation for Red Hat Developer Studio?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Try these resources: <ulink url="http://www.exadel.com/exadelstudio/help/">User Guide</ulink></para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">What version of Eclipse does Red Hat Developer Studio support?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Red Hat Developer Studio works with Eclipse 3.3</para>
  </section>
 <section id="Downloading">
  <title>Downloading</title>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Where can I download a copy of Red Hat Developer Studio?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Go to <ulink url="http://www.exadel.com/web/portal/download/esp35">Download Page</ulink></para>
 </section>
 <section id="Installation_Issues">
  <title>Installation Issues</title>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Do I need to have JBoss server installed to run Red Hat Developer Studio?</emphasis></para>
  <para>No. Red Hat Developer Studio already comes bundled with JBoss server. We bundle it together so that you don't need to download any 
  additional software and can test your application in a Web browser right away.</para>
  <para>If you want to use a different JBoss server installation, after Red Hat Developer Studio is installed open Servers View (select Window &gt; Show View &gt; Others &gt; Server &gt; Servers), then right click on this view &gt; New &gt; Server and follow the wizards steps to point to another Jboss server installation.</para>
  <para>Red Hat Developer Studio works with any servlet container, not just JBoss. For more information on deployment, please see the Deploying Your Application section.</para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold"> What third-party plug-ins are installed with RHDS?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Read the <link  linkend="Installing">Installation</link> section.</para> 
 </section>
 <section id="Importing_Projects">
  <title>Importing Projects</title>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">I have an existing Struts or JSF project. Can I open the project in RHDS?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Yes. From main menu select File &gt; Import &gt; Other &gt; JSF Project (or Struts Project) and follow wizards steps.</para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Can I import a .war file?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Yes. Select File &gt; Import &gt; Web &gt; WAR file. Then follow importing steps.</para>
 </section>
 <section id="Troubleshooting">
  <title>Troubleshooting, Problems, Configuration, Error Messages</title>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Is it possible to increase the performance of Eclipse after installing your product? My Eclipse now crawls.</emphasis></para>
  <para>By default, Eclipse allocates only 128 Mb of memory whatever physical memory you actually have installed. You can significantly increase performance if you allocate more memory. For example:</para>
  <para>-vmargs -Xms128m -Xmx512m -XX:MaxPermSize=128m</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">How can I add my own tag library to the Red Hat Palette?</emphasis></para>
  <para>See <ulink url="http://labs.jboss.com/jbossjsftools/docs">Adding Tag Libraries</ulink> in JBossJSFTools Guide.</para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">I see the Oracle ADF Faces component library tags in the Red Hat Palette, but I can&apos;t seem to find the libraries for ADF. How do I use this component library with RHDS?</emphasis></para>
  <para>See <ulink url="http://labs.jboss.com/jbossrhdsuserguide/docs">Adding Support for the Oracle ADF Components Library</ulink> in the RHDS User Guide.</para>
 </section>
</section>

<section id="OtherRelevantResourcesOnTheTopic33">
<?dbhtml filename="OtherRelevantResourcesOnTheTopic33.html"?>
<title>Other relevant resources on the topic</title>
<para>RHDS on JBoss: <ulink url="http://labs.jboss.com/rhdevstudio/">Red Hat Developer Studio</ulink></para>
<para>Forum: <ulink url="http://www.jboss.com/index.html?module=bb&amp;op=viewforum&amp;f=258">JBoss Forum</ulink></para>
<para>Download: <ulink url="http://www.exadel.com/web/portal/download/esp35">RHDS Download</ulink></para>
</section>
</chapter>

