<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="GettingStartedWithRHDS" xreflabel="GettingStartedWithRHDS">
  <?dbhtml filename="GettingStartedWithRHDS.html"?>
  <chapterinfo>
    <keywordset>
      <keyword>Red Hat Developer Studio</keyword>
      <keyword>Eclipse</keyword>
      <keyword>Java</keyword>
      <keyword>Tomcat</keyword>
    </keywordset>
  </chapterinfo>
 <title>Getting Started with Red Hat Developer Studio</title>
  <section id="Installing">
  <?dbhtml filename="Installing.html"?>
<title>Installing</title>
  <section id="Inst from down ver">
   <title>Installing from the downloaded version</title>
   <itemizedlist>
   <listitem>
   <para>Download the appropriate installation file for your platform from www.exadel.com/web/portal/download.</para>
   </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>Run install.jar and follow the instructions presented by the installation wizard.</para>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
   
   <figure>
    <title>Red Hat Developer Studio Installation Wizard</title>
    <mediaobject> 
     <imageobject>
      <imagedata fileref="images/install.png"/>
     </imageobject>
    </mediaobject>
   </figure>
   
   <para>Installation process includes all required platforms to run Red Hat Developer Studio:</para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem>
     <para>Eclipse 3.2.2</para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
     <para>JBoss J2EE Application Server</para>
     <figure>
      <title>JBoss J2EE Application Server installing</title>
      <mediaobject> 
       <imageobject>
        <imagedata fileref="images/install2.png"/>
       </imageobject>
      </mediaobject>
     </figure>
     <note>The installer will install JBoss J2EE Application Server for running your applications if you select this option during the installation process. 
      If you want to use a different server than ours, you can change the setting in Red Hat Developer Studio.</note>
    </listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
  </section>  
  <section id="InstallingthroughTheUpdateSite">
  <?dbhtml filename="InstallingthroughTheUpdateSite.html"?>
   <title>Installing via update Site</title>
   TBD
  </section>


 </section>
   <section id="Upgrading">
   <?dbhtml filename="Upgrading.html"?>
   <title>Upgrading</title>
   <para>To upgrade, just uninstall your current version and install the new version.</para>
  </section>
 <section id="Uninstalling">
  <?dbhtml filename="Uninstalling.html"?>
   <title>Uninstalling</title>
  
  <para>Make sure Red Hat Developer Studio is not running.</para>
  <para>Uninstall your current version of Red Hat Developer Studio by running uninstaller.</para>

 </section>
  <section id="Subscription">
   <?dbhtml filename="Subscription.html"?>
   <title>Subscription</title>
   TBD
  </section>
  <section id="Support">
   <?dbhtml filename="Support.html"?>
   <title>Support</title>
    <para>If you have comments or questions, you can send them to 
    <ulink url="mailto:support@exadel.com">support@exadel.com</ulink> or 
    <ulink url="http://www.jboss.com/index.html?module=bb&amp;op=viewforum&amp;f=258">Red Hat Developer Studio Forum</ulink>.</para>
   <para>When writing to support, please include the following information:</para>
   <itemizedlist>
    <listitem><para> Red Hat Developer Studio version</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Exact error message</para></listitem>
    <listitem><para>Exact steps you took to get the error</para></listitem>
   </itemizedlist>
  </section>
<section id="FAQ">
 <?dbhtml filename="FAQ.html"?>
 <title>FAQ</title>
 <para>For easy reference to Red Hat Developer Studio related questions, our FAQ provides answers to our most &quot;popular&quot; questions.
  The sections of questions are organized by type. For further support, please contact support@exadel.com.</para>
 <section id="Before_Installing">
  <title>Before Installing, Tutorials, Examples, Readme Files</title>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">I'm looking for examples, do you have any?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Yes, simply go to our tutorials page</para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Where can I find the Red Hat Developer Studio readme file?</emphasis></para>
  <para>It's at http://www.exadel.com/web/portal/products/ReleaseNotes</para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Where can I find some documentation for Red Hat Developer Studio?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Try these resources:</para>
  <para>TBD</para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">What version of Eclipse does Red Hat Developer Studio support?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Red Hat Developer Studio works with Eclipse 3.2.2 </para>
  </section>
 <section id="Downloading">
  <title>Downloading</title>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Where can I download a copy of Red Hat Developer Studio?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Simply go TBD. </para>
 </section>
 <section id="Installation_Issues">
  <title>Installation Issues</title>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Do I need to have JBoss server installed to run Red Hat Developer Studio?</emphasis></para>
  <para>No. Red Hat Developer Studio already comes bundled with JBoss server. We bundle it together so that you don't need to download any 
  additional software and can test your application in a Web browser right away.</para>
  <para>If you want to use a different JBoss server installation, after installing, simply go to preferences and change the settings to point to another 
  Jboss server installation.</para>
  <para>Red Hat Developer Stuiod works with any serlvet container, not just JBoss. For more information on deployment, please see the Deploying Your Application section.</para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold"> What third-party plug-ins are installed with RHDS?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Read the <link  linkend="Installing">Installing</link> section.</para> 
 </section>
 <section id="Importing_Projects">
  <title>Importing Projects</title>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">I have an existing Struts or JSF project. Can I open the project in RHDS?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Yes. Read the TBD</para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Can I import a .war file?</emphasis></para>
  <para>Yes. Read the TBD</para>
 </section>
 <section id="Troubleshooting">
  <title>Troubleshooting, Problems, Configuration, Error Messages</title>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">Is it possible to increase the performance of Eclipse after installing your product? My Eclipse now crawls.</emphasis></para>
  <para>By default, Eclipse allocates only 128 Mb of memory whatever physical memory you actually have installed. You can significantly increase performance
   if you allocate more memory. For example:</para>
  <para>eclipse.exe -vmargs -Xmx512M</para>
    <para><emphasis role="bold">How can I add my own tag library to the Red Hat Palette?</emphasis></para>
  <para>See Adding Tag Libraries in JBossJSFTools Guide</para>
  <para><emphasis role="bold">I see the Oracle ADF Faces component library tags in the Red Hat Palette, but I can't seem to find the libraries for ADF.
  How do I use this component library with RHDS?</emphasis></para>
  <para>See Adding Support for the Oracle ADF Components Library in the RHDS User Guide.</para>

 </section>
</section>
</chapter>

