<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<chapter id="Birt_Designer" xreflabel="Birt_Designer">
    <?dbhtml filename="birtDesigner.html"?>
    <chapterinfo>
        <keywordset>
            <keyword>JBoss</keyword>
            <keyword>BIRT</keyword>
            <keyword>BIRT Designer</keyword>
            <keyword>BIRT Report Designer</keyword>
        </keywordset>
    </chapterinfo>

    <title>BIRT Report Designer</title>

    <para>BIRT Designer is an intuitive and quite easy Eclipse-based set of plugins to make reports.
        In this chapter we will describe its interface and its features to you.</para>

    <section id="birt_designer_UI" xreflabel="birt_designer_UI">
        <title>BIRT User Interface</title>

        <para>The central part of the user interface is the <property>Layout Editor</property>. It
            displays the whole process of building a report and contains the following tabs:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Layout</emphasis> - this is an area where you can edit
                    your report design;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Preview</emphasis> - runs your report created and shows
                    the output;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Script</emphasis> - on this page you can add JavaScript
                    to your report to customize its behavior;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">XML Source</emphasis> - this is an area where you can
                    view and modify the XML source of your report;</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Master Page</emphasis> - use it to format page
                    data.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>The next part of user interface is different <property>Views</property> that can be
            arranged around the Layout Editor area the way you like:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Palette</emphasis> - shows the standard report items you
                    can add to your report using drag and drop.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Outline</emphasis> - shows the structure of your report
                    as a tree view.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Navigator</emphasis> - shows your projects and reports
                    within the projects.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Data Explorer</emphasis> - shows your data sources, data
                    sets and report parameters. You also can use this view to add data set columns
                    to your report layout.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Property Editor</emphasis> - displays properties for
                    many report items.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Properties View</emphasis> - shows all properties for a
                    report item as a simple list.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Library Explorer View</emphasis> - allows the reuse of
                    report objects, such as tables, data sources and styles. Objects created for
                    reuse are stored in a library file. The Library Explorer will display Libraries
                    that exist in the Resource folder. Developed libraries can be added to the
                    resource folder by selecting <emphasis>File→Publish Library in Resource
                        Folder</emphasis>. The resource folder location can be configured. </para>
            </listitem>

        </itemizedlist>

    </section>

    <section id="birt_designer_features">

        <title>BIRT Report Designer Features</title>
        <para>Here are the main BIRT Report Designer features:</para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Palette</emphasis> - contains tables, labels, and
                    charts. It is used in conjunction with the Layout View to design reports.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Data Explorer</emphasis> - organizes your data sources
                    and data sets. The Data Sets editor enables testing your data set to check
                    whether the report receives the correct data. You can also create cubes using
                    your data sets (when building any dynamic cross tables) and design necessary
                    report parameters.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Resource Explorer</emphasis> - BIRT allows the reuse of
                    report objects, such as tables, data sources and styles. Objects created for
                    reuse are stored in a library file. To browse the contents of report libraries
                    BIRT supplies the Resource Explorer view. This view lists all libraries within
                    the resource folder, in addition to other shared content such as images and
                    JavaScript files.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Property Editor</emphasis> - shows the most commonly
                    used properties. BIRT also integrates with the standard Eclipse property view to
                    display a detailed listing of all properties for an item.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Layout View</emphasis> - WYSIWYG editor. You can select
                    any element from the Palette, drag and drop it to the report and then edit the
                    way you like.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Script Editor</emphasis> - scripting adds business logic
                    to reports during data access, report generation, or viewing. The code editor
                    provides standard features for editing scripts: syntax coloring, auto-complete
                    etc. You also can debug scripts when the report is running.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Report Preview</emphasis> - Report Preview is used to
                    test your newly created report with some real data.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Chart Builder</emphasis> - using the Chart Builder you
                    can add any charts to the design of your report. Just select a chart type, then
                    data and, finally, format the chart.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Expression Builder </emphasis> - expressions are simple
                    scripts that return a value. They are used to assign data values to report
                    elements, build image locations, hyperlinks, parameter default values
                    etc.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Cheat Sheets</emphasis> - Cheat sheets are small peaces
                    of useful documentation that lead you through a report creation process. Just
                    select what you need and then follow the instructions.</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para><emphasis role="bold">Outline</emphasis> - this view provides a compact
                    overview of the entire report structure.</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>In this guide we made a short  overview of the BIRT plugin: its installation, support,
            features etc. that will help you to make your first steps with it.</para>

    </section>

</chapter>
