<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<chapter id="Birt_Designer" xreflabel="Birt_Designer">
    <?dbhtml filename="birtDesigner.html"?>
    <chapterinfo>
        <keywordset>
            <keyword>JBoss</keyword>
            <keyword>BIRT</keyword>
            <keyword>BIRT Designer</keyword>
            <keyword>BIRT Report Designer</keyword>
        </keywordset>
    </chapterinfo>

    <title>BIRT Report Designer</title>
    
        <para>BIRT Designer is an intuitive and quite easy  Eclipse-based set of plugins to make reports. In this chapter we will describe its interface and all its features to you.</para>
          
          <section id="birt_designer_UI" xreflabel="birt_designer_UI">
              <title>BIRT User Interface</title>
              
              <para>The central part of the user interface is the <property>Layout Editor</property>. It displays the whole process of building a report and contains the following tabs:</para>
              
              <itemizedlist>
                  <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Layout</emphasis> - this is an area where you can edit your report design;</para></listitem>   
                  <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Preview</emphasis> - runs your report created and shows the output;</para></listitem>   
                  <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Script</emphasis> - on this page you can add JavaScript to your report to customize its behavior;</para></listitem>   
                  <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">XML Source</emphasis> - this is an area where you can view and modify the XML source of your report;</para></listitem>   
                  <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Master Page</emphasis> - use it to format page data.</para></listitem>   </itemizedlist>
                  
              <para>The next part of user interface is different <property>Views</property> that can be arranged around the Layout Editor area the way you like:</para> 
                  
                  <itemizedlist>
                      <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Palette</emphasis> - BIRT View that shows the standard report items you can add to your report using drag and drop.</para></listitem>
                      <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Outline</emphasis> - BIRT View that shows the structure of your report as a tree view.</para></listitem>
                      <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Navigator</emphasis> - Standard Eclipse view that shows your projects, and the reports within your projects.</para></listitem>
                      <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Data Explorer</emphasis> - BIRT View that shows your data sources (connections), data sets (queries) and report parameters. You also use this view to add data set columns to your report layout.</para></listitem>
                      <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Property Editor</emphasis> - BIRT View that displays properties for many report items. It has tabs and groupings that organize properties into categories.</para></listitem>
                      <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Properties View</emphasis> - Standard Eclipse view that shows all properties for a report item as a simple list. This view is optional, and we will not use it in this tutorial.</para></listitem>
                      <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Library Explorer View</emphasis> - BIRT allows the reuse of report objects, such as tables, data sources and styles. Objects created for reuse are stored in a library file. The Library Explorer will display Libraries that exist in the resource folder. Developed libraries can be added to the resource folder by selecting File→Publish Library to Resource Folder or by right clicking in Library Explorer and selecting add. The resource folder location can be configured. </para></listitem>
                      
                      
                      
                  </itemizedlist>
                  
                  
                  
              
              
          </section>
           
    <section id="birt_designer_features">
       
        <title>BIRT Report Designer Features</title>
        <para>Here are the main BIRT Report Designer features:</para>
        <itemizedlist><listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Palette</emphasis> - contains tables, labels, and charts. It is used in conjunction with the Layout View to design reports.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Data Explorer</emphasis> - Organizes your data sources (connections) and data sets (queries). The data set editor allows you to test your data set to ensure the report receives the correct data. Within this view multi dimensional cubes can be created using existing data sets. Cubes are currently used when building dynamic cross tables. This view also is used to design report parameters.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Resource Explorer</emphasis> - BIRT allows the reuse of report objects, such as tables, data sources and styles. Objects created for reuse are stored in a library file. To browse the contents of report libraries BIRT supplies a Resource Explorer view. This view list all libraries within the resource folder, in addition other shared content such as images and JavaScript files.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Property Editor</emphasis> - Presents the most commonly used properties in a convenient format that makes editing quick and easy. BIRT also integrates with the standard Eclipse property view to provide a detailed listing of all properties for an item.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Layout View</emphasis> - WYSIWYG editor that provides drag and drop creation of the presentation portion of your report.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Script Editor</emphasis> - Scripting adds business logic to reports during data access, during report generation, or during viewing. The code editor provides standard Eclipse features for editing your scripts: syntax coloring, auto-complete and more. An interesting new feature, for BIRT 2.3 is the ability to debug scripts while the report is running.</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Report Preview</emphasis> - You can test your report at any time with real data. The preview is a window directly within Eclipse.</para></listitem>
           <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Chart Builder</emphasis> - Adding Charts to BIRT designs is expedited with the Chart Builder. Chart creation is separated into three phases: Select Chart Type, Select Data, and Format Chart.</para></listitem>
          <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Expression Builder </emphasis> - BIRT expressions are really just simple scripts that return a value. Expressions are used for assigning data values to report elements, building image locations, hyperlinks, parameter default values and many other places. Expressions are constructed within BIRT using the Expression Builder.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Cheat Sheets</emphasis> - Learning a new tool is always a challenge, but Eclipse offers an innovative solution: cheat sheets. These are short bits of documentation that walk you through new tasks.</para></listitem>
        <listitem><para><emphasis role="bold">Outline</emphasis> - BIRT reports are organized as a tree structure with the overall report as the root, and separate categories for styles, report content, data sources, data sets, report parameters and more. The Outline view provides a compact overview of your entire report structure.</para></listitem>
            </itemizedlist>
       
      
      
      
        <para>There are a number of ways we can improve the report's appearance: </para>
        
          <itemizedlist>
          <listitem><para>Add a title to the top of the report;</para></listitem>
            <listitem><para> Add a title to the top of the report. </para></listitem>  
            <listitem><para> Add some color to enhance the column headings. </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para> Shrink the size of the city and state columns. </para></listitem>  
            <listitem><para>Add some color to make the state and city group headers stand out. </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Format the phone numbers. </para></listitem>
            <listitem><para>Sort customers by name.</para></listitem>
           </itemizedlist>
    </section>
</chapter>
