<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<section id="hibernate_datasource">


    <title>Using Hibernate ODA Data Source</title>

    <para>The JBoss BIRT Integration feature includes the Hibernate ODA Data Source which is  completely
        integrated with Hibernate Tools. You can use it the way as you would use any of BIRT ODA drivers.

    </para>

<orderedlist>
    <listitem>
    <para>First, you need to reverse engineer from the database to generate Seam entities. You can perform this operation going to  <emphasis>
            <property>File &gt; New &gt; Seam Generate Entities</property>
        </emphasis> in the <property>Seam perspective</property>. More details on the Seam Generate
        Entities please read <ulink
            url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/nightly-docs/en/seam/html_single/index.html#generate_entities"
            >Seam Dev Tools Reference guide</ulink>). 
        In this guide we will use the <property>Employees</property> table of the <property>DATAMODELS</property> database.      
</para>

    <tip>
        <title>Tip:</title>
        <para>Before performing Seam Generate Entities, you should have a connection profile
            adjusted and connected to a database. How to do this see in the <ulink
                url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosstools/nightly-docs/en/seam/html_single/index.html#d0e2725"
                >CRUD Database Application</ulink> chapter of the Seam Dev Tools Reference
                guide.</para>
        <para>
            If you followed the steps described in the
            <link linkend="birt_integration">Adding BIRT Functionality to Standard Seam Web Project</link> chapter,
            you would have a connection profile already configured.        
                </para>
    </tip>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
<para>
    Next you should create a new BIRT report file ( <emphasis>><property>File &gt; New &gt; Other &gt; Business Intelligence and Reporting
        Tools &gt; Report</property></emphasis>) to represent the data from the <property>Employees</property> table. Call the file <property>employees.rptdesign</property>.
</para>
    </listitem>

<listitem>
   
    
    <para>Now switch to the <property>BIRT Report Design</property> perspective.</para>
</listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>In the <property>Data Explorer</property> view right-click the <emphasis>
            <property>Data Source</property>
        </emphasis> node and choose <emphasis>
            <property>New Data Source</property>.</emphasis></para>

    <figure>
        <title>Creating a New Data Source</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/hibernate_datasource/creatingDataSource.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
</listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>The wizard will prompt you to select data source type.  Choose <emphasis>
            <property>Hibernate Data Source</property>
        </emphasis> and give it a meaningful name, for instance <emphasis>
            <property>HibernateDataSource</property>
        </emphasis>. Hit <emphasis>
            <property>Next</property> to proceed.</emphasis></para>

    <figure>
        <title>Creating Hibernate Data Source</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/hibernate_datasource/hibernateDataSource.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>On the next wizard's dialog you can leave the everything with default values, press the <emphasis>
            <property>Test Connection</property>
    </emphasis> button to verify  that the connection is established successfully.</para>
    
    <para>
        The <property>Hibernate Data Source</property> enables you to specify a Hibernate Configuration or JNDI URL. 
        
    </para>

    <figure>
        <title>Hibernate Data Source Profile</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/hibernate_datasource/connectionSuccessful.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>Press  <emphasis>
            <property>Finish</property>
        </emphasis> to complete <property>New Data Source</property> wizard.</para>
    </listitem>
    
    <listitem>
    <para>Now you need to configure a new Hibernate ODA data set. Launch the
        <property>New Data Set</property> wizard. In the <property>Data Explorer View</property>
        right-click the <emphasis>
            <property>Data Set</property>
        </emphasis> node and select <emphasis>
            <property>New Data Set</property>.</emphasis></para>

    </listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>Select <property>HibernateDataSource</property> as target data source and type in the new data set name.
        Call it <property>HibernateDataSet</property>.</para>




    <figure>
        <title>Creating a Hibernate ODA Data Set</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/hibernate_datasource/addingHibernateODADataset.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>

    <para>The next dialog of the wizard will help you compose a query for the new data set.</para>
    <para>We will make a report that will print all employees in the database who has Sales Rep job title.</para>

       <programlisting role="SQL"><![CDATA[...
select jobtitle, firstname, lastname, email
from Employees as employees where employees.jobtitle = 'Sales Rep'
...]]></programlisting>  
        
    
    
 <para>       
        
        To validate the
        entered query you can press the <emphasis>
            <property>Test query</property>
        </emphasis> button. All the HQL features like syntax highlighting, content assist,
        formatting, drag-and-drop, etc., are available to facilitate query composing.</para>

    <figure>
        <title>Composing query for Data Set</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/hibernate_datasource/testingQuery.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        
    <para>Pressing <property>Finish</property> will call the <property>Edit Data Set</property>  dialog where you can adjust the parameters of the data set and preview the resulted set.
        If everything looks good, hit <property>Ok</property> to generate a new data set.
     </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
        
    <para>Now you can insert the  data set items of <property>HibernateDataSet</property> into the <property>employees.rptdesign</property>.</para>
    

    <tip>
        <title>Tip:</title>
        <para>If you don&apos;t know how to do this we suggest that you refer to the <ulink
                url="http://www.eclipse.org/birt/phoenix/tutorial/">Eclipse BIRT Tutorial</ulink>.</para>
    </tip>
  

<para>You can also use parameters in the query to add  dynamics to your report. In the previous example we hardcoded the selection criterion in the <code>where</code> clause. </para>
    <para>To specify the job title on-the-fly your query should look like this:</para>
    <programlisting role="XML"><![CDATA[
select jobtitle,firstname, lastname,email
from Employees as employees where employees.jobtitle = ?
]]></programlisting> 
    
    <para>The question mark represents a data set input parameter, which is not the same as a report parameter.
        Now you need to define an new report parameter to pass the data to the report, call it <code>JobTitle</code>.
        
        
        
        The dataset parameter can be linked to a report parameter.
        In the <property>Data Explorer</property> view click the Data Set node to open it and right-click
        on the data set you created previously( in our case it is <property>HibernateDataSet</property>),
        choose <property>Edit</property> and navigate to the <property>Parameters</property> section.  
        Declare a new data set parameter, name it <code>jobtitle</code> and map it to the already existing <code>JobTitle</code> report parameter.
        </para>
    </listitem>
    <listitem>
    <para>You report is ready, you can view it by clicking on  the <property>Preview</property> tab of the <property>BIRT Report Designer</property> editor. </para>

    
        <para>You will be prompted to assign a value to the report parameter. For instance you can enter &quot;Sales Rep&quot;. </para>

    <figure>
        <title>Resulted Dynamic Report</title>
        <mediaobject>
            <imageobject>
                <imagedata fileref="images/hibernate_datasource/finalReport.png"/>
            </imageobject>
        </mediaobject>
    </figure>
    </listitem>
</orderedlist>
</section>
