<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<chapter id="introduction">
    <?dbhtml filename="introduction.html"?>

    <chapterinfo>
        <keywordset>
            <keyword>JBoss Developer Studio</keyword>
            <keyword>Eclipse</keyword>
            <keyword>JBoss</keyword>
            <keyword>JBoss Tools</keyword>
            <keyword>JBDS</keyword>
            <keyword>BIRT Plugin</keyword>
        </keywordset>
    </chapterinfo>

    <title>Introduction</title>
    
    
    

    <section>

        <title>What is BIRT?</title>
        <para>BIRT plugin is an Eclipse-based open source reporting system for web applications
            based on Java and J2EE. BIRT consists of two main components: a report designer based on
            Eclipse, and a runtime component that can be added to your app server. BIRT also offers
            a charting engine that lets you add charts to your own Web application.</para>
        <para>With the help of BIRT you can generate a great number of reports to be used in your
            application:</para>

        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Lists</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Charts</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Crosstabs, or cross-tabulation, or matrix</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Letters and Documents</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>Compound Reports</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <para>You can find more detailed information on the BIRT plugin, its report types and
            anatomy on the <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/birt/phoenix/intro/">BIRT Homepage</ulink>.</para>

        <para>To understand the basic BIRT concepts and to know how to create a basic BIRT report,
            refer to the <ulink url="http://www.eclipse.org/birt/phoenix/tutorial/">Eclipse BIRT
                Tutorials</ulink>. What extensions <property>JBoss Tools</property> provides for
            Eclipse BIRT you&apos;ll find out in the next sections.</para>
    </section>


    
    <section>
        <title>JBoss BIRT Integration Functionality Overview</title>
        
        <para>
            The key feature of JBoss BIRT Integration  is the JBoss BIRT Integration Framework, which allows to integrate a BIRT report into Seam/JSF container.
            The framework API reference is in the 
            <link linkend="framework">JBoss BIRT Integraion Framework API Reference</link> chapter of the guide.
        </para>     
        <para>
            
            This  guide also covers functionality of <property>JBoss Tools</property> module  which assists in  
            integration with BIRT.
            The integration plug-in allows you to visually configure <property>Hibernate Data Source</property> (specify a Hibernate configuration or JNDI URL),  
            compose HQL queries with syntax-highlighting, content-assist, formatting as well as other functionalities available in the HQL editor. 
           
           
          </para>

        <para>
            To enable <property>JBoss Tools</property> integration with BIRT you are intended to
            have the next:
        </para>
        <itemizedlist>
            <listitem>
                <para>Eclipse with <property>JBoss Tools</property>
                    installed (how to install <property>JBoss Tools</property> on Eclipse, what
                    dependences and versions requirements are needed reed in the <ulink
                        url="&gsglink;#JBossToolsInstall"
                        >JBoss Tools Installation</ulink> section)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>BIRT Report Designer (BIRT Report Designer 2.3.2 
                    you can download from <ulink
                        url="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/download.php?file=/birt/downloads/drops/R-R1-2_3_2-200902181355/birt-report-framework-2_3_2.zip"
                        >Eclipse downloads site</ulink>)</para>
            </listitem>
            <listitem>
                <para>BIRT Web Tools Integration ( BIRT WTP Integration 2.3.2 you can download from
                        <ulink
                        url="http://www.eclipse.org/downloads/download.php?file=/birt/downloads/drops/R-R1-2_3_2-200902181355/birt-wtp-integration-sdk-2_3_2.zip"
                            >Eclipse downloads site</ulink>)</para>
            </listitem>
        </itemizedlist>

        <note>
            <title>Note:</title>
            <para>Versions of BIRT framework and BIRT WTP integration should be no less than RC4 in
                order to the BIRT facet works correctly.</para>
        </note>
    </section>

    

</chapter>
