<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>
<!DOCTYPE chapter PUBLIC "-//OASIS//DTD DocBook XML V4.5//EN" "http://www.oasis-open.org/docbook/xml/4.5/docbookx.dtd" [
<!ENTITY % BOOK_ENTITIES SYSTEM "Cloud_Tools_Reference_Guide.ent">
%BOOK_ENTITIES;
]>
<section id="sect-Cloud_Tools_Reference_Guide-Tasks-using_the_deltacloud_perspective">
	<title>Using the Deltacloud perspective</title>
	<para>
		The Deltacloud perspective consists of three different views: <guilabel>Cloud Viewer</guilabel>, <guilabel>Images</guilabel> and <guilabel>Instances</guilabel>.
	</para>
	<section id="thecloudviewer">
		<title>The Cloud Viewer</title>
		
		<para>
	  		The <guilabel>Cloud Viewer</guilabel> view lists the servers you are connected to, the instances running on each server and the images available on each server. Right-clicking (or control-clicking on Mac OS) on a cloud connection presents you with options to delete a cloud using the <guimenuitem>Delete Cloud</guimenuitem> option or reload the the cloud view with the <guimenuitem>Refresh View</guimenuitem> option. 
	  </para>
		
		<para>   
	  		You can also right-click (or control-click on Mac OS) anywhere in the <guilabel>Cloud Viewer</guilabel> view and select the <guilabel>Launch Instance</guilabel> option to launch a new instance. See <xref linkend="theimagesview"/> for more information on launching an instance.
	  </para>
		
		<para>   
	  	Clicking on a connection name causes details to be shown in the <guilabel>Properties</guilabel> view.
	  </para>
		
		<figure id="deltacloud_perspective-the_cloud_viewer">
			<title>Deltacloud perspective: The Cloud Viewer</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Deltacloud-perspective-cloud_viewer.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>
			 You can have multiple Deltacloud servers connected at any one time. If you have not yet setup a connection to a Deltacloud server see <xref linkend="sect-Cloud_Tools_Reference_Guide-Tasks-connecting_to_a_deltacloud_server"/>. You will also require a unique key file for each user who is to have access to the server. To add and manage your key files see <xref linkend="sect-Cloud_Tools_Reference_Guide-Tasks-add_and_manage_server_keys"/>
		</para>
	
	</section>
	<section id="theimagesview">
		<title id="imagesview">The Images view</title>
		<para>
	      Displayed in the <guilabel>Images</guilabel> view is a table of all images for a specified cloud.
	   </para>
		
		<figure id="deltacloud_perspective-the_images_view">
			<title>Deltacloud perspective: The Images view</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Deltacloud-perspective-images_view.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>
			By right-clicking (or control-clicking on Mac OS) on an image in the table and selecting <guimenuitem>Launch Instance</guimenuitem>, a dialog will appear. Define the <guilabel>Name</guilabel> of the instance, the <guilabel>Realm</guilabel> the instance should appear in, select a predefined <guilabel>Hardware Profile</guilabel> and choose a <guilabel>Key Name</guilabel> for key file authentication. You can also change the default image by defining the value for the <guilabel>Image</guilabel> field, or by clicking the <guibutton>Find...</guibutton> button.
		</para>
		<para>
			User authentication keys are managed for Deltacloud tooling by the <guilabel>Manage Keys</guilabel> dialog. When clicking on the <guibutton>Manage</guibutton> you will be presented with this dialog. Select one from the list or add a new one by clicking the <guibutton>New</guibutton> button. Newly created keys will also be added to the SSH2 key list if they are not already present.
	  </para>
		<para>
	  		Click the <guibutton>Next</guibutton> button to move to the next step.
    </para>
		<figure id="deltacloud_perspective-launching_an_instance">
			<title>Deltacloud perspective: Launching an instance</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Deltacloud-perspective-launch_instance.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
		<para>
			The next wizard page allows you to explicitly create an Eclipse Remote System Explorer (RSE), which is used to browse the remote filesystem and connect to the instance via an SSH terminal.
		</para>
		
		<para>
			You can also create a Web Tools Platform (WTP) server adapter, which will allow you to deploy any WTP compliant web project to the remote instance.
		</para>
				
		<para>
	  		Click the <guibutton>Finish</guibutton> button to launch the new instance and any RSE Connections or WTP Adapters that you have defined.
    </para>
    
    	<figure id="deltacloud_perspective-launching_an_instance2">
			<title>Deltacloud perspective: Defining an RSE Connection and a WTP Adapter</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Deltacloud-perspective-launch_instance2.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		
	</section>
	<section id="theinstancesview">
		<title>The Instances view</title>
		<para>
			Through the <guilabel>Instances</guilabel> view you can see all instances for a cloud server while having the functionality to start, stop and restart a selected instance.
		</para>
		
		<figure id="deltacloud_perspective-the_instances_view">
			<title>Deltacloud perspective: The Instances view</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Deltacloud-perspective-instances_view.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>
	   	Using the <guilabel>Remote System Explorer</guilabel> (<xref linkend="sect-Cloud_Tools_Reference_Guide-Task-using_the_remote_system_explorer"/>) you can connect to a running instance through the SSH protocol. Accessing a remote instance requires authentication; for an EC2 instance a PEM key file will be used. 
    </para>
		<para>
	  	Once connected, files on the external instance can be manipulated as if they were on your local machine.
    </para>
	</section>
</section>



