<chapter id="installation">
    <title>Install &amp; Upgrade</title>
    <para>Eclipse offers an easy way to install/upgrade features. It is done by hand the first time and then, Eclipse can check whether updates are available, download them and install them.</para>
    <para>This chapter describes how to install JBoss-IDE with the install/update features of Eclipse, and how to stay up-to-date automatically.</para>
    <section>
    	<title>Eclipse 3.1.x</title>
    	<para>
    		Follow these steps :
    		<itemizedlist>
    			<listitem>Start Eclipse.</listitem>
    			<listitem>Select <literal>Help</literal> &gt; <literal>Software Updates</literal> &gt; <literal>Find and Install...</literal></listitem>
    			<listitem>Select <literal>Search for new features to install</literal>, and press <literal>Next &gt;</literal></listitem>
    			<listitem>
    				Select <literal>New Remote Site...</literal> from the right menu. In the dialog fill the name with <literal>JBoss Eclipse IDE</literal>
    				and the URL with <ulink url="http://download.jboss.org/jbosside/updates/stable">http://download.jboss.org/jbosside/updates/stable</ulink>
    			</listitem>
    			<listitem>
    				Make sure <literal>JBoss Eclipse IDE</literal> has a check next to it, and press <literal>Finish</literal>.
    			</listitem>
    			<listitem>
    				Expand the <literal>JBoss Eclipse IDE</literal> tree, and check the release named <literal>JBossIDE 1.5</literal>.
    				Click <literal>Next &gt;</literal>, and Eclipse will ask you if you agree to the licensing terms of JBoss Eclipse IDE.
    				If you agree, select <literal>I accept the terms in the license agreement</literal>, and press <literal>Next &gt;</literal>
    			</listitem>
    			<listitem>
    				Eclipse will show you a list of features it is going to install. See <link linkend="jbosside.features">Figure 1</link>. Press <literal>Finish</literal> to start installation.
    			</listitem>
    			<listitem>
    				After all the features have been downloaded, Eclipse will prompt if you want to install each feature.
    				The quickest way to install everything is to press the <literal>Install All</literal> button.
    			</listitem>
    			<listitem>At the end of the installation, you will be prompted to restart Eclipse. Click <literal>Yes</literal>.</listitem>
    		</itemizedlist>
    		
			<tip>If you are behind a proxy you have to go to <literal>Window</literal> &gt; <literal>Preferences</literal> &gt; <literal>Install/Update</literal>,
			select <literal>Enable HTTP Proxy Connection</literal> and insert values for <literal>Host Address</literal> and <literal>Port</literal>.</tip>
			
			<tip>You can be notified when new updates are available. You can also configure Eclipse to fetch new updates and make them ready to install.
			All this configuration can be done through the  <literal>Help</literal> &gt; <literal>Software Updates</literal> &gt; <literal>Configuration Manager</literal> menu.</tip>
		
    		Have a look at the Eclipse documentation to get more information about the Configuration Manager.
			<figure id="jbosside.features">
            <title>Features in JBoss Eclipse IDE 1.5.</title>
            <mediaobject>
                <imageobject>
                    <imagedata align="center" fileref="images/jbosside-1.5-features.jpg"/>
                </imageobject>
            </mediaobject>
        </figure>
    	</para>
    </section>
</chapter>
