<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>

<chapter id="introduction">
	<title>Introduction</title>

	<para>
		The purpose of this document is to describe briefly the functionality present in the <property>Eclipse Guvnor Tools</property> (EGT) for Drools 5. While not intended as a comprehensive reference, there should be enough detail included for early adopters using these tools.
	</para>

	<para>The table below lists the key features of <property>Guvnor Tools:</property>
	</para>

	<section id="drools_key_features">
		<title>Guvnor Tools Key Features</title>

		<para>The following table lists all valuable features of the <property>Guvnor
                Tools</property>.</para>
		<table>
			<title>Key Functionality of Guvnor Tools</title>
			<tgroup cols="3">

				<colspec colnum="1" align="left" colwidth="1*"/>
				<colspec colnum="2" colwidth="5*"/>
				<colspec colnum="3" align="left" colwidth="1*"/>

				<thead>
					<row>
						<entry>Feature</entry>
						<entry>Benefit</entry>
						<entry>Chapter</entry>
					</row>
				</thead>

				<tbody>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>Guvnor Repositories View</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>The purpose of this view is to enable access to Guvnor repository resources in a standard tree format</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="guvnor_repositories_view"/>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>Guvnor Connection Wizard</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>This wizard helps to create a connection to a Guvnor repository.</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="connection_wizard"/>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>Guvnor Resource History View</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>This view shows revisions of specific resources available in the repository.</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="guvnor_history_view"/>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>Resource from Guvnor wizard</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>This wizard helps to get local copies of Guvnor repository resources.</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="resources_from_guvnor"/>
						</entry>
					</row>

					<row>
						<entry>
							<para>A number of actions for working with files</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<para>
								The Guvnor actions (available through the <guilabel>Guvnor</guilabel> context menu on files) are provided for working with files, both those associated with Guvnor repository master copies and those not associated.
							</para>
						</entry>
						<entry>
							<xref linkend="actions"/>
						</entry>
					</row>

				</tbody>
			</tgroup>
		</table>
	</section>
	<section id="what_is_guvnor_tools">
		<title>What is Guvnor Tools?</title>
		<para>
			The <property>Guvnor repository</property> is not intended to be a Source Code Management (SCM) solution, and the <property>EGT</property> is not intended to be an Eclipse “team provider” extension or replacement. Rather, the Guvnor repository is a location where certain artifacts (such as rules and SOA policy definitions) are controlled (“governed”) by policies defined by the deployment environment. The purpose of the <property>EGT</property> is then to enable access to resources held by the Guvnor repository, so they can be used in development. Thus, limited capabilities for reading, writing, adding, and removing Guvnor repository resources are provided in the <property>EGT</property>.
		</para>
	</section>
	<section id="how_to_start">
		<title>Requirements and Installation</title>

		<para>
			<property>Guvnor Tools</property> is a part of the <property>JBoss Tools</property> project. Thus to get started with Guvnor Tools, you should have the following:
    </para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<!--Eclipse IDE with installed JBoss Tools plugins. How to install JBoss Tools onto Eclipse you can find in the JBoss Tools Installation section.-->
					JBoss Developer Studio, which can be downloaded through the <ulink url="https://access.redhat.com">RedHat customer portal</ulink>.
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>JBoss Server 4.2 or higher with Guvnor repository deployed.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>
			To deploy JBoss Server with the Guvnor repository, you should download <ulink url="http://www.jboss.org/drools/downloads.html">Drools Guvnor</ulink>. When downloading you may choose either web based Guvnor to deploy to your JBoss Server or Standalone Guvnor with JBoss AS.
		</para>
		<para>
			If you use JBoss AS 5 and <property>Guvnor Tools</property> doesn't work when deployed to the server, you should perform the following steps to get Guvnor Tools running:
		</para>
		<orderedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Remove the  JBoss Security libraries (<filename>authorization-spi-2.0.2.CR6.jar</filename>, <filename>identity-*</filename>, <filename>acl-spi-2.0.2.CR6.jar</filename>) from drools WAR file (not the app server itself). The JBoss Security libraries are provided in AS 5.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Remove the JAXP libraries (<filename>xercesImpl-2.8.0.jar</filename>, <filename>xml-apis-2.*</filename>)</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>Remove the EL libraries (<filename>el-*</filename>)</para>
			</listitem>
		</orderedlist>
		<para>
			When these steps have been performed, Guvnor should operate as normal. During deployment, you would see the following exception in the log which indicates that the experimental JBoss Security based ACL integration has defined some EJB3/JPA features in guvnor that have not been configured.
		</para>
		<programlisting>ERROR [AbstractKernelController] Error installing to Start: name=persistence.unit:unitName=#ACL state=Create
java.lang.RuntimeException: Specification violation [EJB3 JPA 6.2.1.2] - You have not defined a non-jta-data-source 
for a RESOURCE_LOCAL enabled persistence context named: ACL            
    </programlisting>
	</section>

</chapter>
