<?xml version='1.0' encoding='utf-8' ?>

<chapter id="chap-Beginners_Guide-Service_Oriented_Architecture_Development">
	<title>Service-Oriented Architecture Development</title>
	<para>
		Included <application>JBoss Developer Studio</application> plug-ins for development on Service-Oriented Architecture (SOA) are detailed.
	</para>
	<section id="sect-Beginners_Guide-Service_Oriented_Architecture_Development-jBPM_Tools">
		<title>jBPM Tools</title>
		<para>
			jBPM is a workflow tool for framework control over business processes and languages.
		</para>
		<para>
			jBPM supports the jBPM Process Definition Language (jPDL) and includes a perspective for easy creation and manipulation using the jPDL. Through this view you can add states, transitions and other processes and waypoints in order to create your own business workflow. Refer to the <citetitle pubwork="section">A Minimal Process Definition</citetitle> section of the <citetitle pubwork="chapter">Creating an Empty Process Definition</citetitle> chapter within the <citetitle pubwork="book">jBPM Tools Reference Guide</citetitle> for more details.
		</para>
		<para>
			Refer to the <citetitle pubwork="book">jBPM Tools Reference Guide</citetitle> for further details.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Beginners_Guide-Service_Oriented_Architecture_Development-ESB_Editor">
		<title>ESB Editor</title>
		<para>
			The Enterprise Service Bus (ESB) is an abstraction layer that interacts with the messaging system in a Service-Oriented Architecture (SOA).
		</para>
		<figure id="figu-Beginners_Guide-ESB_Editor-ESB_Editor">
			<title>ESB Editor</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/ESB_Editor.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>
			The <application>JBoss Developer Studio</application> includes a tool called the ESB file Editor. Through the use of this tool you can develop an application that will utilize the advantages of ESB technology. Features of the ESB Editor include:
		</para>
		<formalpara id="form-Beginners_Guide-ESB_Editor-ESB_syntax_validation">
			<title>ESB syntax validation</title>
			<para>
				Contextual error checking is provided constantly, with error checking on incorrect or incomplete tags also included when using the Source viewer.
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<formalpara id="form-Beginners_Guide-ESB_Editor-XML_schema_support">
			<title>XML schema support</title>
			<para>
				By checking the child elements of the providers, the ESB Editor relays incorrect usage combinations to you through error messages upon startup.
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<formalpara id="form-Beginners_Guide-ESB_Editor-ESB_XML_content_assistance">
			<title>ESB XML content assistance</title>
			<para>
				Content Assist enables you to write code fast and with accuracy when using the Source mode.
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<formalpara id="form-Beginners_Guide-ESB_Editor-Synchronized_source_and_visual_editing">
			<title>Synchronized source and visual editing</title>
			<para>
				The ESB Editor gives you the choice of using a graphical view (Tree), a code view (Source) or both when developing your ESB applications. With both instances open at once, the changes made to one can be directly viewable in the other, ensuring that you are always working with the most current version of your application no matter your choice.
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<para>
			Refer to the <citetitle pubwork="chapter">ESB Editor</citetitle> chapter of the <citetitle pubwork="book">ESB Tools Reference Guide</citetitle> for further information.
		</para>
		<para>
			Allowing for the value of messaging between middleware components to be used and intergrated into the JBoss Service-Oriented Architecture, the JBoss ESB is an integral part of JBoss middleware integration. For information on how to use and configure JBoss ESB with the JBoss Service-Oriented Architecture refer to the <citetitle pubwork="chapter">Using and Configuring SOA Platform</citetitle> chapter of the <citetitle pubwork="book">ESB Tools Reference Guide</citetitle>.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Beginners_Guide-Service_Oriented_Architecture_Development-Web_Services_Tools">
		<title>Web Services Tools</title>
		<para>
			JBoss Web Services is an integral part of the JBoss Application Server and JBoss Enterprise Application Platform, providing a standard means of working reliably between different software applications.
		</para>
		<para>
			A Web Service defines a collection of technologies that provide protocols and standards for the exchange of data between applications. You can create a Web Service for your application server through the use of wizards in the <application>JBoss Developer Studio</application>. For further details refer to the <citetitle pubwork="chapter">Creating a Web Service using JBossWS runtime</citetitle> chapter of the <citetitle pubwork="book">JBoss WS User Guide</citetitle>
		</para>
		<figure id="figu-Beginners_Guide-Web_Services_Tools-Example_of_a_Web_Services_wizard">
			<title>Example of a Web Services wizard</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Web_Services_Wizard.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<para>
			Web Services Tools also includes the ability to create a Web Service client through the use of a Web Services Description Language (WSDL) document. This can be useful if you already have a predefined service that you wish to recreate, or you wish to use one as a template for you to work with. Refer to the <citetitle pubwork="chapter">Creating a Web Service Client from a WSDL Document using JBoss WS</citetitle> chapter of the <citetitle pubwork="book">JBoss WS User Guide</citetitle> for more details.
		</para>
		<figure id="figu-Beginners_Guide-Web_Services_Tools-Web_Services_client_creation">
			<title>Web Services client creation</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Web_Services_Using_Document.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Beginners_Guide-Service_Oriented_Architecture_Development-Drools_Tools">
		<title>Drools Tools</title>
		<para>
			Drools is a Business Rule Management System (BRMS) that uses an enhanced implementation of the Rete algorithm to become a forward chaining inference based rules engine (production rule system). Refer to the <citetitle pubwork="chapter">The Rule Engine</citetitle> chapter of the JBoss Enterprise SOA <citetitle pubwork="book">JBoss Rules Reference Guide</citetitle> for more details.
		</para>
		<para>
			Drools Tools includes wizards for creating new Drools projects and resources. The resources that can be created include a new rule, domain specific language, decision table and business rule. After these have been created there are numerous editors included to assist you with the rest of the development. Included editors are The Rule editor, The Domain Specific Language editor, The Rule Flow graphical editor and The Guided editor that provides a Graphical User Interface (GUI). Refer to the <citetitle pubwork="book">Drools Tools Reference Guide</citetitle> for more details.
		</para>
		<figure id="figu-Beginners_Guide-Drools_Tools-Rule_text_editor">
			<title>Rule text editor</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Drools_code_rule_editor.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<figure id="figu-Beginners_Guide-Drools_Tools-Rule_Flow_graphical_editor">
			<title>Rule Flow graphical editor</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Drools_rete_rule_editor.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</section>
	
	<section id="sect-Beginners_Guide-Service_Oriented_Architecture_Development-Eclipse_Guvnor_Tools">
		<title>Eclipse Guvnor Tools</title>
		<para>
			Eclipse Guvnor Tools work with Drools Guvnor through rich web based GUIs and editors to provide a centralized repository for a vast quantity of rules. You can store versions of rules, models, functions, processes and other Drools generated components that all relate to executeable knowledge bases. Access to the Guvnor is controlled, allowing you to lock down access and restrict features so domain experts (non programmers) can view and edit rules without being exposed to all the features at once.
		</para>
		<para>
			The tools included for Eclipse Guvnor are outlined as follows:
		</para>
		<formalpara id="form-Beginners_Guide-Eclipse_Guvnor_Tools-Guvnor_Connection_Wizard">
			<title>Guvnor Connection Wizard</title>
			<para>
				The Guvnor Connection Wizard is used to create a connection to a Guvnor repository. This wizard can be started by following the menu items <menuchoice><guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>New</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Other</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Guvnor</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Guvnor repository location</guimenuitem></menuchoice>, through the Guvnor Repositories View and other locations throughout Eclipse Guvnor Tools. Refer to the <citetitle pubwork="section">Guvnor Connection Wizard</citetitle> section of the <citetitle pubwork="chapter">Functionality Overview</citetitle> chapter within the <citetitle pubwork="book">Eclipse Guvnor Tools Reference Guide</citetitle> for more details.
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<figure id="figu-Beginners_Guide-Eclipse_Guvnor_Tools-Guvnor_connection_wizard">
			<title>Guvnor connection wizard</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Guvnor_connection_wizard.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<formalpara id="form-Beginners_Guide-Eclipse_Guvnor_Tools-The_Guvnor_Repositories_View">
			<title>The Guvnor Repositories View</title>
			<para>
				The Guvnor Repositories View tool displays the contents of a repository using a tree structure. From within this tool you can create a new Guvnor repository connection, remove a Guvnor repository connection, refresh the tree display and expand or condense the tree layout. Refer to the <citetitle pubwork="section">Guvnor Repositories View</citetitle> section of the <citetitle pubwork="chapter">Functionality Overview</citetitle> chapter within the <citetitle pubwork="book">Eclipse Guvnor Tools Reference Guide</citetitle> for more details.
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<figure id="figu-Beginners_Guide-Eclipse_Guvnor_Tools-Guvnor_repository_view">
			<title>Guvnor repository view</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Guvnor_repository.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<formalpara id="form-Beginners_Guide-Eclipse_Guvnor_Tools-Guvnor_Resource_History_View">
			<title>Guvnor Resource History View</title>
			<para>
				The task of the Guvnor Resource History View is to display the revision history details for files that are both locally stored and within Guvnor repositories. Refer to the <citetitle pubwork="section">Guvnor Resource History View</citetitle> section of the <citetitle pubwork="chapter">Functionality Overview</citetitle> chapter within the <citetitle pubwork="book">Eclipse Guvnor Tools Reference Guide</citetitle> for more details.
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<figure id="figu-Beginners_Guide-Eclipse_Guvnor_Tools-Guvnor_resource_history_view">
			<title>Guvnor resource history view</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Guvnor_resource_history_view.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<formalpara id="form-Beginners_Guide-Eclipse_Guvnor_Tools-Guvnor_Resource_Importing_Wizard">
			<title>Guvnor Resource Importing Wizard</title>
			<para>
				The Guvnor Resource Importing Wizard assists with the copying of one or more files from a Guvnor repository to the local workspace (while keeping file association with the Guvnor repository). This wizard can be started by following the menu items <menuchoice><guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Import</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Guvnor</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Resource from Guvnor</guimenuitem></menuchoice>. Refer to the <citetitle pubwork="section">Importing Guvnor Repository Resources</citetitle> section of the <citetitle pubwork="chapter">Functionality Overview</citetitle> chapter within the <citetitle pubwork="book">Eclipse Guvnor Tools Reference Guide</citetitle> for more details.
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<figure id="figu-Beginners_Guide-Eclipse_Guvnor_Tools-Guvnor_resource_importing_wizard">
			<title>Guvnor resource importing wizard</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/Guvnor_copy_file.png" format="PNG" />
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<formalpara id="form-Beginners_Guide-Eclipse_Guvnor_Tools-Actions_for_Local_Guvnor_Resources">
			<title>Actions for Local Guvnor Resources</title>
			<para>
				Through Eclipse Guvnor Tools a variety of actions can be performed on a file. Those actions are:
			</para>
		</formalpara>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>Update</emphasis>: Replaces the contents of the local file with the updated contents from the Guvnor repository.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>Add</emphasis>: Include a local file in a Guvnor repository.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>Commit</emphasis>: Update a Guvnor repository file with new content from a locally modified version.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>Show History</emphasis>: Displays the revision history of a file.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>Compare with Version</emphasis>: Opens a wizard that allows to files to be compared for similarities and differences.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>Switch to Version</emphasis>: Provides the ability to replace a local file with an earlier revision of the same file.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>Delete</emphasis>: Removes a file from the Guvnor repository and the local copy.
				</para>
			</listitem>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					<emphasis>Disconnect</emphasis>: Removes a Guvnor repository association.
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>
		<para>
			Refer to the <citetitle pubwork="section">Actions for Local Guvnor Resources</citetitle> section of the <citetitle pubwork="chapter">Functionality Overview</citetitle> chapter within the <citetitle pubwork="book">Eclipse Guvnor Tools Reference Guide</citetitle> for more details.
		</para>
	</section>
	
	

</chapter>

