<?xml version='1.0' encoding='UTF-8'?>
<chapter id="guvnor_preferences">
	<?dbhtml filename="guvnor_preferences.html"?>
	<chapterinfo>
		<keywordset>
			<keyword>JBoss Tools</keyword>
			<keyword>Eclipse Guvnor Tools</keyword>
		</keywordset>
	</chapterinfo>

	<title>Reference</title>
	<para>This chapter includes detailed reference information about Views and Wizards used to manage Guvnor Tools.</para>

	<section id="guvnor_perspective">
		<title>Guvnor Repository Exploring Perspective</title>

		<para>
			The <property>Guvnor Repository Exploring perspective</property> contains two views supplied by <property>EGT</property>, described in <xref linkend="guvnor_repositories_view"/> and <xref linkend="guvnor_history_view"/>, that will be the center of most interactions with Guvnor. Eclipse standard views such as <guilabel>Properties</guilabel> and <guilabel>Resource Navigator</guilabel> are also useful.
		</para>

		<para>
			While each of these views can be opened and positioned independently within an Eclipse workbench, the <property>Guvnor perspective</property> provides a convenient method for displaying a common layout. In the Eclipse workbench menu, select <menuchoice><guimenuitem>Window</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Open Perspective</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Other</guimenuitem></menuchoice> to view the perspective list:
		</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Enabling the Guvnor Repository Perspective</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/open_guvnor_perspectine.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>Selecting the <guimenuitem>Guvnor Repository Exploring</guimenuitem> option will open the <guilabel>Guvnor</guilabel> perspective.</para>
	</section>

	<section id="connection_wizard">
		<title>Guvnor Connection Wizard</title>

		<para>
			The Guvnor Connection wizard appears in a number of places within the <property>EGT</property> (as detailed below), but in this section we will cover only the two most basic entry points.
		</para>

		<para>The <guilabel>Guvnor Connection wizard</guilabel> can be started in the following ways:</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>
					Selecting <menuchoice><guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>New</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Other</guimenuitem> <guimenuitem>Guvnor</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Guvnor repository location</guimenuitem></menuchoice> within Eclipse		
				</para>

				<figure>
					<title>New Guvnor Repository Location</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/start_guvnor_connection1.png"/>
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>In the <guilabel>Guvnor Repositories</guilabel> view using the drop-down menu</para>

				<figure>
					<title>Adding New Guvnor Connection</title>
					<mediaobject>
						<imageobject>
							<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/start_guvnor_connection2.png"/>
						</imageobject>
					</mediaobject>
				</figure>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>using the menu button 
                    ( <inlinemediaobject>
                        <imageobject>
                            <imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/guvnor_connection_button.png"/>
						</imageobject>
					</inlinemediaobject> )
                </para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<para>Choosing either of these will start the <guilabel>Guvnor Connection</guilabel> wizard.</para>

		<figure id="guvnor_connection_wizard">
			<title>Guvnor Connection Wizard</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/guvnor_connection_wizard.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Default values appear in the <guilabel>Location</guilabel>, <guilabel>Port</guilabel> and <guilabel>Repository</guilabel> fields (See <xref linkend="guvnor_preferences"/> for details about on changing these default values). Of course, any of these fields can be edited by editing the corresponding text box. Drag-and-drop or paste into the <guilabel>Location</guilabel> field a typical Guvnor repository URL such as:
		</para>

		<para>
				<ulink url="http://localhost:8080/drools-guvnor/org.drools.guvnor.Guvnor/webdav">http://localhost:8080/drools-guvnor/org.drools.guvnor.Guvnor/webdav</ulink>
		</para>

		<para>
			This results in the URL being parsed into the respective fields as well. The authentication information (user name and password) can optionally be stored in the Eclipse workbench&apos;s key-ring file based on the selection of <guilabel>Save user name and password</guilabel>.
		</para>

		<note>
			<title>Note:</title>
			<para>
				If the authentication information is not stored in the key-ring, then the <property>EGT</property> uses a session authentication, what means that the credentials supplied are only used during the lifetime of the Eclipse workbench instance.
			</para>
		</note>

		<para>
			If authentication information is not stored in the key-ring, or the authentication information (key-ring or session) is not valid, the <property>EGT</property> will prompt for the authentication information once it has to access the Guvnor repository.
		</para>

		<para>If authentication fails, the <property>EGT</property> will retry once and then issue an authentication failure error.</para>

		<note>
			<title>Tip:</title>
			<para>If an authentication failure error occurs, you can retry the same operation and supply different authentication information.</para>
		</note>

		<para>
			Note that the <property>EGT</property> calls the Guvnor repository at various times, such as when it is determining if any resource updates are available. Thus if you use session authentication, the authentication dialog will appear at different times during the Eclipse workbench session, depending on what actions you take. For ease of use, we recommend saving the authentication information in the Eclipse key-ring.
		</para>

		<note>
			<title>Note:</title>
			<para>
				The Eclipse key-ring file is distinct from key-ring files found in some platforms such as Mac OS X and many forms of Linux. Thus, sometimes if you access a Guvnor repository outside the <property>EGT</property>, the key-ring files might become outdated, and you will be unexpectedly prompted for your credentials in Eclipse. This is nuisance, but in this case you can simply re-enter the appropriate username and password.
			</para>
		</note>
	</section>

	<section id="resources_from_guvnor">
		<title>Resource from Guvnor Wizard</title>

		<para>
			In addition to the single file drag-and-drop features provided within the <guilabel>Guvnor Repositories</guilabel> view, the <property>EGT</property> also includes a wizard for copying one or more files from a Guvnor repository to the local workspace (and setting the association with the Guvnor repository). This wizard is available by selecting <menuchoice><guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Import</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Guvnor</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Resource from Guvnor</guimenuitem></menuchoice> or <menuchoice><guimenuitem>File</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>New</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Other</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Guvnor</guimenuitem><guimenuitem>Resource from Guvnor</guimenuitem></menuchoice>.
		</para>
		<note>
			<title>Note:</title>

			<para>
				Note that the wizard is identical but appears in both locations to accommodate users who tend to view this functionality as being in either category.
			</para>
		</note>

		<para>
			The first page of the wizard asks for the selection of the source Guvnor repository and gives the option to create a new Guvnor repository connection (in which case the second page is the same as the <xref linkend="guvnor_connection_wizard"/>).
		</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Resource from Guvnor Wizard</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/add_toGuvnor_wizard.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>Once the source Guvnor repository is chosen, the wizard prompts for the resources to be copied:</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Resource Selection</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/resource_from_guvnor.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>Finally, the target location in the local workspace should be chosen:</para>
		<figure>
			<title>Choosing the Target Location</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/resource_from_guvnor2.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			On completion the wizard copies the selected files from the Guvnor repository to the local workspace. If a file with the same name already exists in the destination, the wizard uses the Eclipse standard <guilabel>prompt for rename</guilabel> dialog:
		</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Prompt for Rename Dialog</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/resource_from_guvnor3.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
	</section>

	<section id="guvnor_repositories_view">
		<title>Guvnor Repositories View</title>

		<para>The <guilabel>Guvnor Repositories</guilabel> view contains tree structures representing the contents of Guvnor repositories.</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Guvnor Repositories View</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/guvnor_repository.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>You can perform the following actions under the resources in the <guilabel>Guvnor Repositories</guilabel> view:</para>

		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Create a new Guvnor repository connection. This process is described above in <xref linkend="connection_wizard"/>.</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					Remove a Guvnor repository connection. Use the Delete button ( <inlinemediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/delete_connection_button.png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> ) in the toolbar or the <guimenuitem>Delete</guimenuitem> option in the context menu to remove a repository connection.
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					Refresh Guvnor repository resources. Use the <guimenuitem>Refresh</guimenuitem> context menu item to reload the tree for the selected node.
				</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>
					Make use of &quot;drill-into&quot; functionality. It&apos;s represented by a number of toolbar and context menu items such as <guibutton>Go Home</guibutton> ( <inlinemediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/go_home_button.png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> ), <guibutton>Go Back</guibutton> ( <inlinemediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/go_back_button.png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> ) and <guibutton>Go Into</guibutton> ( <inlinemediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/go_into_button.png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> ).
				</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<para>
			Drill-down is useful when working with deeply nested tree structures, and when you wish to concentrate on only a single branch of the tree. For example, drilling into the <guilabel>defaultPackage</guilabel> node changes the tree view to:
		</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Going Into the <guilabel>defaultPackage</guilabel>
			</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/go_into_defaultPackage.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Clicking on the <guibutton>Go Home</guibutton> button ( <inlinemediaobject><imageobject><imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/go_home_button.png"/></imageobject></inlinemediaobject> ) or selecting <guimenuitem>Go Home</guimenuitem> in the context menu returns the 	tree to the top-level structure shown in the previous picture above.
		</para>

		<para>
			There are a number of operations that can be performed on Guvnor repository files. Selecting a file in the Guvnor repository causes the Eclipse <guilabel>Properties</guilabel> view to display the details of that file:
    </para>

		<figure>
			<title>Guvnor Repository Files Properties</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/repository_files_properties.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para></para>
	</section>

	<section id="guvnor_history_view">
		<title>Guvnor Resource History View</title>

		<para>
			The <guilabel>Guvnor Resource History</guilabel> view displays details about the revision history for the selected files, both local and those in Guvnor repositories. The initial state of this view is shown on the figure below.
		</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Initial State of the Guvnor Resource History View</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/resource_history_view.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			The <guilabel>Guvnor Resource History</guilabel> view is populated by <guilabel>Show History</guilabel> actions in either the local <guilabel>Guvnor</guilabel> context menu or in the context menu for a Guvnor repository file in the Guvnor Repositories View (see <xref linkend="guvnor_repositories_view"/>). Once this action is performed, the <guilabel>Guvnor Resource History</guilabel> view is refreshed to display the revision history:
		</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Guvnor Resource History View</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/resource_history_view2.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>
			Here we see that the file <filename>test.txt</filename> has seven revisions. Double clicking on a revision row or selecting the <guimenuitem>Open (Read only)</guimenuitem> option from the context menu opens an Eclipse read-only editor with the revision contents.
		</para>

		<figure>
			<title>Eclipse Read-only Editor with the Revision Contents</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/functionality_overview/resource_history_view3.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>
		<note>
			<title>Note:</title>
			<para>
				You can also use the <guimenuitem>Save As...</guimenuitem> option when a file is open in a read-only editor to save a local writable copy of the contents. Doing so, however, will not associate the file created with its Guvnor source.
			</para>
		</note>

	</section>

	<section id="preferences">
		<title>Guvnor Preferences</title>
        

		<para>The <property>EGT</property> provides a preference page in the <guilabel>Guvnor</guilabel> category:</para>
    	
		<figure>
			<title>Resource Selection</title>
			<mediaobject>
				<imageobject>
					<imagedata fileref="images/guvnor_preferences/guvnor_preferences.png"/>
				</imageobject>
			</mediaobject>
		</figure>

		<para>The preferences cover two categories:</para>
		<itemizedlist>
			<listitem>
				<para>Guvnor repository connections</para>
			</listitem>

			<listitem>
				<para>Local Guvnor repository resource decorations.</para>
			</listitem>
		</itemizedlist>

		<section id="repo_connection_preferences">
			<title>Guvnor Repository Connection Preferences</title>
			<para>There are two preferences that can be set for Guvnor repository connections, which are used when creating new connections:</para>

			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The first is a default Guvnor repository URL template, which can simplify the process of creating additional similar connections by simply changing part of the field, such as the host name.
					</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>
						The second defines whether or not authentication information should be saved in the Eclipse platform key-ring by default.</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>

			<para>
				As with the Guvnor repository URL template, the decision whether to save authentication information in the Eclipse platform key-ring can be determined when creating the connection. That is, both of these preferences are simply convenience values set to reasonable defaults.
			</para>
		</section>

		<section id="resource_decoration_preferences">
			<title>Local Guvnor Repository Resource Decoration Preferences</title>

			<para>
				The second category of preferences provided by the <property>EGT</property> can be used to define how the decoration of local resources associated with Guvnor repository resources is presented. Since the Guvnor repository is not a substitute for a SCM, and since SCM tools in Eclipse tend to decorate local resources, it is useful to be able to control how the <property>EGT</property> decorate its local resources to avoid messy conflicts with SCM packages.
			</para>

			<para>
				In the <guilabel>File Decoration</guilabel> section of the preference page, you can choose the location (Top right, Top left, Bottom right, Bottom left) of the decoration icon, or you can choose not to display it. In the <guilabel>Text</guilabel> section, you can format the Guvnor metadata which is appended to the file names:
			</para>
			<itemizedlist>
				<listitem>
					<para>Whether to show an indicator (&gt;) when the local file has changes not committed back to the Guvnor repository</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Whether to show the revision number</para>
				</listitem>
				<listitem>
					<para>Whether to show the date/time stamp</para>
				</listitem>
			</itemizedlist>

			<para>
				Any changes to these preferences take effect immediately upon clicking the <guibutton>Apply</guibutton> and then <guibutton>OK</guibutton> buttons.
			</para>
		</section>
	</section>
</chapter>
